<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2005-movie/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kung Fu Hustle (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-hustle-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-hustle-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most entertaining I have seen yet, I couldn&#x27;t get enough of
it since I&#x27;ve done numerous repeats of my favorite scenes. It&#x27;s a
showcase of tremendous (albeit underutilized) talent, but there&#x27;s also
many scenes and characters which should have been excluded. Anyways,
much of what one sees in here is simply stuff of dreams. Example: we
have a man catching a speeding bullet with great ease, a very
unsuspecting man at that, and dressed in pyjamas and the cheapest of
sandals, and a man who soon meets his match... I don&#x27;t know if gets
more exciting than that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the movie is very uneven (there are both very badly-made and very
well-made parts), and looks like it suppers from a low budget. The good
parts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The grand entrance of the world&#x27;s top killer, complete with the
bullet moment, the opening of the wall, and the conversation he
enjoys before starting a fight the couple. His is the most
interesting performance (and character) in the whole movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The moments involving the musical killers. The concept is brilliant
and very fresh, and the characters are very interesting, especially
the blind one.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I loved the performance of the guy playing the elastic master. He
was not the sort you&#x27;d take seriously (ever so drunk, and grinning
like he was abnormal), but that perception would quickly change when
he was forced to get violent.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of the three warriors in the poor part of town, Pig Sty Alley, I
loved the food maker and the dressmaker. Of these, the dressmaker
was the most interesting, while also giving the best performance.
Looks out for the brief moment when they spar together before
parting. Beautiful. You will wish there was more of a backstory to
these characters.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Triplets of Belleville (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-triplets-of-belleville-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-triplets-of-belleville-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s what I wrote some years ago:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Totally unlike anything I&#x27;ve seen before, an extraordinary animated
feature, with some superb music, magnificent characters, and amazing
stylistic choices, and supreme storytelling... It&#x27;s an awesome
experience, pity it runs for less than 80 minutes. It carries greater
emotional impact than most movies I&#x27;ve seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&#x27;s what I wrote in 2010:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That still stands except the last sentence, since the revisit brought
no such impact. Let me add that the movie is a bizarre ride (no
dialog, unseemly super-tough heroes, etc.) and that the highlight of
the wonderful music is the one track at start of the end-credits. I
also remember enjoying the raunchy opening sequence much more than on
this revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a third viewing, it feels more a curious experiment than a serious
movie, and it remains as unusual as ever. I love the mother (her resolve
is impressive), but the title characters are even more interesting. The
dog, dumb as it is, is lovable. There is not much going on in the movie,
and if fact, what is supposed to be a climax is just a string of
fantasy-like quirky moments. By the way, I should have said &lt;em&gt;practically
no dialog&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There is a bit, but no more than two or three sentences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Life of David Gale (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-life-of-david-gale-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-life-of-david-gale-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very well-made political drama focused on the issue of death penalty.
Full of good performances, my favorite being the lawyer of the title
character. I have, for a long time, considered it a masterpiece, which
was perhaps careless, considering that I don&#x27;t remember watching it
more than once. A revisit wasn&#x27;t quite as impactful, but the movie
remains impressive. The last twist is okay, but maybe needless (and
earned the movie dislike from many). A better twist happens earlier in
the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The punishment that David Gale goes through, after cheating on his wife
and beeing falsely accused of rape, is rather too much, especially when
refused access to his child. It reminds me of the injustice suffered by
the ever-drunk lead character found in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;crazy-heart-2009&quot;&gt;Crazy Heart&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at the hand of his
lover.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
