<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/masterpiece/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Children of Men (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/children-of-men-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/children-of-men-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The nightmarish way of life portrayed here is about as dark as it gets.
The performances are great and so are the characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lady that can&#x27;t speak English is touching; I also loved the
nurse&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character played by Clive Owen is relentlessly heroic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pregnant lady is charming, and is the most interesting in the
movie; she&#x27;s played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm1715135&quot;&gt;Clare-Hope Ashitey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Julianne Moore freedom fighter is wonderful, and is given the
usual excellent performance the actor is know for&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only character I could have done without is that played by Michael
Caine. He felt recycled, and was somewhat not believable. It was still
heartbreaking when he had to meet his killers though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie features some of the best battle scenes I&#x27;ve seen, a fact
made more impressive due to the fact this isn&#x27;t a war movie. The
direction is also about as good as it gets. The story is quite unusual
and unpredictable, which gives the whole thing a fresh feeling. I still
wish there was more of an explanation of what the fuck fucked UK so bad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Fight Club (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/fight-club-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/fight-club-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;What would one say when reviewing what one considers superior to all
other works of its kind? Following is a (lackluster) attempt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie remains engaging after all these years and repeat viewings
(maybe 10 times). If feels modern as any movie made today, all except
for the lack of cellphones, and a presence of a CRT television set.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s not perfect, and I wish to see something to dethrone it. Here&#x27;s
what I don&#x27;t like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tyler Durden manages to stand up after a bullet makes it through his
throat. He can even talk normal, and gives a comfortable hug.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beating the lead character gets near the end feels so needless,
and it&#x27;s not even interesting (enough to make up for its uselessness).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My least favorite moment is when the lead gives himself a beating in
front of his boss. Boring.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like everything else, and no movie has superior direction, production
design, and cinematography. The cast is great too and so is the editing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s an old review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boasts all-time best direction, cinematography, &amp;amp; sound editing; a
supremely intriguing storyline which is so rich it could be made
into 2 or 3 other features; the entire set-design and acting
convinces me that Fincher, besides being the best, is also more
attentive to detail than perhaps all others... there&#x27;s no bad
physics, no classic movie mistakes, no overuse of visual
effects... this resulting in a visually- and mentally-stimulating
masterpiece. Its technical and artistic perfection blows my mind
away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Being John Malkovich (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/being-john-malkovich-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/being-john-malkovich-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;satires-and-dark-comedies-tend-to-be-good-movies&quot;&gt;Another great dark comedy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is a superbly fresh and entertaining
exploration into what would it be like to experience being another human
being. It also got wonderful performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;probably the only John Cusack performance I&#x27;ve enjoyed yet&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catherine Keener is amazing, and so is the gorgeous Cameron Diaz&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Malkovich rocks playing himself&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my favorite is the movie&#x27;s funniest character, the employer John
Cusack&#x27;s loser; it&#x27;s pure pleasure watching his eccentricities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie could do with better camerawork and visual effects, maybe even
set design, but one can almost ignore those shortcomings since it&#x27;s
well-written and directed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Requiem For A Dream (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/requiem-for-a-dream-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s only truly masterful&#x2F;great movies which offer great experiences on
a revisit as on the first viewing. This, Darren Aronofosky&#x27;s disturbing
masterpiece, is one of them. The story is quite simple, focusing on 4
characters, and each having drug additions, and it&#x27;s about the horrid
results that follow. There is good humor here and there, and there is a
whole lot of good acting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I hardly pay attention to is movie scores, but the one in
here is among the most memorable, and it matches the movie quite well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One tear-jecking moment is when the mommy character (played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ellen_Burstyn&quot;&gt;Ellen
BUrstyn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) expresses the high shitness levels of her life to son. Sadly
this mommy character is a little overdone (as if retarded), though her
acting is pretty good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A far &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.slantmagazine.com&#x2F;film&#x2F;review&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream&#x2F;4394&quot;&gt;superior review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, even though it is a lot more negative than
mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Smokin&#x27; Aces (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/smokin-aces-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/smokin-aces-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This movie is intense and has so many gems spread all over it that I&#x27;m
tempted to call it masterpiece. The experience was better than the first
time around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of what caused this celebration:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taraji P. Hanson&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taraji P. Hanson&#x27;s rifle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common carrying Alicia Keys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FBI poser&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concept (multiple pro-killers targeting one guy)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mafia telephone conversation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the murderous neo-nazi trio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fight-club-1999&quot;&gt;Fight Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before it, the movie is packed too much of goodness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
