<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2009/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>2009 review</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/2009-review/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/2009-review/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;best movie&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of the year is also the best movie ever to be based
in my city of residence, Johannesburg.
The movie also has &lt;strong&gt;best visuals&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;,
as its battle suit is the &lt;strong&gt;best visual effects artefact&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
In addition, it&#x27;s also the &lt;strong&gt;most original&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; movie, which helps it feel super-fresh.
The movie is named &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;district-9&quot;&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;best male performance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is that of Christoph Waltz as Nazi officer
in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;inglourious-basterds&quot;&gt;Inglourious Basterds&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
He plays a very fearsome Nazi officer that is so damn easy to hate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>District 9</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/district-9/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/district-9/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The documentary style has been employed elsewhere before, but there&#x27;s
nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in all movie history. Its weird and
wonderful story starts off with nice comic touches and transitions into
a harrowing tale of human torture, and ends as some action-adventure of
sorts, complete with superb visual effects, with some nice creature
ideas.
Sure there&#x27;s warts here and there (I could not stand the resilience of
the villain, and I found the gang leader ridiculous), but to have a gem like this
emerge from my country of residence, South Africa, is quite something.
It is the best movie based there. The lead performance also deserves
applaud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Inglourious Basterds</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first scene is top-class, for the performance of the weary farmer
when forced to make an unpleasant choice, the sort where I feel
self-death is better. The best performance of the movie however is that
of Christoph Waltz, who plays the Nazi officer questioning him. Brad
Pitt is quite limited in terms of talent but not charisma, and here
provides the weakest performance of all key characters. Quentin
Tarantino is a weirdo who possesses the freedom (perhaps too much) to
paint whatever he pleases on screen, and luckily got the talent. He
gives this one superb suspense, exciting dialog, unusual (and
unpredictable) story, and wonderful editing. It&#x27;s my favorite and best
of all his works, followed by &lt;em&gt;Reservoir Dogs&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting, and rare, thing is I enjoyed the movie a lot more on a
revisit. The second revisit was not so impressive... felt like an
overlong and pompous waste. The praise remains though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
