<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/average/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Mechanic</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-mechanic/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-mechanic/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A stupid story, with two things worthy of mention:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The giant gay hitman has quite a presence, reminding me of the great
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;John_Carroll_Lynch&quot;&gt;John Carroll Lynch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equally impressive is the fat guy playing a self-proclaimed messiah.
Both these characters were surprisingly weel-developed.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-the-battle-of-the-five-armies/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-the-battle-of-the-five-armies/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the creature design of the dragon amazing; best dragon design
I&#x27;ve yet seen. Most everything else is stale, though I do love the
giants. The combat moments were annoying, where you see puny creatures
stand their own against the fearsome beasts. I wish these beasts were
given more than cardboard characters, given that they clearly were
intelligent beings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Big Hero 6</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/big-hero-6/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/big-hero-6/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The level of fantasy in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cloudy-with-a-chance-of-meatballs-2009&quot;&gt;Cloudy With A Chance of Meatballs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; went to
ridiculous levels, but this one is even worse. As was the case with
Cloudy, it started very well, mostly with the help of the cute, chubby,
and funny air-filled robot, but devolves into super-lazy writing with
too many holes, and an overly-skilled teenage engineer. Making things
worse is some bad recycled plot points, an example being the apologetic
moment our (very uninteresting) lead character gets to have after doing
something unbearably stupid. All this spoils the various good spots the
movie offers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lucy (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lucy-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lucy-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s surprising to have a movie with A-list starts be this wacky. It&#x27;s
exciting and feels fresh for the first 30 minutes or so, right up until
the moment the lead character, Lucy, gets the drugs removed from inside
her. The phone call to mommy was especially wonderful. The villain was
also very scary. Most of the rest is gibberish, bordering on stupid. By
the time the whole thing ends, I was tempted to call the move bad, but
there&#x27;s still that first 30 minutes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing to praise was the WTF that Morgan Freeman expressed on
the first phone call to this Lucy character. I don&#x27;t recall such a
level of wonderment in all of my movie-watching experience (but I have
shitty memory).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story concept is similar to that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;limitless-2011&quot;&gt;Limitless&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but with far less
restraint, and a much lesser script.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Expendables 3</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-expendables-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-expendables-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked a few things:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not remember enjoying Antonio Banderas this much; his character
and performance are superior to all others (not hard) in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I initially felt that Mel Gibson was miscast as villain, but he
proved worthy: a fearsome personality (well-developed, and deserving
a better movie) and a really good performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed watching Dolph Lundgren; he gives a decent, humorous
performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jet Li and Arnold Schwarzenegger give awful performances, but it was
interesting to see them play homosexual partners; I proud.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other performances range from substandard to merely okay. They are
not interesting, and neither is the story. The movie is too loud, extra
shallow, and offers nothing new at all. I wish they don&#x27;t make another,
because I&#x27;m gonna have to watch it as well :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Godzilla (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/godzilla-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/godzilla-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this so unpleasant that it made me miss the 1998 movie. None of
the creature designs was any good. This includes the title character,
who, in an effort to resemble the original Godzilla (1960s) ended up
clumsy as fuck. You don&#x27;t emulate shit costume design just to pay
homage, unless you are making satire maybe, or you are a plain better
director. It was also laughable having this Godzilla character be a
friend to humans (stupid twist) and having it spit fire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human characters (and the performances) were also not interesting.
Not one of them were convincing, and some were even unbearable at times
(check the guy playing the heroic son, or the Japanese scientist).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is noisy and the story not interesting. The all-too-common
Hollywood thing about family values was hard to bear. So cheesy, so
stale. Sigh!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Noah (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/noah-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/noah-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I think there isn&#x27;t much to the Noah story, so the writers added a few
things, like talking rocks, a magical grandfather (and pregnancy), a
pointless king (at least in the latter part of the movie), and a God
that sucks at communication. If I was tasked with creating a basic
story-line, I would have had the Noah family actually go find those
animals themselves instead of them magically be brought onto the ship.
In addition, I wouldn&#x27;t do the lazy thing where they are all put to
sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised (and disappointed) that the movie was directed by the
great Darren Aronofsky, who gave up &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pi-1997&quot;&gt;Pi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream-2000&quot;&gt;Requiem For A Dream&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
There is nothing interesting&#x2F;provocative enough to deserve such a
skillful person. The visual design may be interesting, but not by much.
It is dark and desolate, which is typical of his movies, but it&#x27;s too
bland a story. It&#x27;s epic, yes, but it&#x27;s also based on one of the most
nonsensical of all stories in the Bible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Amazing Spider-Man 2 (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is even worse than the 2002 movie, which I considered
the least interesting in the previous series of 3 movies. It was highly
disappointing because I heavily anticipated it (I&#x27;m a sucker for
super-hero movies). It is poorly written, and got cheesy romance and (I
wish Gwen died a lot earlier in the movie). It also has uninteresting
villains (Paul Giamatti is miscast, and so is Jamie Foxx). Not even the
visual effects impress, being worse than those of its predecessor &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-amazing-spider-man-2012&quot;&gt;the
2012 movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the action is too frantic. I do like, however, the
relaxed manner to this Spider-Man. However, his skills are ridiculously
high, and he survives way too much current flowing through his body.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Boogie Nights (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/boogie-nights-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/boogie-nights-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this several years ago and do not remember being impressed. I
just now revisited it to ensure I didn&#x27;t miss anything. Well, it&#x27;s not
much. The character of the lead is curious, with its great innocence and
kindness, until over halfway through the movie when he displays
jealousy. It&#x27;s not a good performance, but more a half-comic one. The
more interesting one is that by Julianne Moore, who is more desirable
here than elsewhere (if memory serves well).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The violence feels forced. Also, some extended sequences, e.g. the
shitty fire-cracker scene, help make the movie overly long, at over 150
minutes. The whole exercise feels pointless, and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Boogie_Nights#Release_and_reception&quot;&gt;is way overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gangster Squad (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gangster-squad-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gangster-squad-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Mireille Enos, who plays the wife, gives a really nice performance. Sean
Penn, on the other hand, gives the worst of his career, perhaps due to
the shitty make-up and bad character development. The movie starts off
well, with the superbly-made heroic antics of the Josh Brolin character,
complete with excellent cinematography and production design. But soon
after, it feels like a failed attempt at an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;l-a-confidential-1997&quot;&gt;L.A. Confidential&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and got
unfunny humor and misguided romance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butler (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butler-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butler-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most shocking thing about this overrated bore is that it was made by
Lee Daniels, the same guy who made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;the most impressive movie made in
the last few years&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s fucking weird! It&#x27;s among the most
surprising things in all of my experiences watching movies. Not even a
wonderful actor like Forest Whitaker pulled off a decent performance.
He&#x27;s embarrassing even, though not as much as Oprah Winfrey, who was
supposed to be a quality actor, given her &lt;em&gt;Color Purple&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; performance
(though I haven&#x27;t seen that in over 10 years). Something must have gone
seriously wrong. Maybe it was a troubled production?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it&#x27;s not utter trash. I liked the concept of the heroic
activists being prepared for racist taunts, which was quite fresh. Not
that it was particularly well-made, but that it&#x27;s just something I
haven&#x27;t seen before in a movie. Another highlight is the character of
the younger brother of the activist at the dinner table, specifically
the &lt;em&gt;party&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; moment. It was beautiful. Sadly, not much else was. None of
the other performances were good (and I&#x27;m not exaggerating), and the
old-age make-up was even worse. Ridiculous!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hunger Games: Catching Fire (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-catching-fire-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-catching-fire-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;More bearable than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-hunger-games-2012&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with amazing visual designs: check
the Rome-like arena and the city. Not much else is interesting, least of
which is the soppy romance. The twist is lack-lustre, and the leading
lady remains unconvincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>12 Years a Slave (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/12-years-a-slave-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/12-years-a-slave-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected a lot more, and got disappointed by the less-than-impressive
direction and script. Not even Chiwetel Ejiofor saves it, and he in fact
exposes his limitations as an actor, which is sad given I am something
of a fan... see him in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;redbelt-2007&quot;&gt;Redbelt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Four Brothers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; for example.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one interesting subplot is one involving the sex pet, whose fate is
less than desirable. Not that her performance is any excellent, nor her
scenes particularly well-made. She just happens to be in a rather unique
situation, and I like her face :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may end up the most overrated movie of the year. There&#x27;s not much
value in here. Find something else. If in a mood for some Black American
slavery stuff, check out the far superior &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mandingo-1975&quot;&gt;Mandingo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;goodbye-uncle-tom-1971&quot;&gt;Goodbye Uncle
Tom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;django-unchained-2012&quot;&gt;Django Unchained&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Goodbye Bafana (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-bafana-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-bafana-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013&quot;&gt;Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; led me to check this one out,
whose existence I&#x27;ve been ignoring for a few years now. Sadly, I have
to say I didn&#x27;t miss much... it&#x27;s about as dull as they come, and
none of the elements are worthy of celebration (cinematography,
direction, acting, script, ...). The concept of exploring the life of
an icon through someone else&#x27;s eyes is something I appreciated about
&lt;em&gt;Cry Freedom&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but then it helped if that someone else is actually
interesting (a heroic journalist). It&#x27;s not the case here (a
sympathetic prison guard). As for the icon in question (Nelson Mandela),
it doesn&#x27;t look like much effort was expended really. Not even an
attempt to make him look older, beyond some white shit on the actor&#x27;s
hair. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also not much effort on the part of the two actors to speak
Xhosa (a major language in South Africa) in a half-convincing manner.
Most of the world won&#x27;t notice of course, but it still does matter...
it&#x27;s embarassing if you have any passing familiarity of the language.
Lazy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good cinematography, production design, sound, and performance of the
lady playing Zinzi. Horrible old-age make-up (check mom of Mandela, or
worse still, check the Mandela face when Zinzi visits him in jail...
embarrassing and unwatchable). Also, I didn&#x27;t see Mandela in the lead
performance (Idris Alba is not a very good performer, and is not
credible in the role).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was very rushed, and it leaves one feeling too many details
were left out (there was no mention of Oliver Tambo or Albert Luthuli,
for example), and some very significant moments merely given passing
attention (Sharpeville and Soweto killings, for example). One thing that
could have helped is narration, or even flashbacks. One can argue that
you can&#x27;t fit everything in a single movie, but that would be an
excuse... I&#x27;ve seen biopics in which feel like they do justice to a
legend, recent examples being &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-iron-lady-2011&quot;&gt;The Iron Lady&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;lincoln-2012&quot;&gt;Lincoln&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pacific Rim (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pacific-rim-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pacific-rim-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For a movie this expensive, I found none of the visual effects
impressive. Not even the designs, both creature and mechanical, deserve
applause. The battles were entertaining, but too erratic to keep track
of what&#x27;s goin on. The story concept is retarded, making it a blatant
excuse to put giant robots on screen who didn&#x27;t happen to be
&lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I also wish there was an explanation for the whole
thing, beyond the too-brief and nonsensical alien invasion story. Not
one performance was beyond average, nor was any of the humor effective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is there anything to celebrate here? Well... it&#x27;s not boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Olympus Has Fallen (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/olympus-has-fallen-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/olympus-has-fallen-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is unique in that movies showing The White House being attacked are
very rare. I can only remember one in fact, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I also
saw this concept explored only once elsewhere... one of the seasons of
&lt;em&gt;24&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (a favorite of mine). The amount of violence is quite unexpected,
and very sudden, though it could have went even further (e.g. killing
son of president). The overall movie, however, feels... inadequate. It
lacks interesting performances, and the acts of the villains are left
pretty much unexplained. The pro-American stance, &amp;quot;we will emerge
victorious no matter what&amp;quot;, is intensely annoying, though not to the
levels of &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Smeagol&#x2F;Gollum is among the legendary movie characters, and I felt he
was a welcome addition to the movie. He&#x27;s as annoying as usual, but I
did like the faces he made during the game he played with the title
character, which I think were more varied&#x2F;complex than he had in &lt;em&gt;The
Lord of the Rings&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy. I also enjoyed the character of the
eccentric animal-lover wizard. The trolls (ugly, disgusting giants)
represent great character design and so do the orcs, complete with their
wolves. Pity none of it is actually new. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;overly-complex-action-sequences&quot;&gt;I dislike the excessive
complexity of the battle scene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;... serious waste of money and effort. I
also hate it when characters go through way too much physical pounding,
as in when the rock giants fight (a ridiculous and unexplained moment),
and the Dwarf escape.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Devil&#x27;s Double (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/devil-s-double-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/devil-s-double-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one has the special distinction of having a body double being the
lead character, something I haven&#x27;t seen before. It&#x27;s just sad that
the performance (all them actually) isn&#x27;t so good, and neither is the
story and direction. It&#x27;s a second-rate production.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Silent Hill (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the creature design which is quite good, best of which is
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Pyramid_Head&quot;&gt;Pyramid Head&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the horrific blade-dragging monster, whose made even
more memorable by his countless bug-like companions. Second favorites
are the supersexy, faceless, murderous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nurse&quot;&gt;nurses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. These pleasures were
however spoiled by a miscast&#x2F;unconvincing villainous lady and the weak
story. This is not to mention random stupid things, like the leading
lady running away from the cop for no reason, or the silly gal whose
hate leads to her being skinned alive, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I felt first time I watched it, and is no longer the case:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deserving of mention is the superb production design (though this is
inconsistent) and certain moments of extreme beauty (e.g. the early
scene of the grassy wilderness where mother and daughter share some
love, and a later scene which shows the internals of the family&#x27;s
home). As for visual effects, the moments of &amp;quot;approaching darkness&amp;quot;
can only be a result of visual mastery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That early scene was nice yes, but calling it &lt;em&gt;extremely beautiful&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is
extreme. As for the visual mastery comment, it must have been mere
virgin excitement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Silent Hill: Revelation (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-revelation-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-revelation-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Pyramid_Head&quot;&gt;Pyramid Head&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is back, this time with someone tough enough to fight
him. This someone is the superbly-designed blade-headed slasher
character, known as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Missionary_(film)&quot;&gt;The Missionary&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (and obviously deserving of a
better name). This is among the most impressive creature&#x2F;character
designs I&#x27;ve yet seen in movies, and nearly as innovative as Mr. Head,
and arguably more dangerous, given her speed. The murderous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nurse&quot;&gt;nurses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are
also back, this time even more glorious than before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, there is nearly nothing else to celebrate... the direction is
quite bad (deceptive and erratic camerawork and editing with annoying
overuse of the tired trademark of horror movies... loud sounds). The
leading lady, and his boyfriend, are not interesting. Sean Bean is a
good actor, but is seriously miscast, as he was in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;silent-hill-2006&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
There&#x27;s lots of meh dialog, but I really did love the leading lady&#x27;s
moment in the classroom, which is something I&#x27;ve never seen before in
movies. But because the script isn&#x27;t solid, her attitude (and strength
of character) was left unexplained, and is simply over-the-top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hotel Transylvania (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hotel-transylvania-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hotel-transylvania-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing fresh here as I expected, judging by the trailer. There is also
that annoying and all-too-common thing of someone lying and later
regretting and apologising in public. Movie is shallow too, and each
character recycled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did like some of the dance sequences though (regardless of the badness
of the music), and I thought the dirty chef character was very
well-animated, and is a showcase of quality character design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Skyfall (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/skyfall-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/skyfall-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is overall a disappointing experience, considering I watched with
anticipation, given its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;quantum-of-solace-2008&quot;&gt;solid predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I however have to give
kudos to Daniel Craig&#x27;s befitting performance. I liked also the first
chase scene, which must have the most daring motorbike stunts I have yet
seen in movies, not to mention an unexpected ending. Most of the rest of
the movie does not live to the expectations set by that opening. The
story is not good either, nor the villain interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Taken 2 (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/taken-2-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/taken-2-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lame and desperate attempt to milk off the success of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;taken-2008&quot;&gt;the first&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It
did succeed though, but not artistically. It is a let-down in a number
of ways:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The classic silliness that is seen in too many action movies, like
leaving the hero unwatched for large periods of time, so as to give
him a chance to escape.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having inexperienced people perform miracles, like the supreme
driving skill of the daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lazy, overly-frantic editing technique that gives the illusion
that some hard-core action is taking place... the sort where you
cannot figure out exactly what is happening. You will often notice
continuity errors in such sequences.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The villain was also very uninteresting, and his utterances extremely
stupid and performance very unconvincing. A person at his level needs a
better script (or at least that is my idea of a high-ranking criminal).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I appreciated though is the great suspense the director
managed to pull off, especially during the first half. Also, I did not
find Liam Neeson as fearsome and convincing as the first time, but the
great efficiency of his character still impressed in a way, like when he
was guiding his daughter to find him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube Zero (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-zero-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-zero-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A rather disappointing, and possibly last, sequel of the series. I
suspect, when the writers set out to explore the intrigue in the
preceding movies (more &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-1997&quot;&gt;the first&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, since &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-2-hypercube&quot;&gt;the second&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was just a
needless rehash), they did not actually have a solid idea how to explain
it... the actual purpose of the Cube. It is sad. Surely one could setup
brainstorming sessions about these things, especially if you are going
to spend a few million?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the execution in this case is not disgusting bad, and there is
okay acting, but the fascination is largely gone, and the excuse of an
explanation is merely a passing reference to patriotism and religion.
Also, the villain is not very impressive, despite a desperate attempt to
portray an eccentric evil character. It&#x27;s a far less successful attempt
than the a character he reminds me of: the genius scientist in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;afro-samurai-resurrection-2009&quot;&gt;Afro
Samurai: Resurrection&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube 2: Hypercube</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-2-hypercube/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-2-hypercube/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-1997&quot;&gt;first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; had the advantage of freshness, and this one... well,
being a sequel can be real tough for movies, since they are often not
judged strictly as separate pieces of work, but rather something of a
continuation. That is, a movie can be superior technically (acting,
directing, writing) but still feel worse, due to lack of innovation&#x2F;loss
of novelty, or too much comparison with the first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one sequel feels like a desperate attempt at continuing the
intrigue. It does have better acting, but worse dialog (or at least, not
as much fun). It feels desperate because now the Cube is like way too
advanced, bringing in some rather unfamiliar physics concepts into play,
feeling too unrealistic. The ending is weird, leaving me with questions,
and me wonders if it was delibarate on the part of the filmmakers, or if
I simply am not smart enough to figure WTF&#x27;s happenin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cloud Atlas (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cloud-atlas-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cloud-atlas-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre treat, far more enjoyable in its first half. Lots of
bad&#x2F;uninteresting performances, even from established actors like Halle
Berry, Tom Hanks, and Hugo Weaving. Lots of brutality, pointlessness,
and... what the fuck is the movie about?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the interview though, and it helps carry the movie along. I
enjoyed watching the guy asking the questions... decent performance
there. The guy rescuing the heroine is admirable too, though the action
he finds self in is just cartoony. Is this not supposed to be close to
reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some interesting quotables sprinkled all over the place. My
favorite is one uttered by a master composer after an attempt at a piano
by one apprentice:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must have misheard me! I said I had a melody, not a malady!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men 3: The Last Stand (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-3-the-last-stand-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-3-the-last-stand-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The worst in the trilogy, it makes one appreciate its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;x-men-2-2003&quot;&gt;immediate
predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; even more. It is also heavily populated with characters,
many new, but they are mostly shallow. Both the script and direction are
far poorer than one would hope. It is full of lame utterances and
uninteresting performances, all but from the super-fast lady, the
Aaliyah (dead RnB artist) looklike, played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dania_Ramirez&quot;&gt;Dania Ramirez&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Looper (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/looper-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/looper-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I dislike the overly-loud banging sounds, which mostly emanate from the
gunshots. This is from a very violent movie which cast Bruce Willis (he
should retire), and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Joseph_Gordon-Levitt&quot;&gt;Joseph Gordon-Levitt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, whose face should have been
left alone, especially since he does not resemble Bruce even a bit even
after all the non-sense is put on his face, digital or not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping this overrated non-sense will be the last time travel movie
ever made, since the concept is utter crap (nonsensical). The story
starts exciting enough but loses steam very soon after. None of the
perfomers are solid, especially Jeff Daniels as villain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Romance (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/romance-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/romance-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The imagery imagined by the lead character, one where women expose their
lower bodies for the pleasure of men they cannot see, is powerful. It
has stayed with me for years, and is one of the main reasons I watched
the movie again, though it lasts less than a minute.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie itself is pointless, and feels like a waste of time. The
characters that are given a chance to speak blubber way too much
philosophical non-sense. Many of the scenes are tiring, for example
showing the entire sequence of a woman undressing, or being bonded for
sexual pleasure... twice. There is likely a message here, but am
perhaps too dumb to notice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mission: Impossible - Ghost Protocol (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mission-impossible-ghost-protocol-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mission-impossible-ghost-protocol-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked the concept of the device that creates an optical illusion; I
also liked watching the Burj Khalifa, my favorite building, on which
some of the (noisy) action takes place. Not much else is interesting,
least of which is performance of the leading lady, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Paula_Patton&quot;&gt;Paula Patton&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I did
however fall for the ultra-desirable &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;L%C3%A9a_Seydoux&quot;&gt;Léa Seydoux&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brave (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brave-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brave-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A big let-down with a shallow and unexciting story, which is a strange
thing for a Disney theatrical release. This is made worse by my great
anticipation. Me was looking forward to something darker, as the poster
would suggest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hair and fur is done quite well, and so was the bear fight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Austin Powers in Goldmember (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/austin-powers-in-goldmember-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/austin-powers-in-goldmember-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The least interesting of the three movies in the series, complete with a
badly miscast Beyonce Knowles, who is even worse than Elizabeth Hurley
in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;austin-powers-international-man-of-mystery-1997&quot;&gt;the first one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This is made even worse by her failed tough 70&#x27;s
black gal persona, a bad parody of Foxy Brown. The most annoying, and
worst-developed, character however is the guy named Goldmember. What
were they thinking? Luckily, Fat Bustard is interesting this time
around, and so is the son of Dr. Evil.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Green Mile (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-green-mile-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-green-mile-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The writers probably did not appear to care of looking silly, given the
amount of stupid events that happen (e.g. some oversized guy touches
crotch of another for some supernatural healing). The direction is
competent though, and so is some of the acting. My favorite was Sam
Rockwell even though he was not convincing in the role; he was just fun
to watch. Another good one was by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Doug_Hutchison&quot;&gt;Doug Hutchison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the hateful, and
easy-to-hate, prison guard. Michael Clark Duncan has an admirable body,
but am curious how it happened they decided to cast him for the role. It
is just so pointless, but I really love his body. Its size is however
inconsistently exagerrated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Terminator Salvation (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/terminator-salvation-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/terminator-salvation-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked the concept of the robo-bikes and... nothing else. The movie is
very unentertaining, and even disturbing at times. Not one character is
interesting, nor is any performance. The first two movies in the
franchise were a lot more watchable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Idiocracy (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/idiocracy-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/idiocracy-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It started pretty well, with nice humor, but the idiocy of a future
human civilization just went too far, and being a passive comedy is not
enough of an excuse for lazy writing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Blood: the Last Vampire (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/blood-the-last-vampire-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/blood-the-last-vampire-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the imagery is beautiful, and so is the lead character. The
scene in the car with father and daughter is surprisingly good, and does
not fit the movie. That daughter is given the movie&#x27;s best performance.
The ends feels rushed... lazy writing. The demons are among some of the
worst creature designs ever in movies... there must have been a problem
with the budget.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part 1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story of the Deathly Hallows makes for some of the best animation
I&#x27;ve seen yet, though it runs for only a few minutes. It&#x27;s a fresh
departure from an otherwise dull and overlong experience. The movie is
even a worse experience than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009&quot;&gt;the immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though bearable, this is the worst so far in the series. Too much of it
feels like filler material (the romance and ensuing jealousy for
example), and it feels like we were denied a proper climax... it feels
incomplete. Even the visual effects are lesser, both in number and
merit, from (at least) the previous two movies. One thing that deserves
praise though is the smoke&#x2F;ink effect that was used whenever the
villains (dis)appear. It was also used to great effect in the
end-credits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Killers (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/killers-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/killers-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember enjoying the movie a lot more first time, most especially
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Katherine_Heigl&quot;&gt;Katherine Heigl&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It is still enjoyable, but that Katherine, though
desirable, is just so irritating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else I felt last time I watched:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writers had no clue where to run with the story; I got surprised
when it ended, because the attacks were simply unjustified, and there
was no resolve.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Faster (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/faster-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/faster-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that this is a second rate actioner that isn&#x27;t overall decent, I
was not going to write a review about it, except that I actually found
the twist quite unique. I am temped to say &lt;em&gt;surprising&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but that&#x27;s
what twists are supposed to be. But this one is especially so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effort to make the professional assassin interesting worked pretty
well, considering it could have been a lot more cheesier&#x2F;cheaper. The
girlfriend of that assassin is extra-lovely too, and gives a decent
performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Great Dictator (1940)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-great-dictator-1940/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-great-dictator-1940/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the set designs of the palace impressive as well as the costumes
worn by the people there, especially those having high ranks in the
military. I found the humor unfunny, and the directing tired, complete
with overlong scenes. Maybe Charlie Chaplin is interesting, but not
here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Izulu Lami (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/izulu-lami-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/izulu-lami-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the natural-looking performance of Tshepang Mohlomi, who plays
the leader of a gang of street kids. Also, his character is given some
depth: he appears an asshole on the sufrace, but is actually a nice guy
who, for example, allows his ass to get ripped apart, only to share the
rewards with the rest of the gang.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display of chilhood innocence (and naivéty) is done well, but sadly
none of the grown-ups are given any attention, all but the sister of the
dead mother, who gives the movie&#x27;s best performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Robot (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robot-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robot-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though incredibly shallow, formulaic, and ludicrous, it is entertaining
at times. Also the beauty of the leading lady is without flaw and her
dance moves wonderful (there&#x27;s stupid full-length music sequences a few
times in the movie), and sex appeal nearly absent (though I would not
refuse an invitation).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anger the creator shows towards the robot is annoying (both given
unsatisfying performances), and is most unbearable at the moment when he
gets to break it apart. It&#x27;s too common &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;unforgiving-characters-are-annoying&quot;&gt;a flaw in Hollywood movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
and it&#x27;s sad to see it in a movie from a different market. The anger is
totally unjustfified because the robot has that time done various good
deeds, including saving a girl from being raped, saving a number of
people from fire, as well as helping a woman in difficult labour. All
that is conveniently forgotten... it&#x27;s just unberarable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Dark of the Moon (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t see any improvement in visual effects over &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009&quot;&gt;the previous
movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The story is shit too, but the gal excessively gorgeous, much
more so than the previous overrated Megan Fox. Beyond money-making,
there can&#x27;t have been a reason this movie was made, especially since it
doesn&#x27;t add anything. The action is as frantic and hard-to-follow as in
the predecessors, with an annoying tendency of having the humans tougher
than would be realisitc (check how much they&#x27;re thrown around, only to
stand and continue fighting). Very little of the humor is effective, my
favorite being the part where the lead assaults own car.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Fantasy: The Spirits Within</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-the-spirits-within/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-the-spirits-within/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The pacing is unbearably slow and the story is not interesting. Luckily,
some of the sci-fi elements are done well, e.g. the material the softens
landing impact is an interesting concept. The designs of suits and other
things, like the aircraft and the city are decent. The only interesting
character is Doctor Sid (voiced by Donald Sutherland). I suspect more
effort (and love) was put into him than anyone else, since he&#x27;s the
most detailed (this is 3D animation) and convincing, while also very
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>J. Edgar (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/j-edgar-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/j-edgar-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The production design is top-class (impeccable set design and props),
while the old-age make-up is embarassingly bad. Even the 2 actors
playing the aging characters are unbearable to watch, perhaps as
unbearable as the immensely unpleasant character of J. Edgar Hoover. The
movie itself starts okay, but starts to be really boring and pointless.
I was surprised that it was made by the great Clint Eastwood. It must be
his worst.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Secretariat (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/secretariat-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/secretariat-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite my dislike of the subject (animal abuse for the sake of
entertainment and profit), I was curious enough to watch the whole
thing. It&#x27;s competently-made and got some decent performances, but it
is merely yet-another sports movie, only this time involving animals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Science of Sleep (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-science-of-sleep-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-science-of-sleep-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Much like the first experience I had with &lt;em&gt;Underground&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, I found this
unbearably irritating. This is due to the bizarre storyline and
directing, as well as an eccentric&#x2F;insane lead character.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desirable gals, especially the main love interest (played by
Charlotte Gainsbourg), makes it survivable. The romantic drama involving
her almost makes the movie worthwhile, and her performance is
amazing&#x2F;flawless. The gal playing the friend is a lot prettier though,
while the one playing the colleague isn&#x27;t bad either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Persona (1966)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/persona-1966/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/persona-1966/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another example of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;The Case of &#x27;The Matrix Reloaded&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is how I
felt after the first viewing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... happens to possess much sophistication (direction and dialogue)
with some shocking imagery, including one which must have inspired
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fight-club-1999&quot;&gt;Fight Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a sort of obscenity which is surprising for a 60&#x27;s
movie). The movie also feels fresh, feeling like a modern
psychological drama&#x2F;thriller, and therefore not as tiring and awkward
as those of its age, perhaps testimony of its director, Ingmar
Bergman, who is among the most honored ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching it again, it&#x27;s so strange that it feels like a different movie
altogether. I struggled to stay awake... it&#x27;s boring as fuck. It&#x27;s
also pointless. I must go find out what the fuss is all about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Things We Lost in the Fire (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/things-we-lost-in-the-fire-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/things-we-lost-in-the-fire-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Halle Barry does a similar character she played in &lt;em&gt;Monster&#x27;s Ball&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,
only this time there appears a lot more close-up shots which exposes her
not-to-impressive acting talent (and overrated prettiness). The movie
itself feels a little pretentious, not least of which is the character
of Benicio Del Toro, who plays a guy suffering from drug addiction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bad Teacher (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bad-teacher-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bad-teacher-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another comedy that relies heavily on goofiness for its laughs, and
pretty effective at that. It is in large part due to the
overly-competitive and pretentious rival teacher, played well by Lucy
Punch. Another good performance is by Justin Timberlake, playing an even
goofier yes-man. The lead performance by Cameron Diaz is extremely
uninteresting, but luckily her students are well-cast, and a very
non-standard cast at that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly the movie is ridiculously shallow, and there is no battle to
fight, and nothing is resolved... I don&#x27;t know what the fuck it&#x27;s
about. It feels very incomplete. Even the quality cast is underused (I
wish I could see more of Timberlake, the fat teacher, the kids, and much
less of Cameron Diaz).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Serpico (1973)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/serpico-1973/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/serpico-1973/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was attracted to this because of the story of a guy who exposed police
corruption, but it turned out to be unbearably boring. Al Pacino gives a
decent performance, but it&#x27;s not enough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Duel (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-duel-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-duel-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The character of the king&#x27;s investigator, with humorous and laid-back
fighting style, is fun to watch, though not nearly as much as the
ultra-sweet sister of the king. The martial are rdiculously overdone (we
know this is fantasy, but there&#x27;s limits even there) and the visual
effects unsatisfactory. The long-awaited for duel is less than
impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the ovie a lot more first time I watched it, mainly impressed
by the romantic aspect of it, but I think it was heavily affected by my
love for that king&#x27;s sister. Check her massive eyes, and check her face
when sad, or when happy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Swordsman II (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/swordsman-ii-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/swordsman-ii-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The romantic relationship between Jet Li&#x27;s lead character and that of
the lead villain (he didn&#x27;t suspect anything about his&#x2F;her
villainy&#x2F;sexuality) is both the most important and my favorite in the
movie. This lead character is surrounded by at least two other lovely
women (me want them), both of whom appear to have the hearts for him,
but he doesn&#x27;t once make a move on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a very low budget movie, but the martial arts choreography is
impressive. The direction is a little unfocused, and the humor does get
in the way of that focus... the balance between comedy and drama isn&#x27;t
quite right, as is so common with old Jet Li movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Legend (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-legend-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-legend-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Real nice opening credits visuals, some interesting martial arts, and a
weird thing where the main story ends way before the end of the movie.
It&#x27;s like the makers were honest enough to realise that they didn&#x27;t
have much material, and decided to start another subplot involving some
Russian fighters challenge our hero. As is usual with these martial arts
Chinese movies, the white foreigners receive some seriously shallow
character development, and happen to be unconvincingly evil.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead character is done poorly by Vincent Zhao, the same guy who
spoiled &lt;em&gt;Once Upon A Time In China&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; series by replacing Jet Li in the
4th and 5th movies in the series. I don&#x27;t remember enjoying any of his
other performances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Midnight in Paris (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/midnight-in-paris-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/midnight-in-paris-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only because Woody Allen made it, and now I wish he was
the one playing the lead character, not a poor imitator. The fantasy
element of it is a bit interesting (no one in my experience has made
such a smooth and unassuming time travel movie) but there&#x27;s a feel of
self-importance about the whole thing and that&#x27;s annoying and makes it
unbearable. Maybe Woody is getting lazy and arrogant. I haven&#x27;t seen
all of his work, but this is likely his worst. The costumes are nice
though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Angel Heart (1987)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/angel-heart-1987/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/angel-heart-1987/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s at least moment where Mickey Rourke shines, where he bullies an
old medical doctor into providing some info. Robert De Niro is
impressive, that is until we tire of his spurious appearance. The black
gal is intensely gorgeous, but I don&#x27;t know what&#x27;s up with the
romp... maybe it was for the audience. Otherwise the movie is not very
interesting and the twist is shitty-ass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Just Go With It (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/just-go-with-it-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/just-go-with-it-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It does not even try to be a good movie, but then again it is an Adam
Sandler comedy. There&#x27;s some very hilarious moments, even though none
of them were original, except the ass-coconut moment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One strange thing though is that I enjoyed Jennifer Aniston&#x27;s
performance, and for the first time (if memory serves well). I also
enjoyed the performance by the girl playing her daughter. Girls of that
age are hardly ever funny (or no one writer really tries), but she was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Love Actually (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/love-actually-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/love-actually-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a delightful&#x2F;fresh feel to it and there&#x27;s a bunch of fun
moments, but the whole thing is spoilt when it goes into typical
romantic comedy mode near the end, things like dozens of people
following a man who intends to propose, or a kid breaching airport
security to go mention his love for some gal. Bill Nighy and his manager
were fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sweeney Todd - The Demon Barber of Fleet Street (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sweeney-todd-the-demon-barber-of-fleet-street-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sweeney-todd-the-demon-barber-of-fleet-street-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Great set design, camerawork, and costume design; a very dark story with
some disgusting elements; a very unbearable musical style (the singing
is often embarassing, and not very well-made, and exposes some bad
acting). I like the ugly actor (the aid of the evil judge), but he&#x27;s a
little too clown-like to celebrate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Elephant Man (1980)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-elephant-man-1980/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-elephant-man-1980/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The filmmakers made sure that the disfigured man looked really
disgusting, and the idea is rather challenging, especially because I&#x27;d
lose my appetite if I shared a table. That doesn&#x27;t look very good
(what&#x27;s the difference between me and the racists?).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is too slow and not very interesting, as if the makers relied
only on the curiosity of this shitty-looking and not much else. Those
who mistreated this guy should have been portrayed in a more convincing
way, because they just look mindless, as if the director was desperate
to make them look bad, just in case we wouldn&#x27;t notice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shutter Island (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shutter-island-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shutter-island-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Me did not enjoy this psychological thriller starring an uninteresting
Leonardo Di Caprio. His character is investigating a missing patient in
some island prison for the criminally insane, and it drags on, inducing
sleep along the way. What&#x27;s the point?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Sixth Sense (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-sixth-sense-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-sixth-sense-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A rather tired supernatural thriller about a boy tormented by ghosts and
a psychologist trying to help him. There isn&#x27;t much of a story, so the
director over-stretches it, resulting overly-long and boring moments.
The boy&#x27;s mom is given the movie&#x27;s best performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Vanilla Sky (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/vanilla-sky-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/vanilla-sky-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;How do I review this? It&#x27;s a little weird and it makes me wonder why it
was made. There&#x27;s an interesting character in the form of an ugly
attorney, but it&#x27;s not a very fresh character. Penélope Cruz is also
interesting, but her character is also stale. Cameron Diaz&#x27;s is the
best character in the movie and some of her moments are quite painful
and hit a bit too close to home (check the complaint regarding lack of
commitment from her lover). She plays the role quite well too. The twist
is unexciting and the brain-teasing happenings not thrilling.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cars 2 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cars-2-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cars-2-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was not a big fan of the original, but this one is even worse. It also
happens to be an excuse to give more screen time to the rusty car that I
suppose was a big hit in the first movie. There was some decent humor
but nothing fresh. Some of the visual are pretty good, but
inconsistently so, as if it was hastily put together... &amp;quot;we gotta go
make millions quick&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lost In Space (1998)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lost-in-space-1998/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lost-in-space-1998/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember this beeing far more fascinating and the visual effects and
design great, but what&#x27;s left now is just a few interesting
performances (the 2 kids and Heather Graham) and some midly decent story
elements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Entrapment (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/entrapment-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/entrapment-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not very interesting, even with the ultra-gorgeous Catherine Zeta-Jones.
I didn&#x27;t get a chance to watch it all these years, even though I had
mild attraction due to my previous love for the featured item, the
Petronas Towers. The amount of money to be stolen by the lead characters
is ludicrous and is suitable only for comedies, or at least it should
have been more convincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Destination (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The initial scene, leading up to the point where wonderboy saves a few
lives, is handled very well, complete with good suspense. But it seems
that&#x27;s where all the effort in the movie went, because the rest is just
average fare. The story is quite thin, so there was a lot of boring
fillers (and uninteresting acting) just so the thing can last ~100
minutes. The villain wasn&#x27;t interesting either, though I remember
greater excitement on the first viewing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Colors (1988)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/colors-1988/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/colors-1988/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This was much more engaging when I was a kid, and it hasn&#x27;t aged well
at all. It&#x27;s an uninteresting and pointless story about two cops
patroling some dingy neighbourhood, and about the gangsters they come
across. The direction is dry and... ah, boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Basic Instinct (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/basic-instinct-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/basic-instinct-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though not as enjoyable as I was hoping this revisit to be, Sharon Stone
is still quite a pleasure to watch. Michael Douglas isn&#x27;t very
interesting nor is anyone else. The sexual energy was rather silly (did
we need to have near-rape in the story). Also, the movie isn&#x27;t aging
well (check the 80&#x27;s fashion for one).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Grown Ups (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/grown-ups-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/grown-ups-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There isn&#x27;t much going for this one, except I admire one of the
characters (in his early forties) falling in love with an elderly lady.
The movie is not unbearable but it should be given a miss. Chris Rock
shows again his extreme lack of acting skill and Salma Hayek hasn&#x27;t
lost her position as among the most beautiful women on the planet. That
old lady gives a nice performance BTW and she looks pretty for her age.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Hate Valentine&#x27;s Day (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-hate-valentine-s-day-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-hate-valentine-s-day-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This was dealt a harsh blow by critics and, although I don&#x27;t like it
much, I don&#x27;t see how it&#x27;s any worse than typical American romantic
comedies. It&#x27;s as annoying as they tend to be (hard-to-bear romance
with an overlong &#x27;sulking&#x27; period) but it has some good humor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Asterix and the Vikings (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/asterix-and-the-vikings-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/asterix-and-the-vikings-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I always found the characters of Asterix &amp;amp; Obelix series fascinating.
Most interesting was the kindly Obelix, the overweight warrior who
happens to be the toughest of them all. The voice talent he&#x27;s given
here is pretty good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this rather quirky movie, the more interesting character is Abba, the
daughter of the Viking king. She isn&#x27;t an originial creation, but her
sass, her tough-gal attitude, and her front-teeth gap makes her fun to
watch. I also liked the dumb son of the villain. There&#x27;s good humor
sprinkled all the place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bolt (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bolt-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bolt-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was attracted by the high-tech action, thinking that&#x27;s what the movie
was about, but I was soon disappointed; the all-too-common cheap
sentiments were unbearable; the humor, though not fresh (except the
begging-for-food part), was fun. Great voice talent and sound.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Das Experiment (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/das-experiment-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/das-experiment-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lacking the intensity of its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-experiment-2010&quot;&gt;remake&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and its lead character not as
heroic (and even annoying), I was left unsatisfied. For its remake, the
injustices begin very early during the movie (perhaps within 30
minutes), while for this one, they begins only in the last 30 minutes.
They however go way too far to be believable (e.g. attempted rape). The
romance is beautiful (did you see that gal!), but they just had to push
it as far as the gal having a part in the violence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Curious George (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/curious-george-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/curious-george-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The uninteresting first scene, that of the playful title character
having fun, made me not want to proceed to the rest, but the ultra-sweet
female love interest and the eye she had for the museum tour guide led
me on. It isn&#x27;t much, and has some unbearable and formulaic happenings
(e.g. the evil son of the museum owner, the break-up between the tour
guide, and the got-to-get-the-monkey-back shit). I managed to muster a
smile here and there as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gamer (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gamer-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gamer-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Intensely violent with some decent visuals here and there. Tries too
hard to impress with over-the-top scenarios and frantic action. The
billionaire villain was fun to watch, especially during the dance
sequence. I don&#x27;t remember the lady playing the talk show host this
sensual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Experiment (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-experiment-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-experiment-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Captivating but stupid and unexplained concept&#x2F;story; decent
performances; lovely romance (complete with a desirable gal); the sound
effects are overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;das-experiment-2001&quot;&gt;The original movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes this remake look better than it actually is;
but it&#x27;s sadly more pretentious... feels more &#x27;merely for show&#x27;; the
guys performing the experiment are even given godlike status, while
those in the original actually have faces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Librarian: Quest for the Spear (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-librarian-quest-for-the-spear-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-librarian-quest-for-the-spear-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Desperate in need of a decent budget (it&#x27;s a fantasy after all); the
concept is interesting, but the movie gets real stupid in its last
third, and the shitty action and unconvincing, B-movie villains don&#x27;t
help either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Red (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/red-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/red-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t like this much (John Malkovich was annoying, Morgan Freeman
uninteresting, and so was Bruce Willis and the girlfriend). But I really
like the eye-pleasing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rebecca_Pidgeon&quot;&gt;Rebecca Pidgeon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who plays the opponent&#x27;s boss.
I just wish that opponent would have been played by a better actor than
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Karl_Urban&quot;&gt;Karl Urban&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paper Man (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paper-man-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paper-man-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Too much in here is unbrearably irritating (the two imaginary
characters, the asshole boyfriend, the slapstick) and uninteresting. The
movie is a horrible experience, though that was eased by the warm
moments between the lead and the stupid (allowing self to be treated
like trash by irritating boyfriend) gal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rio (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rio-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rio-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the first third unbearable, and the whole thing is rather trite
and recycled. Things become better when the bird wearing a bottle cap as
a hat charms me. The street celebrations are beautiful. Regardless, this
isn&#x27;t Pixar-quality, complete with shitty, supposed-to-be-kool music
and singing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Inland Empire (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/inland-empire-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/inland-empire-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Excessively bizarre, and disturbing at times I couldn&#x27;t figure what the
fuck the story is about; the whole is unbearable, and the experience is
made worse by it&#x27;s 3hr length. How can people get away with so much
audience torture? Worse still, there are mainstream critics who called
it &lt;em&gt;brilliant&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. What did I miss?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Scar (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/scar-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/scar-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A run-of-the-mill horror that, luckily, has pretty gals and decent
camerawork. There is nothing new and the twist is underwhelming. What I
like about it is that it&#x27;s not pretentious, and is devoid of arrogance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people spend so much effort on a movie, I wonder how they the
justify the question, &lt;em&gt;what makes this stand above the rest?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Straightheads (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/straightheads-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/straightheads-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A revenge story, and not much else. The sexual spontaneity of the couple
deeds is strange, and isn&#x27;t justified. The story setup is made to look
like there was more than what actually transpired.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Grit (1969)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-1969/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-1969/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality direction can successfully mask an okay storyline. As evidence
of that, this sucky movie has a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;true-grit-2010&quot;&gt;a far better movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; based on that same
story. And it&#x27;s not like that much-younger movie takes advantage of
superior visuals of anything like that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also do not get the appeal of John Wayne; why did anyone thinks he&#x27;s
any interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paul (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paul-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paul-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s good humor to be had in here, but I expected more. The two
idiotic scifi lovers who help rescue the alien are played by the guys
who appeared in &lt;em&gt;Shaun of the Dead&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and they are fun to watch, most
especially the short one (he looks like an old woman). The alien they
are rescuing, the title character, is not interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Saw: The Final Chapter (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/saw-the-final-chapter-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/saw-the-final-chapter-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An early scene, involving the gal cheating on two guys, was very
promising. That our gal was so fine also did help, and is the fact that
the torture was on public display. This made it look like it actually
had a fatter budget, and this got me excited. The only other moment that
was well-done was the torture of the racist, and this is due to it&#x27;s
great production design and casting. The rest of the farce was worn out.
Luckily the movie was more enjoyable than it&#x27;s predecessor, &lt;em&gt;Saw IV&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole premise of the series is actually interesting (though I sure
hope no one would tries to imitate it), and I wish it was limited to the
initial ideology, whereby the victims&#x27; decisions involved only them.
But it seems to the writers that wasn&#x27;t exciting enough, and there was
instead an insistence on having it been done to others too, who were
often innocent (e.g. you go through some horrid torture OR your wife
dies). Sounds like desperate writing to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2008-10-12&quot;&gt;earlier review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of another in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Puppet Masters (1994)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-puppet-masters-1994/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-puppet-masters-1994/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Its concept of mind-controlling parasites is quite interesting, but its
action is not. I watched this forgettable movie a while ago (10+
years?). None of the acting is any good, but at least they got a real
gorgeous gal. The character design of the creatures is quite good, and I
especially like how they shape themselves when transported, before
spreading out their bodies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lost Battalion (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lost-battalion-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lost-battalion-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story is not interesting enough for this to be a cinema movie,
that&#x27;s why it went straight to tv. I hate watching a movie which makes
me impatient when it&#x27;s going to end. The interesting moments are too
few to make if worth a watch. One notion worth mentioning though is the
idea of sacrifice, that one high-ranking officer knowingly sacrificed an
unusual number of soldiers for the &#x27;greater&#x27; good. It&#x27;s not clear
what the standpoint of the movie is, but I suspect the writer leaned
more towards the brutality being worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] It would be interesting to know why attaching knives on
rifles stopped becoming fashionable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Road (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-road-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-road-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is better than the annoying &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-10-25&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Book of Eli&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but not as
interesting. The portrayal of the post-apocalyptic world is as grim as
it gets, and seems far more realistic than &lt;em&gt;Eli&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;i-am-legend&quot;&gt;I Am Legend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The
danger they face, where people kill and&#x2F;or eat each other for survival,
gives an edge to the movie as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mata Hari (1931)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mata-hari-1931/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mata-hari-1931/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This looks good for a movie so old. I expected some creaky stuff, due to
rotten film stock. Anyways, the title character, a spy, is extremely
uninteresting and is given a very unconvincing performance by Greta
Garbo. Similarly unconvincing and even caricatured is the general she
chills with, and worse still, her soon-to-be-lover.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sex And The City (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sex-and-the-city-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sex-and-the-city-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone might feel a need to slap me on my wrist, but I&#x27;m seriuosly not
a fan of romantic comedies&#x2F;chick flicks (I&#x27;m not the target market,
duh!). I&#x27;ve never been much interested in the tv show in which this is
based for similar reasons. But I relented, and in turn got punished by
2hr+ of age-old formula that made me hate the genre in the first place.
Regarding the story, the musings regarding sexual&#x2F;romantic relationships
are quite sickening (think &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;eat-pray-love-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eat Pray Love&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Eat Pray Love (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/eat-pray-love-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/eat-pray-love-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this one really unbearable and boring. There is decent acting,
but Julia Roberts is extremely uninteresting as a leading lady (I&#x27;ve
never enjoyed any of her performances). The story makes me curious if
the writers believe in the shit they are promoting (prayer; fortune
telling). On the bright side, the experiences in Italy were kinda fun,
and I felt longing for the warmth of the relationships created there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Farmhouse (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/farmhouse-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/farmhouse-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Edgy as horror movies tend to be, nothing special; an extremely bad
performance by the guy playing husband; I didn&#x27;t get it at the end...
I don&#x27;t know why the couple did what they did.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Percy Jackson &amp; The Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/percy-jackson-the-olympians-the-lightning-thief-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/percy-jackson-the-olympians-the-lightning-thief-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a weird one, with a silly title, and nice visual effects, and a
desirable gal in the form of the title character&#x27;s love interest. The
script is really stupid (e.g. one woman withstands the abuses of a
smelly man in order to keep her son safe, since the smell can hide the
son&#x27;s scent!) and the end empty like a mothafucka. They just sit there,
without dialog? So, so strange that you spend millions on technical
wizardry, but neglect to spend enough time developing the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/g-i-joe-the-rise-of-cobra-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/g-i-joe-the-rise-of-cobra-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice visual effects (check the suits) help rescue the shitty and
formulaic movie. The action is rather too loud, but the Paris chase
sequence deserves praise. I wish a better lead actor was chosen; I wish
there wasn&#x27;t no past romantic connection with him and the lady; I wish
there wan&#x27;t no past connection between the two best fighters: the
villainous one and the silent one. These are all badly-handled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Good Will Hunting (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/good-will-hunting-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/good-will-hunting-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I love stories about genius, but this one is as depressing as fuck.
Also, it&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Good_Will_Hunting#Reception&quot;&gt;waaay overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The one character that tries make it
colorful is Minnie Driver&#x27;s (the girlfriend), but like everyone else,
she isn&#x27;t convincing. She was designed to be super-cool, but it looks
fake and cheap, like a character I would create.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rashomon (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rashomon-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rashomon-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Of the highest-rated of Akira Kirosawa&#x27;s movies, &lt;em&gt;Rashomon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is given
the stature of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-samurai-1954&quot;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, if not more, but for me it&#x27;s just a
dumb story with bad acting. In fact I found its ridiculousness
unbearable in this revisit. Regardless, Toshiro Mifune is really an
interesting actor, but happened to be given a shitty role, where he
practically is a madman. I also enjoyed the performance of the inquisive
guy, though he overdoes it, not to mention silly grins and forced
laughter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
