<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/travel/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>a visit to Mozambique</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-mozambique/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-mozambique/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Outside my country, South Africa, I have only been to Botswana,
Swaziland, and Lesotho. I recently visited Mozambique, and it feels far
more different compared. The most notable thing is that Portuguese
dominates far more than English. It was quite hard to find people we (me
and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;tshepomathopa&quot;&gt;a friend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) could ask for help as we navigated its largest city,
Maputo. Other issues:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are too many people seeking to take advantage of foreigners,
like overpricing much of their shit, and gradually lowering them
when faced with protest. I suppose this shitty practice is found
everywhere, but it&#x27;s particularly rife there. At the border post,
for example, you&#x27;d have 3-4 guys trying to score something by
offering the service of guiding us through the border (fill this
form, queue here for this, etc.), and would ask for something like
R100 for that... ridiculous! Perhaps I should not complain given
the great poverty the country suffers... only desperate people
would behave like that I&#x27;m guessing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The condition of Maputo, the city we stayed at, is horrific. It
looks like a very run-down Durban, and quite large as well. We
didn&#x27;t explore it as much as I would have liked, but it&#x27;s such
pain, given the language barriers, as well as hardly having any
street names or markings on buildings. We were in bad need for a
guide. Most on the buildings are in a very dilapidated state. A very
rough guess is over 80% of them, though you&#x27;d find something
gorgeous here and there. The roads are heavily congested and the
drivers very inconsiderate... the worst I&#x27;ve seen. It&#x27;s amazing
there wasn&#x27;t a traffic accident we&#x27;ve witnessed. Anyways, it was
mostly not a pleasant city, and so many of the streets were damn
dirty. It&#x27;s fucked-up.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prices of stuff was ridiculous. One particularly egregious
example is the price of eggs as we saw in a franchise that also
operates in South Africa. A pack of 60 eggs went for M360 (about
R120)! That&#x27;s about twice the price in South Africa. Accommodation
was expensive too; the place we got cost about M2200 and that was
the cheaper one we could get, but was yet disappointing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were provided only a single pillow for each of us (separate
beds in one room), and it didn&#x27;t look pleasant for the
attendant to get us another.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was just one parking space. That I just don&#x27;t understand.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bed I was on was uncomfortable. I was discouraged from
complaining because it just felt like I was bothering the hosts,
and I had already complained about the not-cold water provided
in the room. I don&#x27;t like feeling like a bother.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hot water was rather luke-warm, though it wasn&#x27;t too much
of an issue given the high temperatures of the city. In
addition, the pressure of the water was quite low.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&#x27;t like it when one the senior workers asked us not to
drink alcohol (in case we were planning to) because he was
Muslim, and that it was a Muslim-owned place. Such arrogance!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sort of thing really lessened the enjoyment of the trip there. I
felt unwelcome really, and it made me miss my far-more-pleasant South
Africa. I am sure there is far less crime there, but South Africa is not
particularly scary either (in general). It also has far better and much
cheaper places to sleep. We could very well have missed some great
lodging places in Mozambique, that Maputo is just a shit place to be,
and we should have avoided it, who knows. We didn&#x27;t do much research on
it really, and decided to take a chance. It didn&#x27;t work out, but I&#x27;m
glad we tried. I would like to go some other time (I hear there&#x27;s great
beaches), but with proper guides, perhaps via a cruise ship.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, we just decided to cut our trip short, and went back to
South Africa.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>a visit to Lesotho</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-lesotho/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-lesotho/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Maseru is a lot better than I thought:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I expected something tiny and poor, but got pleasantly surprised. It
it pretty, and there were hardly any potholes. Sure there were
untarred roads as you move away from the center, but there were
hardly any shacks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was especially impressed by the parliament building... so
majestic, made better by them overlooking the city down below. I
feel it&#x27;s a bit of overkill though... imagine what it cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something I noticed is the overly smooth tile surfaces, which is a
health hazard. I saw it in 3 separate places:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A rather large mall, which is the only one I we saw&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fast food shop (where the food was very unimpressive; I&#x27;ve
never in my life been served a burger whose bread was so dry it
was hard)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A supermarket&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of service was rather horrible, and worse than any place
I&#x27;ve been to in South Africa. Worst of this was the place we stayed at:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the gate, there was some guy who looked very unexcited about his
life. He was just sitting there, his face looking down, and he
didn&#x27;t even give us a look. I guessed he was the security because
he had a two-way radio.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reception room was very stuffy... I wonder if the two ladies
noticed. I didn&#x27;t check if the windows were open. It must have been
a result of some serious cost-saving. At least our room had that
modern convenience.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While waiting to check if a room is available, the lady openly asked
some other worker to check if the room is clean. I asked what
happens if it isn&#x27;t, and she said she&#x27;d just send us away. Weird.
Not even &amp;quot;I&#x27;d get it cleaned right away for you, sir&amp;quot; or
something like that.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went away to do a city tour and came back late, so it was quite
dark. There was no lighting on the path the the room, so one had to
tread carefully.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#x27;s normal practice for the light switch to be near the door, but
not in this case. And it was so dark that we had to ask for
assistance, and the light switch was near the bed.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They guy that helped us with the light switch seriously needed a
bath. He didn&#x27;t look friendly either. I felt like we were a bother.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What wasn&#x27;t near the bed, though, was a power socket (to keep my
laptop charged), so I went out to ask for an extension cord, only to
find there isn&#x27;t any spare... it was used for the washing machine.
Yep.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was curious what was on TV, and found horrible reception... no
digital channels. There was no remote control either. When I asked,
it was simply missing. Also, the price sticker for the TV was still
affixed on it... 4,999 (Lesotho currency is valued the same as
South African rands).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe there wasn&#x27;t much they could do about this, but there wasn&#x27;t
water in the morning so we could bath and get the fuck out. The
receptionist said the issue was in the area.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, this is maybe the best on: before we could leave, they didn&#x27;t
open the gate for us before first checking the room. My guess is
they ensured we didn&#x27;t steal anything. The receptionist did earlier
claim they wanted to check if we didn&#x27;t leave anything. Maybe
that&#x27;s true :)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that explains the price... the room cost M290 for the night, for
both of us. Ridiculous cheap. We thought the price was per person. I
wanna check out some other super-cheap places elsewhere to ensure this
is the kind of service one should expect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, we went on to drive towards Hlotse, a town to the West of
Maseru. The road was quite good, and the view wonderful (Lesotho is a
beautiful country). Still, I didn&#x27;t see much evidence of ridiculous
poverty for the whole 100km drive. It was interesting to see that the
traffic cops didn&#x27;t have cars around. Serious cost-saving there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thing, the Lesotho side of the border stamped our passports
when leaving, but didn&#x27;t when we entered. Interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>another visit to Eastern Cape</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/another-visit-to-eastern-cape/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/another-visit-to-eastern-cape/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;a-visit-to-eastern-cape&quot;&gt;Last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I raved about my experiences at a friend&#x27;s home place,
Nyosini. My memory is not to be completely trusted, but this second (or
third, if we count attending &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;one-less-angel&quot;&gt;a funeral&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) one was even better. Such
hospitality is what I feel most people on the planet have never
experienced. We (me and two friends, who were just as impressed) were
treated like royalty. We slept there just one night though, so we spent
nearly all our time there in one yard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never seen a family quite like this. My own (maternal) family is
quite close, but definitely not as kindly as this one. And by the way,
there are no exceptions. The love they have, and express, for each other
is... damn I wish I could express self better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met Bongo again, and the guy&#x27;s character hasn&#x27;t changed a bit...
maybe even more shy than last time, I can&#x27;t tell. Lwazi and Siya
weren&#x27;t there (boarding school).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could say it was me (us?) paying homage to that wonderful family
(it&#x27;s been over 3 years), but also an excuse to go enjoy the warmth of
their welcome, not to mention the gorgeous scenery of the surrounding
hills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>a visit to Botswana</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-botswana/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-botswana/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I finally went to this neighbouring country of ours,
Botswana. This was the first time I ever left South Africa. I was
welcomed by wonderful people, and the visit was limited to its largest
city +++ Gaborone +++ which is beautiful, sparse, and vast, when
compared to my country&#x27;s own cities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of its residents got shocked when I argued that South Africa
doesn&#x27;t have a unifying identity; I argued that the country is too
diverse to have such. Instead she argued that such is country&#x27;s very
strength which led to her pointing out the following wins:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diverse (and therefore strong) economy; she stated Botswana is
over-reliant on diamonds&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diverse tourist attractions; Botswana&#x27;s tourism is nearly
non-existent in comparison&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diverse export market; Botswana is all diamonds, again&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;press freedom - my input, which she agreed with&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high foreign investment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diverse cultures&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;high media production standards; Botswana has only one tv channel
and the little exposure I got of it expresses amateurish levels of
production&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passionate people (highlighting freedom fighters that enabled black
rule; highlighting the toyi-toyi culture)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation opened my eyes a little bit, that there&#x27;s a lot to
appreciate about South Africa. As I talked to more Botswana residents,
and read one critical piece of journalistic writing, Botswana, despite
being far more peaceful and having superior living standards (minimal
crime, kindly people, minimal poverty, far-reaching welfare), has some
serious smelly bits: abortion and homosexuality are illegal. I was
shocked by these two, and most especially about the second one. What the
fuck!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>a visit to Eastern Cape</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-eastern-cape/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-visit-to-eastern-cape/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the beautiful countryside of Nyosini, a small (a few hundred
households?) rural village nearby a buzzing Mount Frere, a town set atop
a hill of the same name. This &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Eastern_Cape&quot;&gt;Eastern Cape&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; village is the home of a
friend of mine and the visit happened to be an excuse to see the
province for the first time in my life, and the highlight was the
amazing hospitality granted by the home we stayed during most of the
visit, and the closeness of family I experienced here is unmatched in
memory. Notable and positive mention ought be granted to 3 characters
(Lwazi, Bongo, Siya) for reasons I&#x27;m too lazy to mention.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;another-visit-to-eastern-cape&quot;&gt;another visit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
