<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/tv/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>top tv shows</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/top-tv-shows/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/top-tv-shows/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The list is roughly in the chronological order of the first time I
watched them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yizo Yizo (seasons 1 and 2)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game of Thrones (seasons 1 to 6)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homeland&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utopia&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Girls (seasons 1 and 2)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;House of Cards (seasons 1 and 2)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Knick&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;honorable mentions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alphas&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Americans&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bodyguard (season 1)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Leftovers - Season 2 Episode 1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tv episodes have left as much an impact on me as this bizarre one. I
was reeling from it for days after watching it first time, and I hardly
ever re-visit tv shows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performances are without flaw. My one favorite is that of they guy
playing the fireman. He delivers one of the most impressive performances
I&#x27;ve seen yet. He&#x27;s such a pleasure to watch. Equally irresistible is
the gal playing his daughter. The character development given these two
is amazing. Playing the mother is Regina King and what is the only one
her performances I&#x27;ve really enjoyed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a strange choice of events which don&#x27;t serve the story in any
obvious way, but they add to the enjoyment, and are given excellent
direction:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incident with the scientist taking water samples&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brief and quiet moment showing the girls in the car&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The girls running naked&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prison confession&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sherlock - Season 3 Episode 3</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Episode 0 of Season 1, which was remade into Episode 1, got me excited
about the series. I loved the villain (superb performance), and it had
great humor (Dr. Watson character). None of the later Episodes could
match, all but the third (and last) of the third Season. The highlight
here is the villain, who ranks as the best in the series (Moriarty is
rather overdone). He represents great character development and is given
a flawless performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sidenote, of the series regulars, none of the characters was as
interesting as that of Sherlock&#x27;s big brother. It&#x27;s a superb
performance too, the character is such a joy (mature, wise,
influential), and he was made all the more interesting to later discover
that his intelligence matched that of Sherlock.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Person of Interest - Season 2 Episode 16</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/person-of-interest-season-2-episode-16/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/person-of-interest-season-2-episode-16/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of the series, &lt;em&gt;Person of Interest&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There is much to
celebrate, among which is the wonderful portrayal of the brilliant
creator of the machine that (illegally) looks for patterns in society so
as to predict, with high certainty, which people will be involved in
violent crimes, either as victims or perpetrators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series&#x27; normal formula is that our heroic, bespectacled hero would
mention the details of the new person, and his very capable sidekick, a
former assassin, would go follow this person, to try avert the impending
crime. In the 16th episode of the 2nd season, however, this formula
isn&#x27;t followed (by the camera). Instead we follow the person who would
be victim, and our heroes only appear midway through, like they were
secondary characters. It&#x27;s beautiful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love it when such breaks from normal routine occur, especially when
they are as well-made. Not to say this is the best episode of this
series so far (I can think of a few which were superior), nor was this
the first time such a break from normal routine occur (there were some
in the earlier episodes of the season), but it felt fresh enough to be
worth a mention in this blog of mine. What added to the excitement is
that it was the first time in the series that a so-called Relevant&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
crime prevention was showed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means &lt;em&gt;relevant&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to (U.S.) national security. This is as
opposed to the sort solved by our heroes, which only involve civil
cases.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Battlestar Galactica - Season 3 Episode 20</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/battlestar-galactica-season-3-episode-20/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/battlestar-galactica-season-3-episode-20/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hardly ever write anything about tv productions regardless of how
many times I tend to get impressed, and there hasn&#x27;t been a shortage of
that. That&#x27;s mainly due to laziness&#x2F;motivation, but this time I just
have to mention this one gem.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very last episode of the Season mainly focuses on the trial of one
former president who is accused of treason due to surrendering to the
cylons (a species created by humans) as well as giving them official
approval to execute dozens of people. The defence given by an assistant
lawyer is a masterpiece, and would match well with any court thing I&#x27;ve
seen in my tv&#x2F;movie-watching history. The performance matches as well,
and that&#x27;s interesting because the performer&#x2F;character combination is
among the least interesting in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sidenote, I find this Season to be the best (in a series of four),
because it covers more interesting events (the capturing of the humans,
the resistance, their eventual rescue, and a lot more, best of which was
the trial of course).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This positiveness could make it look like I&#x27;m a huge fan of the series,
but I&#x27;m not. There&#x27;s a whole lot of religious non-sense that I can&#x27;t
bear, some seriously annoying characters, at least overly eccentric one,
too much day-dreaming, some too-stupid plot decisions... but Episode 20
goes some way to help me forgive the rest of the shit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>SABC 1 glory</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sabc-1-glory/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sabc-1-glory/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I got captivated by the new SABC 1 theme presentation (for lack of a
better name), which is a fusion of computer animation and live footage
with reddish filtering, an artistic impression reminding me of the
visual landmark that is 300. It&#x27;s however not nearly as popular or
memorable as the previous theme which portrayed South African Black and
White people having switched roles (as in White people living in
townships and Black people leading a more affluent lifestyle). This, the
latter, is an interesting play on the stereotypical both races have on
each other and was notably also because of the superb camerawork and
some interesting acting. It&#x27;s interesting as regards the former for I
thought the latter couldn&#x27;t be bettered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
