<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/substandard/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Star Trek Into Darkness (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/star-trek-into-darkness-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/star-trek-into-darkness-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept of a spaceship that can double as a submarine is
interesting, but there&#x27;s not much else to celebrate in this otherwise
not-boring movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>John Carter (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/john-carter-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/john-carter-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre story (powerful beings screw around with affairs of entire
planets), and a hero with unexplained powers and flashbacks (unless I
missed the explanation). I do, however, appreciate superb character
design of the four-arm humanoids, even though their look and behavior is
similar to that of the giants of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;avatar-2009&quot;&gt;Avatar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men Origins: Wolverine (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-origins-wolverine-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-origins-wolverine-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The worst in the X-Men movies, it just feels like an excuse to milk the
brand. Fact that the production was troubled probably explains it. None
of the visual effects are any good, and the location of the final fight,
top of the cooling towers, was quite stupid... why did Wolverine go
there? Also, why did my favorite guy had to wear such a stupid and
unconvincing fat suit? Horrible!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect 2 (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only because of my great love for &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2004&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It
feels like a student effort, and is just not interesting, and therefore
challenged my perseverance a bit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however like two of the characters, the criminals who want their
money back. The guys playing them give superb performances. One other
quality performance is that of company boss, while the best friend is
not so bad in parts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Snow White and the Huntsman (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/snow-white-and-the-huntsman-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/snow-white-and-the-huntsman-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I went into this one with high anticipation, only to be met with lots of
careless direction, as if the thing was rushed. It is also the worst
performance of Charlize Theron in memory, and the only one I found
embarassing. However, the worst performance in the movie is that of the
lead character.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are isolated moments of beauty and decent visual effects. Not one
of the seven dwarfs are interesting, even though many were portrayed by
good actors. Why didn&#x27;t they use real dwafs?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hunger Games (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If we ignore the shallow non-sense about Americanism, I find &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tnr.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;film&#x2F;102038&#x2F;the-hunger-games-collins-lawrence-ross-terrible-un-american&quot;&gt;this
review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, among the few negative ones on the movie, very true. I find the
movie an uninteresting waste of time, and therefore it&#x27;s appeal is
mysterious to me. As mentioned in the review, there is a glaring lack of
explanation on the cruel situation some of the people find themselves
in. Not even the visual effects are really good, though I liked the
visual design of some of the sets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Streetcar Named Desire (1951)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-streetcar-named-desire-1951/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-streetcar-named-desire-1951/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The direction is shitty and the performances unbearably-irritating, most
especially the mentally-challended leading character (by Vivien Leigh).
As if that&#x27;s not enough, there&#x27;s also a horrible asshole played by
Marlon Brando. The only believable character is that of the lady
upstairs, though she isn&#x27;t given much screen time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is among the most irritatingly-unbearable movies I&#x27;ve yet seen.
How the movie, and its performances, got so much praise is hard to
fathom. What the fuck!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Trade (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/trade-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/trade-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The pretty brother of the gal who gets kidnapped for sex should have
been given less screen time. Either that or more acting classes. Same
applies to his sister, the victim, though to a greater extent. I wonder
if Kevin Kline took the role because his career isn&#x27;t doing so good, or
because of the subject matter (one would hope for the latter). I wonder
what&#x27;s up with the guy driving the victims to their fates. He
represents a failed attempt at a portrayal of a bad guy with some good
inside of him, but is given a real poor performance. In conclusion, I
really think the director is bad, and should not have been allowed to
head a movie that carries such an important message.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Arthur (1981)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/arthur-1981/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/arthur-1981/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rottentomatoes.com&#x2F;m&#x2F;1001240-arthur&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The world&#x27;s critics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; amaze me again, with their love for this
uninteresting and (mostly) unfunny comedy. Someone even nominated it for
its script. WTF! &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;arthur-2011&quot;&gt;The sequel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a lot better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some appeal to the lead performer, but he&#x27;s mostly just
annoying. None of the other performances are particularly good, except
of course &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;John_Gielgud&quot;&gt;the guy playing the caregiver&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who never fucks up anyways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Fantasy VII Advent Children (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was a lot more impressed the first time I saw this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity and technical sophistication of the fight sequences are
what &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy only dreamed of. It&#x27;s the best piece of
action I&#x27;ve seen so far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a revisit, I feel like that first statement is an exagerration,
even though the action really is good. Problem is that it&#x27;s just too
frantic, such that it&#x27;s hard to notice what the fuck is going on. With
that in mind, the second statement is no longer true.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the movie unbearable, and I find it strange that I managed first
time around. I found all the talk of life force or somesuch silly, I
found the characters uninteresting, I found the obsession with
children&#x27;s innocence overdone, I found the obsession with beautiful
boys and girls needless, I found the character design (worst of which
was the monster flying creature) to be of intensely bad taste, I found
the choice of lighting shitty, I found the (seeming) requirement to have
familiarity with the games the movie is based in order to appreciate the
(complex) backstory stupid, ...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Notebook (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-notebook-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-notebook-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If found the largest part of the movie unbearably bad, and the very
uninteresting performances of the two leads didn&#x27;t help. The movie
attempts to be a great romance, but there&#x27;s nothing fresh nor is there
anything really interesting. Also, it&#x27;s mostly a period movie, but none
of the costumes impress, and the production design is even worse,
reminiscent of made-for-tv stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Judge Dredd (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/judge-dredd-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/judge-dredd-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So someone spent close to $100m on this, and then classified it as
ready for release! One of the mysteries of movie-making. It is mildly
entertaining, but the visual effects are so bad (was it this bad in the
mid-90s?), the storyline so lacking, and characters so thin. I did
however like 2 character designs:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the oversized (and scary) robot&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they guy with a metal head&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a far better take on the title character, see &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dredd-2012&quot;&gt;Dredd&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tai Chi Boxer (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tai-chi-boxer-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tai-chi-boxer-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another case where white people are portrayed as both retarded and
cruel, with bad performers. The lead actor is fun to watch and the
leading is a pleasure to the eye. All characters are shallow as fuck but
the martial arts are decent, though often uninteresting and some fights
are too long. The hair thing is ludicrous.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Sunset Limited (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-sunset-limited-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-sunset-limited-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This I watched merely for the sake of curiosity: the entire movie takes
place in a single room and has only two characters engaged in one long
conversation. They discuss a number of issues (god, suicide, jail, bad
deeds, friendship...). Samuel L. Jackson is as unsatisfying (and noisy)
as usual while Tommy Lee Jones should have done something more fitting
of his acting skills. It happens to be mainly noise about nothing, and
me wonders what the point is (life sucks?). Beware of some really bad
usage of sound effects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ferris Bueller&#x27;s Day Off (1986)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/ferris-bueller-s-day-off-1986/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/ferris-bueller-s-day-off-1986/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbearably slow pacing, maybe the worst I&#x27;ve experienced yet. The gal
playing jealous sister is desirable, while the guy playing friend gives
a decent performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Princess Mononoke (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/princess-mononoke-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/princess-mononoke-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this with high expectation, due the high critical acclaim it
possesses, but now have to wonder that the fuck is wrong with these
people. The story, an epic, resonates a bit with environmental care, so
I guess that&#x27;s part of its appeal, but the animation and visual design
is crappy as hell, and so is the dialog (likely partly because of shitty
translation).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Passion of the Christ (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-passion-of-the-christ-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-passion-of-the-christ-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much of a story, and all could have fit inside an hour, but the
makers decided to drag it on and on, with a fanatical lust for
showcasing extreme brutality. I found it to be a very good movie first
time I watched, but a revisit proves to damn unbearable. There way too
much screen presence of mother+prostitute duo; the conception of Satan
is both needless and badly done. It&#x27;s bad direction, and it makes me
wonder what the fuck Mel Gibson (director) was thinking. Maybe this is
his form of (expensive) masturbation, given that he&#x27;s a Christian and
all, so he maybe wasn&#x27;t thinking straight, perhaps obsessed of showing
just how much the lord suffered for us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Swordfish (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/swordfish-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/swordfish-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;John Travolta is interesting but the movie is the opposite, and is badly
written. It desperately tries to feel kool and fails, except for
Travolta, who sadly plays the same character he &#x27;always&#x27; plays (no
effort). Halle Berry is extra pretty, but her character is shit and so
is everyone else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Something Borrowed (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/something-borrowed-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/something-borrowed-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some day I should simply stop punishing myself so much. I should learn
to quit the first sign I see trouble. My problem is high levels of
curiosity, for I&#x27;m often worried what I must miss, while wary of
passing judgement on a movie before watching its entirety.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s kinda hard to find an original and good romantic drama&#x2F;comedy, and
worse still, they tend to wallow in unbearable cheesiness. This one is
worsened by uninteresting leads, the Tom Cruise and Kirsten Dunst
look-alikes. It&#x27;s fucking weird how come movies like this still get
made at all, because there&#x27;s absolutely nothing new in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/who-framed-roger-rabbit-1988/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/who-framed-roger-rabbit-1988/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly uninteresting and irritating mixture of 2D animation and live
action, which luckily has an ultra-sexy wife of the title character. No
one else is interesting, unless you want to mention the brief appearance
of the pig &amp;quot;that&#x27;s all folks&amp;quot; and Bugs Bunny. The movie is also badly
directed and acted, and it&#x27;s strange considering that the director is
Robert Zemeckis. Maybe the producers (the money people) got in the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Confucius (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/confucius-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/confucius-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An embarassing lead performance by Chow Yun Fat; with the help of
unimpressive direction and script, it showcases silly ancient Chinese
traditions, as if they were somehow virtuous. Oh, and I still wondered
what&#x27;s so great the title character did for the world, other than at
times using his influence to try exert kindness to his world. I would
have preferred some time spent on explaining how he actually gained that
influence... and I&#x27;m not visiting his Wikipedia article.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monty Python&#x27;s Quest for the Holy Grail (1975)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s funny moments but the whole thing feels more like a collection
of sketches than a unit commonly knows as &lt;em&gt;a movie&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;a film&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among my favorite moments is when an anarchist explains to the baffled
king about how his community operates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain America: The First Avenger (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of its moments are so bad that they are hard to bear. There&#x27;s some
uninteresting acting too, e.g. the frail Captain America and the love
interest. None of the other performances are really good, and the
villain is embarassingly bad, as if from some low-budget sci-fi movie.
The script is bad and it&#x27;s strange that the movie comes from the same
studio as &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There isn&#x27;t even decent visual effects to lessen
the pain. Luckily, the final-form Captain America hero is fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>My Big Fat Greek Wedding (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/my-big-fat-greek-wedding-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/my-big-fat-greek-wedding-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An okay and shallow romantic comedy; there&#x27;s some bad make-up for the
lead character in her early scenes; none of the acting is any good and
the male romantic lead is especially bad, as if he&#x27;s embarassed or
something; it&#x27;s interesting watching warm human relationships like the
Greeks in the movie have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Midnight Meat Train (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-midnight-meat-train-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-midnight-meat-train-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After watching what felt like a waste of time, I was surprised to find
that &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Midnight_Meat_Train#Reception&quot;&gt;there were those who found it decent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The villain is given a
laughably bad performance by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Vinnie_Jones&quot;&gt;Vinnie Jones&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I don&#x27;t remember any of
his work any good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parts of the movie are decent:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the intrigue the lead character goes through as he unravels the
mystery that is the serial killer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lady our lead character tries to impress with his art&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Penance (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/penance-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/penance-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An okay torture movie where a number of strippers get abducted by a
religious nut claiming to cleanse them of sin. It&#x27;s pretty much stupid
and made worse by its ineffective documentary style. Luckily, the acting
isn&#x27;t bad, though only &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Rooker&quot;&gt;Michael Rooker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; stands out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Planet 51 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/planet-51-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/planet-51-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When you got recycled (and shallow and stupid) material, the least you
can do is make it interesting. On the bright side, character animation
for the human when in the large spacesuit is fun to watch, especially
when dancing on stage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Let Me In (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/let-me-in-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/let-me-in-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An exercise in embarassment. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;let-the-right-one-in-2008&quot;&gt;The first novel-to-movie adaptation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was
released only 2-3 years before. I thought they wanted to offer something
else, maybe a budget, with some visual flair. But there&#x27;s nothing. In
fact there is an uninteresting &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Elias_Koteas&quot;&gt;Elias Koteas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the investigator (there
was basically none in the earlier movie), and the companion of the
vampire (played by an extrememly uninteresting &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Richard_Jenkins&quot;&gt;Richard Jenkins&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who
bored me horrendously in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;eat-pray-love-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eat Pray Love&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). But these greedy
motherfuckas just wanted to exploit a good story, and give nothing in
return. In fact, the even got lazy, walking briskly over material that
was dealth with more depth in the first movie. But, I don&#x27;t know the
details of the novel, so who knows, they might be more faithful than the
first movie. So I guess they just wanted to make an extra buck from an
audience that&#x27;s too lazy to read subtiles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While watching this, I kept wondering if would I give it more praise had
I not seen (or known) about the original movie. I&#x27;m not sure, because
it comes across as yet-another-horror movie, even though there&#x27;s a gal
vampire. But that&#x27;s not exactly a new concept (remember &lt;em&gt;Interview With
A Vampire&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). It&#x27;s not even remotely interesting. What&#x27;s most puzzling,
beyond that the shit (it&#x27;s not that smelly, I just hate it) got made is
the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Let_Me_In_(film)#Critical_response&quot;&gt;positive response&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; it received from critics. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An unbearably-uninteresting and badly-made take on the legend of Dracula
(Gary Oldman), the world&#x27;s first vampire. It&#x27;s rather shocking that it
was made by the great Francis Ford Coppola, and it&#x27;s probably his
worst. A better (character development; acting) vampire can be found in
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nosferatu_the_Vampyre&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nosferatu&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (1979). Winona Ryder is quite bad as the vampire&#x27;s
lover, though not as much as Keanu Reeves (who also has a face so
gorgeous).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of the vampire&#x27;s shadow, which defies physics, is rather
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Chronicles of Narnia: Prince Caspian (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-prince-caspian-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-prince-caspian-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As so often happens, it baffles me why so many critics &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Chronicles_of_Narnia:_Prince_Caspian#Reception&quot;&gt;found this any
good&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The only thing worthy of praise is the sea good, who happens to
embody some of the best water effects I&#x27;ve seen yet. Everything else
was just bland (cinematography, costumes, battles, acting, story,
production and creature design, character development), just like the
first movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lazarus Project (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lazarus-project-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lazarus-project-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Slow pacing gives it a feeling of self-importance, and makes it boring,
especially after lethal injection. Having a bad actor as lead doesn&#x27;t
help either. Luckily, the other performances aren&#x27;t so bad, though none
is any spectacular. The twist is rather implausible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves (1991)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robin-hood-prince-of-thieves-1991/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robin-hood-prince-of-thieves-1991/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It isn&#x27;t aging well and has nothing going for it: not it&#x27;s story,
it&#x27;s performances, or its direction. It&#x27;s formulaic as hell, and humor
doesn&#x27;t work. Being led by an extremely uninteresting Kevin Costner as
title character doesn&#x27;t help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nanny McPhee (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this one hard to bear. If I saw it first, I would likely not
have given it&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010&quot;&gt;far superior sequel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a chance. It&#x27;s strange that they
were written by one person, because it&#x27;s full of formulaic family
values, and stuff that is so stupid it makes me cringe. Even Emma
Thompson sucks. The only enjoyable character is the caricatured cook.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Stepfather (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first scene is classic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decent acting (my fave is hose salesperson)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pretty ladies (my fave is hose salesperson, and the son&#x27;s
girlfriend)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice cinematography (the atmosphere fits the subject matter)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just another murder thriller, adding nothing new to the genre, and
with a shitty story; the writers just didn&#x27;t know what to do with
the killer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-stepfather-1987&quot;&gt;The earlier movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is much better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Unstoppable (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/unstoppable-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/unstoppable-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought that the critics would be with me with this for being not
great, but [they actually liked it]. That&#x27;s strange for I didn&#x27;t see
anything worthy in it. In fact there&#x27;s some stupid things: there were
cars parked right next to where the attempted derailment was; some train
driver manages to keep the speed of the train super-humanly constant,
when driving in reverse. More annoying is the subplot regarding the
conductor&#x27;s troubled marriage, which is maybe as bad as Denzel
Washington&#x27;s uninteresting performance. The guy is just plain
overrated, and always plays himself (instead of seeing the character he
plays, I see him playing the character).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also no character development. If you are not going to bother
creating decent characters, at least try make them interesting. Well, at
least the daughters of Denzel are pretty, but they are nothing other
than filler material. They tried make them interesting by having them
work at a strip-club though, which reminded me of Will Smith&#x27;s stripper
gal in &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. None of these served the story in any way, so
it&#x27;s a strange distraction in my eyes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[they actually liked it]:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sunset Boulevard (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sunset-boulevard-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sunset-boulevard-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is typical of those unbearable age-old Hollywood movies. It&#x27;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sunset_Boulevard_(film)#Stature&quot;&gt;overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as hell, and I&#x27;m now curious what it&#x27;s appeal was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He may be a caricature, but the butler is interesting to watch.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wannabe writer is so wantable, and so is her friend.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shitty storyline.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unconvincing scenarios.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overacting by the lead lady, playing a yesteryear star.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Alpha &amp; Omega (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/alpha-omega-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/alpha-omega-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Stale (nothing new) and second-rate animation and story; the main love
interest is charming, but the movie&#x27;s best is the French golfer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>(500) Days of Summer (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/500-days-of-summer-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/500-days-of-summer-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Tries so hard to be fresh, and although its back-and-forth is unique, it
doesn&#x27;t rescue the movie from being yet-another-romantic-drama. It&#x27;s
ineffective, and there&#x27;s nothing refreshing, and it&#x27;s attempt at
trying to make it different makes it unbearable. I was surprised that it
got such &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;(500)_Days_of_Summer#Critical_reception&quot;&gt;good ratings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One fresh concept I gotta applaud is the Expectations&#x2F;Reality thing,
where two scenes are put side-by-side, one real and one not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wall Street: Money Never Sleeps (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wall-street-money-never-sleeps-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wall-street-money-never-sleeps-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production design; check the home of the father (Michael Douglas)
and the office of the billionaire (Josh Brolin)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinematography; the best moments are near the end&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Susan Sarandon is both beautiful and lovely&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feels like a desperate attempt to live off the shine of the 80&#x27;s
(overrated) original&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the slow pacing and stale direction made me go &amp;quot;when does it end?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is stale&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lead actor is miscast, and exposes his lack of talent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-review-2009&quot;&gt;first review (2009)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the 2nd &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie is going to have superior visual
effects to its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-2007&quot;&gt;predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but nothing more groundbreaking. You oughta
love the destruction of the aircraft carrier though. And the same
complaint I had with the first one is that there&#x27;s way too much going
on as regards the action such that I can&#x27;t keep up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears I wasn&#x27;t the only one who loved the human hero&#x27;s parents in
the first movie, as evidenced by their far greater screen presence here,
and they don&#x27;t misstep here too. But they don&#x27;t help advance the
story, which is pretty much non-existent anyways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember anything believable, and at the end of it ya feel like
&lt;em&gt;what a waste!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but then the entire concept of the Transformers is
pre-juvenile anyways!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;second-review-2010&quot;&gt;second review (2010)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit of &lt;em&gt;The Transformers 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; was an unpleasant experience. It makes
apparent the farce&#x2F;silliness the entire concept actually is. I am
especially annoyed by the impossible survival our heroes have, and worse
still, none of the members of the military are any interesting. It&#x27;s
nearly unbearable and just too noisy. It&#x27;s as bad as the first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-review-2007&quot;&gt;first review (2007)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching this spectacle, the greatest so far this year, I kept
wondering which has superior visual effects if compared to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pirates-of-the-caribbean-3&quot;&gt;Pirates of
the Caribbean 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It wins in terms of spectacle due to the far larger
activity going on all over the screen and it&#x27;s really unbelieavable how
seemingly no cash was spared, and it&#x27;s only since King Kong (2005) have
I been so overwhelmed by sheer size. Interestingly, I can&#x27;t single out
a favorite effect because they are all over the place (the scorpion
battle, the city battle, the transformers).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead performer is quite impressive and so is the mother, who
provides among the movie&#x27;s finest comic moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the movie isn&#x27;t pretentious (say the ridiculous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;spider-man-3-2007&quot;&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)
about its seriousness, feeling like a mere crowd-pleaser, and what a
crowd-pleaser it is! This fact allows one to enjoy it pretty well,
disregarding plot-holes and other deficiencies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;second-review-2008&quot;&gt;second review (2008)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This revisit turned into a frustrating exercise since I noted too many
compositing errors, unimpressive production design (especially for such
an expensive movie), worse cinematography (unbearable and overdone
lighting), and cardboard characters, none being believable. This is not
even mentioning some really bad casting choices (Anthony Anderson
playing the best computer cracker; the entire heroic soldier crew).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformations are overwhelming (as if that&#x27;s supposed to be an
advantage) and there&#x27;s way more action than necessary... I could not
keep up. Worse still, none of it is believable (e.g. we get our nerdy
hero getting serious physical pounding without getting hurt, or acting
all calm while a multi-ton machine falls very close-by).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the entire concept is god-damn silly, but then &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
managed to get away with its own silly concept (machines &#x27;farming&#x27;
human energy... WTF!) by being better elsewhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
