<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/gaming/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>God of War trilogy</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The last time I played any of the 3 games from the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_(series)&quot;&gt;God of War&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; trilogy
was nearly 2 years ago, but the experience still lives vividly in my
mind; they offered among the greatest gaming experiences I ever had. I
haven&#x27;t played any of the other 4 games in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known about the first game for years, before playing it, and it
was among the top of my wishlist. The appeal was simply the imagery of
the angry lead character (Kratos), the giants he was portrayed to
battle, the setting (ancient Greek mythology), as well as the title.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally managed to get my hands on the games (about 2 years ago),
they did not disappoint. The epic feel of it all, the character design
(the best ever that covers ancient Greek mythology), and (as regards
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_III&quot;&gt;God of War III&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) impressive realism, makes for a fantastic series.
Sadly, this trilogy is only available for PlayStation (2 &amp;amp; 3).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hercules (demigod, son of Zeus), who appears in the 3rd game of the
trilogy, is a mini-giant with a massive muscle structure and an
interesting attitude, not to mention armed with some awesomely large
and powerful weapons, that the playable character (Kratos) luckily
gets to play with. The moment where this Hercules character appears
is among my most favorite battle scenes in the whole trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades (God of the Underworld), who we also only get to fight in the
3rd game of the trilogy, is another great design, and his underworld
the best environment of the whole trilogy. His assortment of weapons
is also quite impressive, but the battle involving him, though quite
good, could be more epic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Centaur#Centaur_General&quot;&gt;Centaur General&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (human-horse being) were quite a presence. Not
only were they rather tough to beat, but they were also the most
charming characters in the whole trilogy. One wishes they had a
greater screen time. Note that there were other Centaurs in the
trilogy, but these particular ones were most interesting, and their
slaying most... beautiful. They appear first time in the 3rd game
in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poseidon (God of the Sea), is an interesting one. His represents the
most complex (and hardest) fight sequence in the entire trilogy, it
it also happens on the third installment of this fine trilogy. It&#x27;s
not exactly my favorite, but his character has a certain level of
charm, and the final kill is particularly brutal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kratos, the protagonist, was most impressive in the first game, but
he was getting less interesting later on and the novelty of his
anger was wearing off. He was also getting petty at times, and too
bloodthirsty to be convincing. Regardless, he is a work of superb
character design, and this well-enhanced by the pale color and red
stripes on his skin, as well as a body that makes him look like pure
lethal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Stone_Talos&quot;&gt;Stone Talos&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are a one-of-a-kind character... muscular stone
statues that come to life to incur damage on our protagonist.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome as it is, the series does have weaknesses:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one notable bad work of character design, which is Ares,
the original god of war (a title Kratos took from him after
defeating him). He is totally uninresting (and clumsy), and the
battle in which the two fight is the worst in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One other horrible character was the goat-snake-lion combo
character. It was probably a first in gaming history, but it was a
real stupid idea.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were also some particilarly hard stages to pass, where I had
to ask for help from a friend to proceed to the next level. I hate
stuff like that... I normally pick the easiest difficulty level in
games, for I hate to struggle for too long.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zero Punctuation rocks</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zero-punctuation-rocks/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zero-punctuation-rocks/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered an incredibly entertaining and scathing game
reviewer, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.escapistmagazine.com&#x2F;videos&#x2F;view&#x2F;zero-punctuation&quot;&gt;Zero Punctuation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. None of the reviews I&#x27;ve seen so far are
any shallow, and there&#x27;s even solid social commentary.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>BioShock</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bioshock/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bioshock/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;gamelife&#x2F;2008&#x2F;02&#x2F;ken-levine-how&quot;&gt;negative review of BioShock&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; partly because everything else
I&#x27;ve read so far was full of praise, and partly because, immersive as
it is, really is overrated. For one, I couldn&#x27;t believe that I was
restricted to basically one environment, and I got so lost around the
repetitive-looking environment just as I was in &lt;em&gt;Halo: Combat Evolved&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
(a superior game, even considering it was released over 5 years
earlier).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like about the game:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an amazing array of genetic weapons&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great art direction&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fearsome Big Daddies&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an appealing gloomy storyline of genetic engineering gone awry&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing did alert me what a tremendously useful tool 3D games
could be as exploration tools to unfamiliar worlds. Note that I&#x27;ve
lived through such an experience with the vastly underrated &lt;em&gt;Conflict:
Desert Storm&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>GameSpy&#x27;s &#x27;BioShock&#x27; review</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gamespy-s-bioshock-review/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gamespy-s-bioshock-review/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, I got seduced by GameSpy with their &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20120603023844&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;goty.gamespy.com&#x2F;2006&quot;&gt;2006 review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and this
time around, I got seduced yet again by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;web.archive.org&#x2F;web&#x2F;20131030142800&#x2F;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;goty.gamespy.com&#x2F;2007&#x2F;special&#x2F;22.html&quot;&gt;their review of BioShock&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
Going through their various categories, that game got mentioned more
than twice, being among the top10 PC games, winning Art Direction award,
and then, in what truly caught my attention, winning the Best Story
award. The review makes me salivate. [&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;bioshock&quot;&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Halo 3</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/halo-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/halo-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I could not spot a real improvement from Halo 2, bar the hyper-realistic
environments of Flood-infested walls, the addition of some vehicles, and
the ability to dislodge heavy guns. It seems most effort went into just
the environments while ignoring gameplay and a fresh and good storyline.
It&#x27;s quite a pity because the first Halo was such an epic achievement,
while the second, while unable to replicate the first&#x27;s grandeur, had
quite a few innovations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
