<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/excellent/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain Fantastic</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-fantastic/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-fantastic/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the writing and direction excellent, and the acting very
competent. The funeral was very touching, and its simplicity admirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a minor complaint, I wish grandpa, the only real adversary in the
movie, was not so soon forgotten by the writers. Also, I suspect a less
fairy-taily ending would have made for an even better movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the whole thing offers a fantastic (and refreshing)
examination of a self-educated and self-sufficient family.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Deadpool</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/deadpool/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/deadpool/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this the most fun (lots and lots of good humor) of all superhero
movies I&#x27;ve yet seen. I&#x27;m also tempted to call it the best, but a
revisit is required before dethroning &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;iron-man&quot;&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from that position. I
find it the most daring (the vulgarity), and has a great number of movie
firsts. In addition, the action direction is superb, and so are the
visual effects. The movie also offers some of the most delicious
instances of Breaking the Fourth Wall. I am also glad that the character
of Colossus (man of metal) was changed... the X-Men movies did a bad
job with theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complaints:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish the romantic interest was less of an action hero herself,
just to lend a bit of realism, as well as avoiding the
super-annoying formula.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Near the end of the movie, tough lady simply disappears without
explanation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Leftovers - Season 2 Episode 1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tv episodes have left as much an impact on me as this bizarre one. I
was reeling from it for days after watching it first time, and I hardly
ever re-visit tv shows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performances are without flaw. My one favorite is that of they guy
playing the fireman. He delivers one of the most impressive performances
I&#x27;ve seen yet. He&#x27;s such a pleasure to watch. Equally irresistible is
the gal playing his daughter. The character development given these two
is amazing. Playing the mother is Regina King and what is the only one
her performances I&#x27;ve really enjoyed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a strange choice of events which don&#x27;t serve the story in any
obvious way, but they add to the enjoyment, and are given excellent
direction:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incident with the scientist taking water samples&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brief and quiet moment showing the girls in the car&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The girls running naked&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prison confession&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Haywire</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/haywire/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/haywire/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a rather unusual and very well-made Bourne-style movie. It also
had the best hand-to-hand combat scenes I&#x27;ve seen outside of martial
arts movies. I wish the lead actor had more training, for her lack of
skill show near the end. All other performances are solid, luckily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Iron Man</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/iron-man/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/iron-man/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The best superhero movie made so far, I was amazed it held its
entertainment value after a few revisits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The relaxed and superb performance of Robert Downey, Jr.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The charming performance of Gwyneth Paltrow&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The unique performance of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Clark_Gregg&quot;&gt;Clark Gregg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The great designs of the Iron Man suit, and all related visual
effects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The laid-back humor (first scene being the best example)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bad:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of the villains are any interesting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish the main villain had a bit of practice before managing to use
the giant suit with such competence&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hero manages to fool his captors of what he&#x27;s building for a
long time, especially given that he&#x27;s under camera surveillance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He also survives way too much physical pounding&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#x27;ll wish the filmmakers would invest as much in plausibility and
common sense as in the gorgeous suits on display here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hated these bad things on the first revisit, but they were easy
to overlook this time around... the good stuff managed to distract me well
enough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nightcrawler</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nightcrawler/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nightcrawler/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is overall well-made and got a story that feels fresh, and one
that&#x27;s seldom told: people taking video footage of gruesome events. The
scene that culminates in a police car chase is intense and feels
realistic; great direction and camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jake Gyllenhaal, the lead of the quality cast, is a highly skilled actor
(see &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;prisoners-2013&quot;&gt;Prisoners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;zodiac-and-david-fincher&quot;&gt;Zodiac&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), but I haven&#x27;t seen him this good. His
character is very unusual and scary, and pretty much a supreme asshole
you wish didn&#x27;t exist. His life is shit (he&#x27;s lonely, out of money,
and seems to have some mental problem), so I almost don&#x27;t blame him for
his criminal behavior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rene Russo also gives a great performance, and so does the lady
portraying the detective, Michael Hyatt. The latter is very imposing,
and pretty much towers above everyone in her (few and short-lived)
scenes. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-movie-characters#tough-women&quot;&gt;Great toughness portrayal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sherlock - Season 3 Episode 3</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Episode 0 of Season 1, which was remade into Episode 1, got me excited
about the series. I loved the villain (superb performance), and it had
great humor (Dr. Watson character). None of the later Episodes could
match, all but the third (and last) of the third Season. The highlight
here is the villain, who ranks as the best in the series (Moriarty is
rather overdone). He represents great character development and is given
a flawless performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sidenote, of the series regulars, none of the characters was as
interesting as that of Sherlock&#x27;s big brother. It&#x27;s a superb
performance too, the character is such a joy (mature, wise,
influential), and he was made all the more interesting to later discover
that his intelligence matched that of Sherlock.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Se7en (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/se7en-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/se7en-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It would be dishonest of me to claim that my recent experience of this
movie was that of a masterpiece, a label I&#x27;ve placed on it for years.
It felt more as an academic exercise, the kind that movie students would
be &#x27;forced&#x27; to consume, in order to make notes on various elements
(and there are many notable ones).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One minor gripe I&#x27;ve had with the movie is that it lacks superb
&lt;strong&gt;acting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Morgan Freeman is as boring as usual with a standard
performance which isn&#x27;t really better than that of Brad Pitt. Kevin
Spacey, although much better than the two, doesn&#x27;t go anywhere near
what he&#x27;s capable of. As for others, it mainly is nothing outstanding,
but Gwyneth Paltrow is without any noticeable flaw, and is sweeter here
than anywhere else in her career.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other gripe I&#x27;ve not been satisfied with for a while is the lack of
justification of the Envy crime. I also found the scenes with Brad
Pitt&#x27;s beloved wife forced into the story (and boring too), and a cheap
manipulation used only to serve the ending. I also never liked the chase
scene, not due its execution (David Fincher is the best movie director
who ever lived, duh!), but because the movie isn&#x27;t escapist material,
and the chase scene simply doesn&#x27;t suit it, a fact made worse by its
being too long. One other complaint is that the conversations seem mere
quick pepperings over some important philosophical issues. I do
understand that time is limited, but every time I watch the
all-important scene with John Doe sitting behind in a police car, I wish
the conversation would be longer. It was way too interesting to be kept
that short. Sure it&#x27;s handled very well (excellent editing, and
camerawork), but the cops should really have been more curious,
especially Somerset.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And given all that negativity, it doesn&#x27;t mean all&#x27;s lost. The movie
remains &lt;strong&gt;the best detective movie&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I&#x27;ve seen yet. The cinematography
isn&#x27;t bad, but the production design is really top-class. The attention
to detail is lovely, but I&#x27;ve seen better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich and well-crafted as it is, the movie has a rather shallow and small
world. Nothing else exists. That could be seen as a strength of course,
for I suppose a great movie is one that can really absorb you, allowing
you to drown in its &#x27;reality&#x27;. Perhaps I was just hungry for a far
richer and complex world offered by a number of superb movies I have
been drowning in the last fews years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are among my favorite moments:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An early scene where an uninterested detective questions the
investigative approach of Somerset (Morgan Freeman) regarding the
first murder, where there&#x27;s blood splattered on the dirty window.
The memory of this moment, complete with its sombre atmosphere,
incites the sort of excitement that is only reserved for when I&#x27;m
in love, romantic or otherwise.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A later scene where Mills (Brad Pitt) is withstanding heavy rain
near a murder scene while waiting for the detective Somerset. The
atmosphere here helps too, as is the seeming dedication of the
officer to the job. Thinking further, I find it a stupid deed, given
there are buildings around.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The moment where the detectives are called in by a uniformed officer
into a noisy club, guiding them to a murdered prostitute. The
alarmed look of this police officer adds to the intensity of the
horrific levels of the ordeal the prostitute had to endure. I just
wonder why the club wasn&#x27;t shut down... why do these police
continue working in this noise.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Inglourious Basterds (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first scene is top-class, for the performance of the weary farmer
when forced to make an unpleasant choice, the sort where I feel
self-death is better. The best performance of the movie however is that
of Christoph Waltz, who plays the Nazi officer questioning him. Brad
Pitt is quite limited in terms of talent but not charisma, and is
provides the weakest performance of all key characters. Quentin
Tarantino is a weirdo who possesses the freedom (perhaps too much) to
paint whatever he pleases on screen, and luckily got the talent. He
gives this one superb suspense, exciting dialog, unusual (and
unpredictable) story, and wonderful editing. It&#x27;s my favorite and best
of all his works, followed by &lt;em&gt;Reservoir Dogs&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting, and rare, thing is I enjoyed the movie a lot more on a
revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>the two versions of &#x27;Water No Get Enemy&#x27;</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-two-versions-of-water-no-get-enemy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-two-versions-of-water-no-get-enemy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=IQBC5URoF0s&quot;&gt;The first version of this song&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was released in 1975 as part of the
album, &lt;em&gt;Expensive Shit&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It&#x27;s among &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-tracks-fela-kuti&quot;&gt;the best works of Fela Kuti&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-musicians&quot;&gt;himself the best musician in history&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It also has the special
significance of being a great favorite of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;tshepomathopa&quot;&gt;a great friend of mine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what compelled to write this post is the version made by one son of
Fela Kuti, Femi Kuti. It was released in his not-so-good 2004 album,
&lt;em&gt;Africa Shine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I enjoy it more, perhaps because I&#x27;ve listened to way
too much of the original, resulting in it feeling a lot more fresh. It
has a faster pace, while being half as long (5 min). I love the lyrical
performance, the most distinctive thing about it as compared to the
original. I am sometimes tempted to call the whole thing superior, which
would not be accurate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Still Grazing (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/still-grazing-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/still-grazing-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorites from this, the best album by Hugh Masekela:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 2 - &lt;strong&gt;Ha Lese Le Di Khanna&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A remake of a track from Masekela&#x27;s 1993 album, &lt;em&gt;Hope&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It&#x27;s far
superior to both the original and the second remake, found in the
2001 compilation, &lt;em&gt;Grazing in the Grass: The Best of Hugh Masekela&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
It&#x27;s a masterpiece! I am tempted to call it the best of this
musician.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 6 - &lt;strong&gt;Grazing In the Grass&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s perhaps not fair to place this old classic here since, if it
was remade, doesn&#x27;t sound any different from its form when it was
first released in&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 5 - &lt;strong&gt;Bajabula Bonke (The Healing Song)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh Masekela must have really loved doing the vocals on this one.
One could feel the passion. The song sadly doesn&#x27;t end too well...
the last minute or so is anti-climactic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 7 - &lt;strong&gt;Gold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a very typical song, more like an experiment. Also quite sad...
it&#x27;s about economical exploitation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only let-down of a track in the whole 11 track album is the 10th,
&lt;strong&gt;Been Such A Long Time Gone&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. You wonder how it slipped in there. The
11th track, &lt;strong&gt;Stimela (Coal Train)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, is not the best version of this
beloved song. It&#x27;s of mere decent quality. To be fair, it&#x27;s also not
the worst.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Redbelt (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/redbelt-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/redbelt-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a nice find. I bumped onto it by accident. The first scene got
me sold (gritty, with good performances, especially the amazing Chiwetel
Ejiofor, as well as good direction). It does not disappoint throughout,
and it&#x27;s amazingly unpredictable. I wish it could have been longer,
with more of the loose ends tied.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>God of War trilogy</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The last time I played any of the 3 games from the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_(series)&quot;&gt;God of War&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; trilogy
was nearly 2 years ago, but the experience still lives vividly in my
mind; they offered among the greatest gaming experiences I ever had. I
haven&#x27;t played any of the other 4 games in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known about the first game for years, before playing it, and it
was among the top of my wishlist. The appeal was simply the imagery of
the angry lead character (Kratos), the giants he was portrayed to
battle, the setting (ancient Greek mythology), as well as the title.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally managed to get my hands on the games (about 2 years ago),
they did not disappoint. The epic feel of it all, the character design
(the best ever that covers ancient Greek mythology), and (as regards
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_III&quot;&gt;God of War III&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) impressive realism, makes for a fantastic series.
Sadly, this trilogy is only available for PlayStation (2 &amp;amp; 3).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hercules (demigod, son of Zeus), who appears in the 3rd game of the
trilogy, is a mini-giant with a massive muscle structure and an
interesting attitude, not to mention armed with some awesomely large
and powerful weapons, that the playable character (Kratos) luckily
gets to play with. The moment where this Hercules character appears
is among my most favorite battle scenes in the whole trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades (God of the Underworld), who we also only get to fight in the
3rd game of the trilogy, is another great design, and his underworld
the best environment of the whole trilogy. His assortment of weapons
is also quite impressive, but the battle involving him, though quite
good, could be more epic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Centaur#Centaur_General&quot;&gt;Centaur General&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (human-horse being) were quite a presence. Not
only were they rather tough to beat, but they were also the most
charming characters in the whole trilogy. One wishes they had a
greater screen time. Note that there were other Centaurs in the
trilogy, but these particular ones were most interesting, and their
slaying most... beautiful. They appear first time in the 3rd game
in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poseidon (God of the Sea), is an interesting one. His represents the
most complex (and hardest) fight sequence in the entire trilogy, it
it also happens on the third installment of this fine trilogy. It&#x27;s
not exactly my favorite, but his character has a certain level of
charm, and the final kill is particularly brutal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kratos, the protagonist, was most impressive in the first game, but
he was getting less interesting later on and the novelty of his
anger was wearing off. He was also getting petty at times, and too
bloodthirsty to be convincing. Regardless, he is a work of superb
character design, and this well-enhanced by the pale color and red
stripes on his skin, as well as a body that makes him look like pure
lethal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Stone_Talos&quot;&gt;Stone Talos&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are a one-of-a-kind character... muscular stone
statues that come to life to incur damage on our protagonist.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome as it is, the series does have weaknesses:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one notable bad work of character design, which is Ares,
the original god of war (a title Kratos took from him after
defeating him). He is totally uninresting (and clumsy), and the
battle in which the two fight is the worst in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One other horrible character was the goat-snake-lion combo
character. It was probably a first in gaming history, but it was a
real stupid idea.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were also some particilarly hard stages to pass, where I had
to ask for help from a friend to proceed to the next level. I hate
stuff like that... I normally pick the easiest difficulty level in
games, for I hate to struggle for too long.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Payback: Straight Up (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/payback-straight-up-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/payback-straight-up-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the most extensive Director&#x27;s Cut I&#x27;ve seen yet. There is so
much that is different:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most regretful is the absence of the Kris Kristofferson character,
whose role of head of The Outfit is replaced by a female voice. This
itself isn&#x27;t so bad, if we ignore that Kris was amazing to watch,
most especially the moment he first appeared on screen (amazing
direction).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one moment of domestic abuse that is rather hard to
swallow. I thought it was quite daring (and surprising), especially
because a character we are supposed to like is the perpetrator. This
moment alone makes it understandable why it was edited out.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending is a lot different and more involved (and perhaps a bit
over-the-top), but superior overall.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of the bodyguards were totally removed from the original cut,
which is rather sad for they given wonderful performances (they look
mean as fuck). I am referring to the two who drive the Val Resnick
character about.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could be wrong, but I felt like there were more shots of the
city&#x27;s environment, which makes me appreciate the great production
design both movies display. Wonderful.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first scene from the earlier movie, the one in which Potter is
getting bullets removed from his body, is missing. It&#x27;s among my
favorite scenes, and displays very well the darkness the movie
explores, complete with a curious medical practitioner.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lead character&#x27;s voice-over is missing, and was actually quite
good. This version proves it wasn&#x27;t essential though.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I find &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-1999&quot;&gt;the earlier release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; superior, but not by a big margin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Payback (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/payback-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/payback-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It remains impressive after all this time:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The detective partners are a joy to watch, and remain my most
favorite pair in movie history. Superb character development and
humor.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The direction, set design, script, and cinematography are all
superb. It&#x27;s wonderful watching Porter, the lead character,
progress from level to level, all the way to the top of the
underworld.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character of Val Resnick is the best-developed in the movie,
complete with a real good performance. His shining moment is an
outburst resulting from pride and fear.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The three heads of The Outfit represent more great character
development, and are honored with impressive performances, best of
which is Kris Kristofferson in what amounts to my most favorite of
his work, and a very memorable lead villain.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The two ladies in Porter&#x27;s life are given solid portrayals.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are some more nice appearances here and there, fat guy being
one, and his boss another.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, overall this is a real joyful experience, and my complaints aren&#x27;t
major:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mel Gibson gives a nice performance, but is not a convincing
bad&#x2F;tough guy; his narration is excellent though.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final shootout involving the Orientals was just needless, and
its violence almost cartoonish.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-straight-up-2006&quot;&gt;A Director&#x27;s Cut version&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was released in 2006, and I loved it too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In Bruges (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-bruges-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-bruges-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far better than the more expensive and colorful later work of this
talented director, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-psychopaths-2012&quot;&gt;Seven Psychopaths&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Great camerawork, enjoyable
acting (including even from Colin Farrel, which must be my most favorite
of his career), superb script (and dialog), a gorgeous and intensely
desirable gal, unusual storyline, and, and... what a gem?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a bit of a lull partway through it, but soon after, the fun
continues, and builds up to an intense and unpredictable last act, which
does not feel rushed at all... it&#x27;s amazing. It&#x27;s also helped a lot
by the superb Ralph Fiennes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the above-mentioned movie, one can sense a work of a liberal
writer&#x2F;director, where there is also some mention (and elevation) of
inter-racial relationships, and condemnation of a racist character. More
importantly, there is an important character in a form of a dwarf (real
nice performance there, reminiscent of that of the superb &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Peter_Dinklage&quot;&gt;Peter
Dinklage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the excellent TV series, &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), though,
ironically, he is the racist in question (but later apologises for it).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>District 9 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/district-9-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/district-9-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The documentary style has been employed elsewhere before, but there&#x27;s
nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in all movie history. Its weird and
wonderful story starts off with nice comic touches and transitions into
a harrowing tale of human torture, and ends as some action-adventure of
sorts, complete with superb visual effects, with some nice creature
ideas. Sure there&#x27;s warts here and there, but to have a gem like this
emerge from my country of residence, South Africa, is quite something.
It is the best movie based there. The lead performance also deserves
applaud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Baise-moi (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/baise-moi-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/baise-moi-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A low-key French-language and less cartoonish answer to &lt;em&gt;Natural Born
Killers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It also has affecting and believable performances and a
horrific, painful, and powerful story which also feels as random and
undirected as its two leads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best performance is that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Raffa%C3%ABla_Anderson&quot;&gt;Raffaëla Anderson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the more
trigger-happy of the 2 girls. It is sad that she has not done anything
else of significance, beyond porn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one complaint I have is that the switch between &#x27;sad girls&#x27; to
&#x27;killer girls&#x27; is not really explained, and rather sudden.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dr. Strangelove (1964)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dr-strangelove-1964/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dr-strangelove-1964/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of the rare old black &amp;amp; white movies that are actually
enjoyable throughout; it&#x27;s always a pleasure to revisit. The movie&#x27;s
greatest triumphs are it&#x27;s characters and performances, best of which
is Sterling Hayden as the mad general. One bonus performance is the guy
who is concerned about destroying property of the Coca Cola Company; and
he didn&#x27;t even look the idiot he was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attention-to-detail, regarding the procedures the guys in the bomber
plane follow, is impressive; the dialog is incredible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-vs-payback&quot;&gt;a comparison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between this classic and a much younger
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-1999&quot;&gt;Payback&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Taken (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/taken-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/taken-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A top-notch thriller, complete with enthralling and fast-paced action
and a solid cast, led by a very credible Liam Neeson. The intensity
matches that of any movie in the trend-setting &lt;em&gt;Bourne&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy, though
with an evidently lower budget, and therefore less gloss, which is
pretty much welcome since found those movies rather wasteful, most
visibly in their chase sequences. In this one movie, there are two
chases sequences, and I feel the first one should have been cut
short... it wasn&#x27;t very interesting, and the movie feels too good to
be yet-another noisy actioner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve noticed the movie has received much negative criticism, which I
found very strange, especially given the skill the material was handled
with. Much of the complaints had to do with it having implausible plot
points, and I guess that I enjoyed it so much that I either didn&#x27;t
notice them, or that such weaknesses were really insignificant.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the subject material (forced sex slavery) quite scary and
expertly handled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dry And Heavy (1977)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dry-and-heavy-1977/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dry-and-heavy-1977/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very laid-back Burning Spear album, with a mere 9 short tracks, the
best of which is a re-imagining of one of my eternal favorite tracks of
all time, &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (live versions). It&#x27;s named &lt;em&gt;It&#x27;s A Long Way
Around&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and I could not stop myself from repeating it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the other tracks is quite good, though not catchy at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I once hailed this as a masterpiece, and though it remains excellent,
the emotional punch it carries has been reduced. The movie feels like
it&#x27;s cut short even though it&#x27;s nearly 2 hours long. I enjoyed the
story so much, with it&#x27;s multiple alternate-reality stories concept,
that I wanted more and more of it. It&#x27;s done quite well, but none of
the stories are given enough treatment, resulting in the movie feeling
too short.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7-year old boy gives one of the best child performances I&#x27;ve seen
yet, but the movie&#x27;s best is that by the fat friend in college, while
my most favorite was the religious guy who sharing a cell with the lead
character. It was quite interesting to have the actors take different
roles in each alternate reality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have preferred superior camerawork, not the shitty tv-like one,
which was most evident in the very first scene.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Butterfly_Effect#Reception&quot;&gt;negative critical reception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; surprising.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I later found out the version I watched on a revisit was an
alternate ending, one that ends with a suicide. I don&#x27;t think the
de-facto one would have made the movie much better&#x2F;worse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bourne Supremacy (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-supremacy-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-supremacy-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;All is better&#x2F;bigger than the original: the intensity of the story, the
production design, the camerawork, and the car chase. All performances
are either good or beyond, if we don&#x27;t count Karl Urban (the Russian
assassin).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite bit of performance is given by the guy playing the assassin
Bourne duels early in the movie. Another well-directed one is the kid of
the murdered Russian couple. Joan Allen is as good as usual (not one
wrong move). Matt Damon does even better than in the first movie and so
does Julia Stiles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Megamind (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/megamind-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/megamind-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;These 5 movies offered some of the best first-time viewing experiences I
ever had:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monsters, Inc.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2001)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2004)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Robots&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2005)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2007)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall-E&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2008)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do they all have in common:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wonderful character design and development&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enchanting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a great&#x2F;exciting story concept&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest entrant on this list is &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, a thoroughly satisfying
movie, which has the traditional hero&#x2F;villain thing, with a twist. The
character of the hero is simply amazing, for its deliberate
stereotypical design and development. The movie also has great costume
design. The title character is great fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, one other characteristic of this list of movies is that the
appeal went down on a revisit, a very worrying trend, and that was the
case with &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, though it wasn&#x27;t so devastating for it remains
excellent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Apocalypto (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/apocalypto-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/apocalypto-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a bunch of movies that showcase cultures where people
wear skimpy clothes and use heavy body modification, and this
is the best of them. There is also excellent casting and directing, and
an interesting story that&#x27;s spoiled by some plot holes:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far can a human outrun a jaguar?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How close can a 30m+ waterfall be to an ocean?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long can a human run with a wound that bad?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to the good stuff: The environment where the human
sacrifices take place is among the richest ever committed to screen, and
the silly traditions aren&#x27;t embarassingly executed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kung Fu Panda 2 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this even more than the first time (which wasn&#x27;t the case
with the first movie). The humor is great, and so is the action, and
it&#x27;s overall better than the first movie, except that nothing beats the
escape sequence and the wobbly bridge fight. The villain is amazing, as
is his display of martial arts prowess. Sadly, the movie feels a bit too
short, and doesn&#x27;t take itself seriously at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>L.A. Confidential (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/l-a-confidential-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/l-a-confidential-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It has lost some of the intensity and edginess of the earlier viewings,
perhaps because there&#x27;s been heavier stuff since, but it maintains its
excellence (direction, acting, script, production design). It got a
great cast, minus Kim Bassinger as top-class prostitute, and the gal
playing the raped character. The best performance is by Kevin Spacey
(smooth-talking cop), followed by James Cromwell (police chief).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Collateral (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/collateral-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/collateral-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Tom Cruise plays one of my most favorite hitmen and in fitting
performance (his shortcomings aren&#x27;t so obvious) while Jamie Foxx
embarasses, especially later when more (he&#x27;s supposed to express great
distress and rebellion) is demanded from his boring performance.
Everyone else does very well, and the casting is excellent, as is the
direction, and the dialogue. The whole is very unpredictable and the
seemingly random nature of the story and the style of the camerawork
(the same used in the 2006 &lt;em&gt;Miami Vice&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) gives the movie a certail level
of realism. It&#x27;s magnificent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Caught (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/caught-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/caught-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with this one years ago when I watched it first time, and
a revisit didn&#x27;t disappoint at all. The characters are very
well-developed and it&#x27;s easy to fall in love with them. This most
especially applies to Edward James Olmos, who gives a wonderful
performance as a stubborn fisherman husband. His son is excessively
annoying, and his wife excessively desirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#x27;s extra kool about the movie is that the cheaters aren&#x27;t
portrayed like villains, but rather, victims of lust. At the same time,
it&#x27;s still not portrayed as an okay thing to do, but the 2nd-last scene
was a little too much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all movies that cover the subject of infidelity, this is probably the
best.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rabbit Hole (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rabbit-hole-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rabbit-hole-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicole Kidman has played troubled women quite a few times before, but
the performance she gives here is quite fresh, and really unlike
anything I&#x27;ve seen before, either from her or anyone else. The
character she plays is also quite throughly developed, and my shitty
memory says she is the greatest female asshole I&#x27;ve seen yet in any
movie. This character is grieving of son&#x27;s accidental death.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy playing the killer gives the movie&#x27;s best performance, and
perhaps the best teenage performance in any movie (remember the quality
of my memory). He&#x27;s fucking amazing. And this is a movie not having any
shortage of excellent acting. Most notably, we have &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sandra_Oh&quot;&gt;Sandra Oh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who is
as desirable as she is excellent. She is a good actor, but she hasn&#x27;t
in my eyes done anything better than this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m still not sure about Aaron Eckhart. Not a bad performance at all,
but he&#x27;s too uninteresting. I&#x27;m also not sure about the lady playing
the mother. Not bad either, but not too beliavable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialog is quite good and so is the camerawork. The great direction
easily hides the fact the movie itself is pretty much plotless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tangled (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tangled-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tangled-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An enchanting fantasy with superb character design (the evil old lady,
the drunkards, and the 2 outlaws), amazing action sequences, and nice
humor. It&#x27;s originality is in having a horse in a different role than
in anything I&#x27;ve seen yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending (&#x27;climax&#x27;) feels forced, and does not do justice to the
rest of the movie; the movie is a musical, and none of it is
embarassing, but the love song (on the boat) is the low point...
boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one, simply because I
never heard it mentioned before. Note also that, for a few years now, I
don&#x27;t really check out what&#x27;s on the circuit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Apocalypse Now (1979)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/apocalypse-now-1979/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/apocalypse-now-1979/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first hour is nothing short of masterful. I&#x27;m referring here to
goosebumps that only result from supreme artistic excellence. I am
referring more specifically to the movie&#x27;s first battle, the merciless
attack led by Robert Duvall. Not only is it amazing to watch, but Robert
Duvall&#x27;s performance is mesmerising. His character&#x27;s eccentricity
(insane bravery and obsession with surfing) is unforgettable. It&#x27;s one
indication of the director&#x27;s love for being over-the-top, and it works
quite well, in the first hour.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marlon Brando has very powerful moments dedicated to his character, a
twisted fuck who revels in intense horror. He doesn&#x27;t appear in much of
the movie, and is filmed with reverance of a prophet, reminding me of
the old man in the early scenes of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-samurai-1954&quot;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Dennis Hopper does a
wonderful turn as his admirer, in the only one of his performances that
I actually find enjoyable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, I am not going to neglect to mention some questionable
casting choices:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Sheen is not bad, but there must have been someone more
suitable. Nice voice though, especially when he narrates.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The driver of the boat sucks, and he sucked in &lt;em&gt;Malcolm X&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; too.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;m not sure about Laurence Fishburne; he seems too artificial,
like some sorry attempt to keep the story interesting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harrison Ford looks like ineffective comic relief, without being
one.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the quality of being over-the-top worked well in the first
hour, that was not exactly the case elsewhere. For one, the Playboy
antic was acceptable. But as if that wasn&#x27;t enough, they (later on, for
some silly and unjustified reason) also had to fuck the travelling men.
There was also the moment at a dinner table with the French. Note that
these moments were very well done, but they just don&#x27;t live up to what
the first hour promised. They almost seem like desperate attempts at
keeping the whole thing exciting. Yes, and that wasn&#x27;t enough still, so
there had to be sex and romance too. Regardless, the gal rocks so hard,
complete with the face and sensuality of the magnificent Tilda Swinton.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate the shortcomings of the, for I would be happy to name it a
masterpiece. Surely this is a work of visual excellence, and is showered
with amazing cinematography and, especially, production design. The only
war movie that is any match on both these elements is &lt;em&gt;Saving Private
Ryan&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Maybe that&#x27;s a careless statement, but then again my memory is
hardly ever impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version I watched is the one released in 2001, fully titled
&lt;em&gt;Apocalypse Now Redux&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>4 Months, 3 Weeks and 2 Days (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Done with the style of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;crimson-gold-2003&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it&#x27;s a superbly-made and
-acted movie about the ravages of poverty and the problems associated
with making abortion illegal. The general ill-treatment people give each
other is horrid, but luckily things are lightened up when our hero&#x27;s
boyfriend celebrates mom&#x27;s birthday (even though there&#x27;s a sour note).
And the mom gives quite a good performance (and so does everyone else).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the comparison with &lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, it has far better acting, but
doesn&#x27;t cover as much ground and is therefore simpler. I can&#x27;t decide
which is superior between the two, but &lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; had a stronger
emotional impact on me. Maybe that makes it a better movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sex, Lies, and Videotape (1989)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sex-lies-and-videotape-1989/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sex-lies-and-videotape-1989/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just one piece of memory of this movie, and it&#x27;s of James Spader
sitting naked watching women talk of sex on video. I can&#x27;t recall
anything else, other than that I really found it boring, but that was
back in the 90&#x27;s. I probably didn&#x27;t even watch the whole thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways I really loved the movie this time around. The direction is
really amazing, with wonderful performances, especially from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Andie_MacDowell&quot;&gt;Andie
McDowell&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Not only desirable, but a fuckin&#x27; excellent performance. She
isn&#x27;t a bad actor, but I don&#x27;t remember her shining like this
elsewhere. As for James Spader, I don&#x27;t remember enjoying any of his
performances, until now. Well, not entirely, but I loved his portrayal
of mystery guy in his early scenes. Great character development there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialog is excellent, and the story simple, and it feels really
fresh. Quite a feat, considering that it&#x27;s made in the 80&#x27;s (there&#x27;s
hardly anything still fresh from that era).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Insider (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-insider-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-insider-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s one important movie, not only because of its excellence, but
because it covers issues of media and corporate ethics. I was rather
shaken by the excellence of these elements: acting, direction, and
dialogue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;acting&quot;&gt;acting&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a huge cast of veteran actors, and none of them is less than
excellent. My favorites:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Al Pacino plays the heroic producer who fights to get the story on
air. For him (as is the case for everyone else actually), the
performance is business as usual. It&#x27;s not the best of his career,
not is it any bad at all. He&#x27;s one of those actors who are
incapable of giving a shitty one after all.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Christopher_Plummer&quot;&gt;Christopher Plummer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who plays the interviewer. It&#x27;s always a
pleasure watching him.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Bruce_McGill&quot;&gt;Bruce McGill&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who scared me in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;revisiting-matchstick-men&quot;&gt;Matchstick Men&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He plays one of
the lawyers here, and a tough one at that. He delivers the movie&#x27;s
most potent dialogue, when in court (or whatever tha was).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Gambon&quot;&gt;Michael Gambon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; plays the unscrupulous and dishonest tocacco
company owner.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Philip_Baker_Hall&quot;&gt;Philip Baker Hall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; plays an executive producer, the boss of Al
Pacino&#x27;s character.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Russell Crowe, I was actually satisfied, until much later on
where I just realised that this was just a man in a mask (it sometimes
felt like he tried too hard), though not as awkward a mask as that of
Matt Damon in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-informant-2009&quot;&gt;The Informant&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I say this because the Crowe was really
good, regardless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing of note is that, regardless of how strong these performances
were, they are not convincing. At the end of it all (or more accurately,
near the end of the movie, say an hour or so before ~150m running time
ends) you are left with this aftertaste that you are watching an excuse
of a spectacle. Here&#x27;s this director with a massive budget and
highly-acclaimed actors at his disposal, carefully crafting a fine piece
of art, but sanitising it so much that it loses the realism, and leaves
the glamour of Hollywood. The performances feels more like showing off
(&amp;quot;we are a bunch o&#x27; fuckin&#x27; good actors, motherfucka!&amp;quot;). It&#x27;s like
who&#x27;s outdoing who in the craft. There&#x27;s way too many of them, and
some are even wasted. For example, my favorite, Bruce McGill, actually
appears in about 3 scenes and Michael Gambon who appears in something
like 1 scene. When things like this happens, I am left wanting. I see
boys showing off the sizes of their balls, sadly. I&#x27;m temped to mention
masturbation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the reasons I outlined above, I feel that the cast of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;Precious&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is
superior (there was no such aftertaste), even though the actors are far
less experienced. I think cold skill isn&#x27;t enough to win my affection.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;direction-and-script&quot;&gt;direction and script&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direction is really tense, and extremely engaging. The warmth of the
2 families, Crowe&#x27;s and Pacino&#x27;s, is plain lovely. There are some
seiously powerful dialogue moments, and actually each line that&#x27;s
delivered seems meticulously-crafted. Also, perhaps as testament to the
lack of skill of the director, there is a sense of lack of completeness.
The movie runs at ~250minutes, yet it feels like some parts were left
off. I&#x27;ve mentioned for one the underuse of some the characters. This
may be unfair, as in maybe I wouldn&#x27;t have missed them so much had the
performances not been so strong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme running through the story is that of heroism of the two lead
characters, the Al Pacino news teller and the whistleblower. This
divorces the movie a bit from reality (considering the subject matter),
making it feel like mere gloss (fairytale). Actually that&#x27;s one thing
that the younger &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-informant-2009&quot;&gt;The Informant&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (2009) stayed away from. No one was an
angel there, well except for one FBI agent, but he wasn&#x27;t given a
blowjob that our two heroes here got.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m not satisfied with this review. The movie is tough to review
because it&#x27;s so sophisticated, with so much that&#x27;s beautiful (and so
much lacking).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Crimson Gold (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/crimson-gold-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/crimson-gold-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a one-of-a-kind movie (almost) following a small-time
crook&#x2F;pizza delivery guy (Hussein) on his devoid-of-excitement journey
around some densely-populated city. The guy playing him has a lot of
presence (and he&#x27;s really fun to watch), even though in a typical
Hollywood, he would be reduced to merely a secondary character. The
direction is such that you feel affinity with the main characters, and
they feel as real as any movie can make them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a few wonderful moments in the movie:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene where our normally-sad protagonist passes time by giving
pizza away, and he does this to some of his captives. That act
kindness gave me warm and fuzzy feelings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene where our protagonist delivers pizza to a rich guy, who
invites him to stay and enjoy the pizza with him. The motivation is
that he needed to vent a bit and needed some ears for that.
Hussein&#x27;s unwillingness reminded me of the Travis Bickle (Robert De
Niro) in the classic scene of &lt;em&gt;Taxi Driver&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, where one passenger
talks about the pain of a cheating wife... well except that rich
man&#x27;s pain isn&#x27;t quite as intense. The scene also serves to show
the heavy contrast between the worlds of the rich and the poor (and
you should compare rich man&#x27;s place with Hussein&#x27;s; it&#x27;s
ridiculous how the world came to be like this).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though almost nothing happens (at least as compared to normal
Hollywood fare), the movie also covers the issue of sexual oppression,
but very skillfully and subtly, and in more than one occassion. It made
me appreciate some of the pleasures we have here in South Africa.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of this movie is very similar to that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Abbas_Kiarostami&quot;&gt;Abbas Kiarostami&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;A Taste of Cherry&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Wind Will Carry Us&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), and that&#x27;s not
strange since he wrote the screenplay, and is considered by the director
as his mentor. Most notable, it&#x27;s far better than those two boring
pieces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Rosenbaum, the best movie critic I&#x27;ve read, has a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jonathanrosenbaum.com&#x2F;?p=6061&quot;&gt;superb
and highly-detailed review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He&#x27;s also the one that inspired me to
watch the movie for he is a huge fan of it, to the point of labeling
it a masterpice.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;ve compared this to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007&quot;&gt;4 Months, 3 Weeks and 2 Days&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which is made
in a similar style.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hold It Down (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hold-it-down-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hold-it-down-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got hold of &amp;quot;Hold It Down&amp;quot; (1995) by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Das_EFX&quot;&gt;Das EFX&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Real good
ole-style hip-hop, thanks to a friend who, when I asked who he reckoned
the best hip-hop group is, he mentioned Das EFX. In my investigations, I
also got hold of their &amp;quot;Generation EFX&amp;quot; (1998) which is really bad.
Strange that just 3 years later people can fuck up like that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s my favorites:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 18 -- &lt;em&gt;Hardcore Rap Act&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 12 -- &lt;em&gt;Alright&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 05 -- &lt;em&gt;Real Hip Hop&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Cat In The Hat (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-cat-in-the-hat-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-cat-in-the-hat-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of these days I&#x27;m simply going to have to admit the world&#x27;s movie
critics are quite strange, and I really can&#x27;t rely on them for what
they consider excellent. Take for example their thoughts on &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Cat_in_the_Hat_(film)#Reception&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cat
in the Hat&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This is because I find it really great family
entertainment. It&#x27;s great fantasy and very funny, with great production
design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mandingo (1975)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mandingo-1975/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mandingo-1975/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember watching this one quite long ago, perhaps less than the age
of ten. It was heavily entrenched in my mind due to its powerful imagery
(full-frontal nudity; sex; beatings). That was porn for me, at the age
when I wasn&#x27;t exposed to much. Revisiting it after all these years is
quite an experience. The imagery is still arresting, and the story
powerful. Oh, and there&#x27;s some hot and happening gals within.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme of extreme oppression, both of women and of black people,
is very well done&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent production design&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent acting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lady playing the jealous wife is amazing, both her performance
and her desirability levels&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It feels realistic (as if I know!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did u see the first gal the young slave-master screwed!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Young slave-master&#x27;s regular black fuck (I thought it was Angela
Bassett) was pretty too, though rather skinny&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ummm... is there any?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing is that the plight of the the jealous wife
saddened me more than that of the slaves. I don&#x27;t know if this was
deliberate by the writer or director, but I cared more for her than for
the slaves, even though they got even shittier treatment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Showgirls (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/showgirls-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/showgirls-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Back then when I saw it for the first time, I was excessively impressed
with it, which made it hard to comprehend why the heck it got such &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Showgirls#Reception&quot;&gt;low
ratings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. If we remove &#x27;excessively&#x27;, that&#x27;s still the case. It&#x27;s
got good performances and a very fitting lead role. It&#x27;s very energetic
and intense, but it&#x27;s too full of frantic, over-the-top acts (the
near-accident caused by the guy offering a lift, the first meeting with
sweet gal, the lap dance, ...), which are rather disturbing, divorcing
the movie from reality. The brutality shown at the end wasn&#x27;t needed,
and is neither explanied nor justified. The movie remains excellent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Downfall (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/downfall-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/downfall-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t recall ever seeing such extreme loyalty and devotion to a
living figure as the people surrounding Adolf Hitler in this grim
portrayal of his final hours. It goes beyond irrational, and into insane
territory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent movie by the way (acting, direction, writing). The portrayal
of Hitler&#x27;s moments of outrage are classic, one of which has been
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.bbc.co.uk&#x2F;2&#x2F;hi&#x2F;uk_news&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;8617454.stm&quot;&gt;parodied numerous times&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Somewhere (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/somewhere-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/somewhere-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead character of rich, famous, and easily fucks ultra-hot gals, yet
the only bright thing in his life seems to be her beloved daughter (who
is given a flawless portrayal). This feeling of purposelessness is
well-punctuated by Sofia Coppola&#x27;s superb direction of loong takes and
a story where nealy nothing happens. This movie is a greater favorite to
the director&#x27;s earlier &lt;em&gt;Lost in Translation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, which covered similar
territory; the lead is far more interesting, and does not have that
irritating Japanese tv host.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Festen (1998)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/festen-1998/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/festen-1998/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The painful story of &lt;em&gt;Festen&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; was powerful enough to have me label it a
masterpiece. Unfortunately that honor didn&#x27;t survive a revisit. I still
consider it very well-made (only a master-director can make such a
movie, given its &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dogme_95&quot;&gt;self-imposed limits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and the emotions it stirs are
still high-impact, and the story is important enough that I&#x27;d promote
it heavily if I had the means.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] The very first scene is intensely horrid, one where
super-asshole chases wife and kids outta the car. It was hard to
swallow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
