<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/excellent/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Leftovers - Season 2 Episode 1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/leftovers-season-2-episode-1/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tv episodes have left as much an impact on me as this bizarre one. I
was reeling from it for days after watching it first time, and I hardly
ever re-visit tv shows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performances are without flaw. My one favorite is that of they guy
playing the fireman. He delivers one of the most impressive performances
I&#x27;ve seen yet. He&#x27;s such a pleasure to watch. Equally irresistible is
the gal playing his daughter. The character development given these two
is amazing. Playing the mother is Regina King and what is the only one
her performances I&#x27;ve really enjoyed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a strange choice of events which don&#x27;t serve the story in any
obvious way, but they add to the enjoyment, and are given excellent
direction:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incident with the scientist taking water samples&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brief and quiet moment showing the girls in the car&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The girls running naked&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prison confession&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sherlock - Season 3 Episode 3</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sherlock-season-3-episode-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Episode 0 of Season 1, which was remade into Episode 1, got me excited
about the series. I loved the villain (superb performance), and it had
great humor (Dr. Watson character). None of the later Episodes could
match, all but the third (and last) of the third Season. The highlight
here is the villain, who ranks as the best in the series (Moriarty is
rather overdone). He represents great character development and is given
a flawless performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sidenote, of the series regulars, none of the characters was as
interesting as that of Sherlock&#x27;s big brother. It&#x27;s a superb
performance too, the character is such a joy (mature, wise,
influential), and he was made all the more interesting to later discover
that his intelligence matched that of Sherlock.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>the two versions of &#x27;Water No Get Enemy&#x27;</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-two-versions-of-water-no-get-enemy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-two-versions-of-water-no-get-enemy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=IQBC5URoF0s&quot;&gt;The first version of this song&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was released in 1975 as part of the
album, &lt;em&gt;Expensive Shit&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It&#x27;s among &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-tracks-fela-kuti&quot;&gt;the best works of Fela Kuti&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-musicians&quot;&gt;himself the best musician in history&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It also has the special
significance of being a great favorite of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;tshepomathopa&quot;&gt;a great friend of mine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what compelled to write this post is the version made by one son of
Fela Kuti, Femi Kuti. It was released in his not-so-good 2004 album,
&lt;em&gt;Africa Shine&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I enjoy it more, perhaps because I&#x27;ve listened to way
too much of the original, resulting in it feeling a lot more fresh. It
has a faster pace, while being half as long (5 min). I love the lyrical
performance, the most distinctive thing about it as compared to the
original. I am sometimes tempted to call the whole thing superior, which
would not be accurate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Still Grazing (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/still-grazing-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/still-grazing-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorites from this, the best album by Hugh Masekela:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 2 - &lt;strong&gt;Ha Lese Le Di Khanna&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A remake of a track from Masekela&#x27;s 1993 album, &lt;em&gt;Hope&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It&#x27;s far
superior to both the original and the second remake, found in the
2001 compilation, &lt;em&gt;Grazing in the Grass: The Best of Hugh Masekela&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
It&#x27;s a masterpiece! I am tempted to call it the best of this
musician.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 6 - &lt;strong&gt;Grazing In the Grass&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s perhaps not fair to place this old classic here since, if it
was remade, doesn&#x27;t sound any different from its form when it was
first released in&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 5 - &lt;strong&gt;Bajabula Bonke (The Healing Song)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugh Masekela must have really loved doing the vocals on this one.
One could feel the passion. The song sadly doesn&#x27;t end too well...
the last minute or so is anti-climactic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;track 7 - &lt;strong&gt;Gold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a very typical song, more like an experiment. Also quite sad...
it&#x27;s about economical exploitation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only let-down of a track in the whole 11 track album is the 10th,
&lt;strong&gt;Been Such A Long Time Gone&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. You wonder how it slipped in there. The
11th track, &lt;strong&gt;Stimela (Coal Train)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, is not the best version of this
beloved song. It&#x27;s of mere decent quality. To be fair, it&#x27;s also not
the worst.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>God of War trilogy</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The last time I played any of the 3 games from the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_(series)&quot;&gt;God of War&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; trilogy
was nearly 2 years ago, but the experience still lives vividly in my
mind; they offered among the greatest gaming experiences I ever had. I
haven&#x27;t played any of the other 4 games in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known about the first game for years, before playing it, and it
was among the top of my wishlist. The appeal was simply the imagery of
the angry lead character (Kratos), the giants he was portrayed to
battle, the setting (ancient Greek mythology), as well as the title.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally managed to get my hands on the games (about 2 years ago),
they did not disappoint. The epic feel of it all, the character design
(the best ever that covers ancient Greek mythology), and (as regards
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;God_of_War_III&quot;&gt;God of War III&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) impressive realism, makes for a fantastic series.
Sadly, this trilogy is only available for PlayStation (2 &amp;amp; 3).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hercules (demigod, son of Zeus), who appears in the 3rd game of the
trilogy, is a mini-giant with a massive muscle structure and an
interesting attitude, not to mention armed with some awesomely large
and powerful weapons, that the playable character (Kratos) luckily
gets to play with. The moment where this Hercules character appears
is among my most favorite battle scenes in the whole trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades (God of the Underworld), who we also only get to fight in the
3rd game of the trilogy, is another great design, and his underworld
the best environment of the whole trilogy. His assortment of weapons
is also quite impressive, but the battle involving him, though quite
good, could be more epic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Centaur#Centaur_General&quot;&gt;Centaur General&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (human-horse being) were quite a presence. Not
only were they rather tough to beat, but they were also the most
charming characters in the whole trilogy. One wishes they had a
greater screen time. Note that there were other Centaurs in the
trilogy, but these particular ones were most interesting, and their
slaying most... beautiful. They appear first time in the 3rd game
in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poseidon (God of the Sea), is an interesting one. His represents the
most complex (and hardest) fight sequence in the entire trilogy, it
it also happens on the third installment of this fine trilogy. It&#x27;s
not exactly my favorite, but his character has a certain level of
charm, and the final kill is particularly brutal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kratos, the protagonist, was most impressive in the first game, but
he was getting less interesting later on and the novelty of his
anger was wearing off. He was also getting petty at times, and too
bloodthirsty to be convincing. Regardless, he is a work of superb
character design, and this well-enhanced by the pale color and red
stripes on his skin, as well as a body that makes him look like pure
lethal.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;godofwar.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Stone_Talos&quot;&gt;Stone Talos&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are a one-of-a-kind character... muscular stone
statues that come to life to incur damage on our protagonist.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome as it is, the series does have weaknesses:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one notable bad work of character design, which is Ares,
the original god of war (a title Kratos took from him after
defeating him). He is totally uninresting (and clumsy), and the
battle in which the two fight is the worst in the trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One other horrible character was the goat-snake-lion combo
character. It was probably a first in gaming history, but it was a
real stupid idea.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were also some particilarly hard stages to pass, where I had
to ask for help from a friend to proceed to the next level. I hate
stuff like that... I normally pick the easiest difficulty level in
games, for I hate to struggle for too long.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dry And Heavy (1977)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dry-and-heavy-1977/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dry-and-heavy-1977/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very laid-back Burning Spear album, with a mere 9 short tracks, the
best of which is a re-imagining of one of my eternal favorite tracks of
all time, &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (live versions). It&#x27;s named &lt;em&gt;It&#x27;s A Long Way
Around&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and I could not stop myself from repeating it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the other tracks is quite good, though not catchy at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hold It Down (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hold-it-down-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hold-it-down-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got hold of &amp;quot;Hold It Down&amp;quot; (1995) by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Das_EFX&quot;&gt;Das EFX&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Real good
ole-style hip-hop, thanks to a friend who, when I asked who he reckoned
the best hip-hop group is, he mentioned Das EFX. In my investigations, I
also got hold of their &amp;quot;Generation EFX&amp;quot; (1998) which is really bad.
Strange that just 3 years later people can fuck up like that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s my favorites:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 18 -- &lt;em&gt;Hardcore Rap Act&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 12 -- &lt;em&gt;Alright&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 05 -- &lt;em&gt;Real Hip Hop&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
