<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2008-movie/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Children of Men (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/children-of-men-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/children-of-men-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The nightmarish way of life portrayed here is about as dark as it gets.
The performances are great and so are the characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lady that can&#x27;t speak English is touching; I also loved the
nurse&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Character played by Clive Owen is relentlessly heroic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pregnant lady is charming, and is the most interesting in the
movie; she&#x27;s played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm1715135&quot;&gt;Clare-Hope Ashitey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Julianne Moore freedom fighter is wonderful, and is given the
usual excellent performance the actor is know for&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only character I could have done without is that played by Michael
Caine. He felt recycled, and was somewhat not believable. It was still
heartbreaking when he had to meet his killers though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie features some of the best battle scenes I&#x27;ve seen, a fact
made more impressive due to the fact this isn&#x27;t a war movie. The
direction is also about as good as it gets. The story is quite unusual
and unpredictable, which gives the whole thing a fresh feeling. I still
wish there was more of an explanation of what the fuck fucked UK so bad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mars Attacks! (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mars-attacks-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mars-attacks-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The deception by the aliens on humans is one of the interesting things
about the movie, and the other being the flirting between the Pierce
Brosnan and the Sarah Jessica Parker characters. The latter is actually
quite charming, especially as a dog. Other interesting characters are
the forgetful lady and the disguised alien.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is overall entertaining, but has just too much violence...
the attacks are prolonged. The sub-plot about the former boxer is
horrible, complete with bad acting and uninteresting characters (boxer,
wife, kids) and looks like it&#x27;s from some shitty B-movie. The whole
thing is also pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cloverfield (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cloverfield-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cloverfield-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cloverfield-vs-i-am-legend&quot;&gt;I once compared this movie with I Am Legend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and I then I had the
following to say later that year:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit of &lt;em&gt;Cloverfield&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; wasn&#x27;t as much a let-down as that of &lt;em&gt;I Am
Legend&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and am even tempted that it&#x27;s so far the year&#x27;s greatest
achievement in visual effects. I just want more of that fabulous
monster, and hopefully in a really good sequel. Perhaps an equally
good sequel would be another discovered tape, maybe with a bigger
budget. Here&#x27;s me salivating on what could be an extremely satisfying
franchise. I just so much wish no one will fuck up the idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the above are still accurate, except I didn&#x27;t enjoy the plot as
much this (third) time around. The setup was okay, all but the romance
part of it, which just felt tired. I also found it far-fetched to have
the guy brave the monsters to go rescue gal, and managing to drag around
two more people on his quest onto a heavily-compromised building, up
dozens of stairs, all to find a gal heavily injured, yet managing to run
around for several minutes on end... makes me sad :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kung Fu Panda (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;1st review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a tremendous amount of fun to be had in &lt;em&gt;Kung Fu Panda&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, a
superb crowd-pleaser with some of the greatest action I&#x27;ve seen of
any movie. The filmmakers&#x27; taste however varies from mine; I
wouldn&#x27;t have chosen animals, some of which are simply a result of
eccentricity, and which I suspect to have been deliberate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a third viewing, I still find the action impressive, but would not go
as far as &lt;em&gt;among the greatest&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. The lead character tends to be annoying,
partly because he&#x27;s used to legitimize lying (which is way too common
in movies), and partly due to the slapstick humor. He also survives way
too much physical pounding, and without a scratch. The movie is also
shallow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Silent Hill (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the creature design which is quite good, best of which is
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Pyramid_Head&quot;&gt;Pyramid Head&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the horrific blade-dragging monster, whose made even
more memorable by his countless bug-like companions. Second favorites
are the supersexy, faceless, murderous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nurse&quot;&gt;nurses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. These pleasures were
however spoiled by a miscast&#x2F;unconvincing villainous lady and the weak
story. This is not to mention random stupid things, like the leading
lady running away from the cop for no reason, or the silly gal whose
hate leads to her being skinned alive, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I felt first time I watched it, and is no longer the case:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deserving of mention is the superb production design (though this is
inconsistent) and certain moments of extreme beauty (e.g. the early
scene of the grassy wilderness where mother and daughter share some
love, and a later scene which shows the internals of the family&#x27;s
home). As for visual effects, the moments of &amp;quot;approaching darkness&amp;quot;
can only be a result of visual mastery.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That early scene was nice yes, but calling it &lt;em&gt;extremely beautiful&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is
extreme. As for the visual mastery comment, it must have been mere
virgin excitement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Planet Terror (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/planet-terror-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/planet-terror-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert Rodriguez is a strange director. He is a good director, but he
tends to deliberately screw up his movies with some nonsensical events.
He did this previously with &lt;em&gt;From Dusk till Dawn&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, where he would create
a quality setup, and then mess it all with lots of ugly creatures. He
does the same here, with lots of disgustingness, in a form of people
infected with something that turns them into zombies. It&#x27;s sad mostly
because there is nice camerawork, lots of quality acting (check
especially Josh Brolin as medical doctor), and lots of quality humor
(check the child and mother moment, as well as the first meeting with an
infected patient). It&#x27;s like some sort of &#x27;fuck you&#x27; from the
director.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Buffalo Soldiers (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/buffalo-soldiers-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/buffalo-soldiers-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My initial review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s surprising that a movie as radical as Buffalo Soldiers could be
distributed at all since it&#x27;s about the most effective anti-war movie
I&#x27;ve seen in a long time. It&#x27;s filled with fresh acting, though the
movie&#x27;s villain doesn&#x27;t really convince while the lead character
could have been portrayed by a better actor (Phoenix isn&#x27;t
interesting at all).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit was not so great, including the radicalness I felt, the
freshness of the acting (what was I thinking?), nor the anti-war
sentiment strong at all. I even went as far awarding it best story of
movies I watched first time in 2008, which is something a little
puzzling now. Instead, it just feels pointless and arbitrary.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Syriana (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/syriana-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/syriana-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is my initial review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syriana is an uncompromising examination of government-sponsored
corporate evil and an idiotic oil-rich monarchy that condones it, with
a surprise ending. It&#x27;s a minimalist, yet powerful, narrative.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit proved not as impressive, and I don&#x27;t remember what was
surprising about the ending. The quiet and distrinctive style of
direction gives it a fresh feel, although the quiet treatment tends to
make it boring in places.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all performances are interesting, especially the investigator with a
troubled housemate. I did not enjoy watching the middle-East kids
either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>No Country for Old Men (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/no-country-for-old-men-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/no-country-for-old-men-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;With tremendous suspense, superb performances, great cinematography as
well as immersive production design, this is easily the Coen Brother&#x27;s
best ever. The movie&#x27;s best scene is when the Josh Brolin character
explores the scene of the murdered gangsters; the atmospherics are
crying of perfection, and so is the execution of it all. Another thing
of note is the Coen&#x27;s love for the American South characterisations
(remember the touching &lt;em&gt;Raising Arizona&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), and this is among the best
such treatments (e.g. check the guy who helps jumpstart the villain&#x27;s
vehicle).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelly McDonald is a favorite here and not forgetting Brolin. And though
Tommy Lee Jones does a decent performance, I could have been happier
with someone else (he&#x27;s not a great favorite), and his role didn&#x27;t
need a superstar he is. The unflinchingly evil villain is fearsome, made
worse by his calm demeanor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Matador (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-matador-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-matador-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I seriously enjoyed this dark comedy first time I watched. This was due
to the highly enjoyable performances of Pierce Brosnan (the assassin)
and Greg Kinnear (the much nicer guy). The freshness of the story even
led me to place it among the best movies I watched that year. On second
viewing, it started off very well, but the Pierce character, though
still very good (my favorite of all his work), just gets tiring with his
repeated self-deprecating speeches (&amp;quot;I am a mess&amp;quot;). Also, at times,
the character lacks believability. I also found the ending not too
satisfactory, that this assassin character would pull off the last job
so easily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Taken (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/taken-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/taken-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A top-notch thriller, complete with enthralling and fast-paced action
and a solid cast, led by a very credible Liam Neeson. The intensity
matches that of any movie in the trend-setting &lt;em&gt;Bourne&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy, though
with an evidently lower budget, and therefore less gloss, which is
pretty much welcome since found those movies rather wasteful, most
visibly in their chase sequences. In this one movie, there are two
chases sequences, and I feel the first one should have been cut
short... it wasn&#x27;t very interesting, and the movie feels too good to
be yet-another noisy actioner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve noticed the movie has received much negative criticism, which I
found very strange, especially given the skill the material was handled
with. Much of the complaints had to do with it having implausible plot
points, and I guess that I enjoyed it so much that I either didn&#x27;t
notice them, or that such weaknesses were really insignificant.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the subject material (forced sex slavery) quite scary and
expertly handled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Fantasy VII Advent Children (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was a lot more impressed the first time I saw this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity and technical sophistication of the fight sequences are
what &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy only dreamed of. It&#x27;s the best piece of
action I&#x27;ve seen so far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a revisit, I feel like that first statement is an exagerration,
even though the action really is good. Problem is that it&#x27;s just too
frantic, such that it&#x27;s hard to notice what the fuck is going on. With
that in mind, the second statement is no longer true.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the movie unbearable, and I find it strange that I managed first
time around. I found all the talk of life force or somesuch silly, I
found the characters uninteresting, I found the obsession with
children&#x27;s innocence overdone, I found the obsession with beautiful
boys and girls needless, I found the character design (worst of which
was the monster flying creature) to be of intensely bad taste, I found
the choice of lighting shitty, I found the (seeming) requirement to have
familiarity with the games the movie is based in order to appreciate the
(complex) backstory stupid, ...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Appleseed (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In animation, I don&#x27;t remember seeing a face of a female character as
beautifully shot as the lead character here. We also get to have
multiple such moments (she really is gorgeous!), which makes me suspect
the director must have oogled over her. The one problem though is that
she doesn&#x27;t exactly look the part of a supremely skilled warrior. Her
great strength is also left unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 more characters that could have been better:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitomi, the leader of the rescue mission that helped the lead; she
sucks because she was chosen merely for some Japanese idea of sex
appeal, the sort so common in erotic Japanese soft porn stuff;
that&#x27;s no problem, except her character doesn&#x27;t fit the role, and
in a more severe manner than the lead herself.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Gilliam Knute, the genius creator of a species similar to
humans, is also designed purely for sex appeal (she is pretty too).
She really isn&#x27;t my idea of the character she&#x27;s forced into. Also,
the moments involving her aren&#x27;t done very well, a lame attempt to
give the movie emotional punch.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the visual design is quite nice, but is inconsistently so. The
fusion of 2D and 3D is a bit poor, but some of the movements of the
characters (e.g. some movements like walking, or fighting) are quite
impressive. As for the designs of the exo-skeleton, did they have to
look so bulky? Anyways, the catwoman-like robots are wonderful to look
at, complete with their metal-cutting whips. This is one case where sex
appeal worked well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-ex-machina-2007&quot;&gt;my review of its sequel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Notebook (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-notebook-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-notebook-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If found the largest part of the movie unbearably bad, and the very
uninteresting performances of the two leads didn&#x27;t help. The movie
attempts to be a great romance, but there&#x27;s nothing fresh nor is there
anything really interesting. Also, it&#x27;s mostly a period movie, but none
of the costumes impress, and the production design is even worse,
reminiscent of made-for-tv stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Persona (1966)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/persona-1966/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/persona-1966/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another example of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;The Case of &#x27;The Matrix Reloaded&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is how I
felt after the first viewing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... happens to possess much sophistication (direction and dialogue)
with some shocking imagery, including one which must have inspired
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fight-club-1999&quot;&gt;Fight Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a sort of obscenity which is surprising for a 60&#x27;s
movie). The movie also feels fresh, feeling like a modern
psychological drama&#x2F;thriller, and therefore not as tiring and awkward
as those of its age, perhaps testimony of its director, Ingmar
Bergman, who is among the most honored ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching it again, it&#x27;s so strange that it feels like a different movie
altogether. I struggled to stay awake... it&#x27;s boring as fuck. It&#x27;s
also pointless. I must go find out what the fuss is all about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Things We Lost in the Fire (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/things-we-lost-in-the-fire-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/things-we-lost-in-the-fire-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Halle Barry does a similar character she played in &lt;em&gt;Monster&#x27;s Ball&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,
only this time there appears a lot more close-up shots which exposes her
not-to-impressive acting talent (and overrated prettiness). The movie
itself feels a little pretentious, not least of which is the character
of Benicio Del Toro, who plays a guy suffering from drug addiction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shooter (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shooter-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shooter-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Similar in style to the &lt;em&gt;Bourne&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; series, it also happens to be quite
entertaining, although three of the major characters are given bad
performances (the lead, the love interest, and the black guy in power).
The subject matter is of a fearsome concept of sniper work, except that,
as regards to the story, it&#x27;s not convincing how far the bad guys went
for the cash payoff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bourne Identity (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-identity-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-identity-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very enjoyable and well-made, but it feels a little thin in terms of
production design, and the camerawork does not fit a thriller so
gripping (this was fixed in the 2 sequels). There&#x27;s a bad performance
by the guy playing the African target, Clive Owen (playing one of the
assassins) was miscast and doesn&#x27;t do a good job. Matt Damon (Jason
Bourne) pulls the character quite well, and that&#x27;s kool for an actor I
don&#x27;t like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kinsey (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kinsey-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kinsey-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The title character of Kinsey, who is granted a committed performance by
Liam Neeson, is a relentless and brave scientist who embarks on studies
of human sexuality. The movie&#x27;s academic and smart dialogue reminds me
pretty much of &lt;em&gt;Wit&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and among its notable moments was a touching scene
where Kinsey feels pain for his father&#x27;s past, a moment that brought
tear to eye, though nothing compared to the volume of tear delivered by
a later interview with an elderly lady who happened to be grateful of
the professor&#x27;s book. The movie itself is a serious work, and one
that&#x27;s totally devoid of cinematic gloss.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof Kinsey must be my favorite human character in my movie memory
(stern, professional, unflinchingly unapologetic about the scientific
value of his work, intelligent, brave, adventurous, and brutally
honest). I won&#x27;t risk my integrity by saying he&#x27;s the best-developed
character in that admittedly weak memory, but when thinking of such a
guy who went against the status quo by doing controversial research in
American&#x27;s sexual deeds, a tear nearly fills the eye.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leeson&#x27;s performance, excellent as it is, isn&#x27;t award-worthy, but I&#x27;m
too shallow to imagine anyone who can better him in this role.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hancock (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hancock-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hancock-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe something got seriously fucked-up during the production of
&lt;em&gt;Hancock&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; because the pre-twist moments are amazingly fresh and original
and about everything afterwards is shitty:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unnecessary brawl that should have taken place elsewhere other than
the city&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;underdeveloped explanation of super-ability&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;annoying plot-holes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like someone came up with a good story and didn&#x27;t know where
to run with it, and in those moments of panic, hashed up something that
will disappoint any viewer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily all casting is spot-on. Check...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the 1st corporate meeting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the PR guy and his wife&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the inmates&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the kids&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also some of the action (and visual effects) is pretty good (check the
train smash). This a really fresh kinda superhero and it makes one
salivate for (superior) sequels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to find that &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Hancock_(film)#Reception&quot;&gt;so many critics agreed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that the move
started well and screwed up about halfway through.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dark Knight (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t really express the excitement the movie induced into me, mainly
due to Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker, a great contender for the best ever
villainous character in movie history. This character is the centerpiece
of the whole movie, and actually makes everybody else pretty
uninteresting, including the Dark Knight himself. What makes the
character so interesting is beyond just the acting, but also its unusual
philosophical leanings, personality (no fear for death whatsoever),
genius-level smarts (extremely elaborate and effective plans), all of
which makes the material feel real fresh and making this character
thoroughly developed. The character is also fearsome, funny, and
seriously cunning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t say there&#x27;s anything outstanding about the visual effects (the
&lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; series never impressed in this front) and the chase sequences
don&#x27;t rock so hard (EG the Knight&#x27;s super-sized motorbike could have
done with greater speed to enhance the feeling of adrenaline, but
instead felt like it was slouching around at 60km&#x2F;h). The single
greatest visual effect however is Two-Face&#x27;s ugly side. Though nothing
groundbreaking, it&#x27;s somewhat a first, combining a live face with some
very realistic effects. An early bank robbery scene is pure fun and much
of the action is so sophisticated and complex that it&#x27;s hard to keep
track of what happens. It&#x27;s the movie&#x27;s best.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s great length (over 150 minutes) allows room for some shit to creep
in (Two-Face shouldn&#x27;t have been afforded a sub-plot) but it&#x27;s so
amazing elsewhere that it&#x27;s easily the best ever comic book adaptation
(replacing &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, I&#x27;m pretty glad that the Knight&#x27;s romantic interest has
been recast cuz&#x27; the previous actress was the weakest point in the
magnificent &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second look at &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; wasn&#x27;t favorable, all but:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker, the year&#x27;s performance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the bank robbery in an early scene&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not even the action saves the movie, which was mostly wasted cash since
it ain&#x27;t really good. And the last scene really is unbearable. And who
gives a shit about the cheap philosophical blah I so previously
cherished.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no, this isn&#x27;t the best ever comic book adaptation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Incredible Hulk (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-incredible-hulk-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-incredible-hulk-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;1st review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Incredible Hulk&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; has got a great fight between Hulk and &#x27;an
abomination&#x27; and is far better than its shitty predecessor. The
scenic (and abused) views of the massive Latin American slums are
memorable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2nd review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found William Hurt unbearable, while Liv Tyler and Tim Roth didn&#x27;t
help much. Not even the battle of monsters, which itself did lose its
appeal, saves the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The New World (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-new-world-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-new-world-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve since watched Disney&#x27;s &lt;em&gt;Pocahontas&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; over a decade ago and
remember it leaving quite an impression, and it does deserve a revisit,
even though I&#x27;m pretty sure it won&#x27;t match the tremendously superb
re-telling in &lt;em&gt;The New World&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. That&#x27;s a movie in which we are blessed
with amazing story-telling, aided by amazing editing, costume design,
and characterisation (the immeasurably-rich native behavioral customs
which probably exceeds that of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;apocalypto-2006&quot;&gt;Apocalypto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;; the struggling white
inhabitants and especially the kids).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gal playing &lt;em&gt;Pocahontas&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; must have been quite a search, given that
she&#x27;s so perfect and gorgeous and all that shit. Collin Farrell, who
helped me undermine the movie on first appearance, does manage to pull
quite a decent performance too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only realised this was Pocahontas when shown on the end-credits. Yeah,
I watched the movie almost by accident. That it is romance made me
worry, since it&#x27;s hard to find good ones. It doesn&#x27;t disappoint in
that department, and the courtship moments are just about unbeatable.
It&#x27;s like paradise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Magnificent Seven (1960)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-magnificent-seven-1960/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-magnificent-seven-1960/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I find the effort to remake &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-samurai-1954&quot;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; into a western, The
Magnificent Seven unworthy, most especially because the original was so
formidable that it makes the remake laughable or disgusting actually +++
compare the wise old man for example, or worse, the young wannabe
(played by the Toshiro Mifune in the original).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
