<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2016/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>2016 review</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/2016-review/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/2016-review/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;best movie&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of the year is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;captain-fantastic&quot;&gt;Captain Fantastic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The movie also
boasts &lt;strong&gt;best direction&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;best script&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best &lt;strong&gt;visual effects&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;deadpool&quot;&gt;Deadpool&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a movie that
also boasts best &lt;strong&gt;action direction&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;humor&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;favorite character&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is Black Panther (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;captain-america-civil-war&quot;&gt;Captain America: Civil
War&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and runner-up is Leslie Jones in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;ghostbusters&quot;&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;best
performance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is by Simon Helberg in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;florence-foster-jenkins&quot;&gt;Florence Foster Jenkins&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, while
the best &lt;strong&gt;character design&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is that of the Hollows of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;miss-peregrine-s-home-for-peculiar-children&quot;&gt;Miss
Peregrine&#x27;s Home for Peculiar Children&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain Fantastic</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-fantastic/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-fantastic/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the writing and direction excellent, and the acting very
competent. The funeral was very touching, and its simplicity admirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a minor complaint, I wish grandpa, the only real adversary in the
movie, was not so soon forgotten by the writers. Also, I suspect a less
fairy-taily ending would have made for an even better movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, the whole thing offers a fantastic (and refreshing)
examination of a self-educated and self-sufficient family.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Arrival</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/arrival/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/arrival/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Never have I seen the idea of aliens portrayed with such realism. The
attempts at communication is exhilarating, the kind that &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
(1997) gave when I first watched it. Sadly, like that earlier movie, the
movie focuses way too much on the lead... I would have preferred more
attention given to the event. The worst of it is an ability that&#x27;s
revealed towards the movie&#x27;s end. It really takes away from the joy the
movie was. Why do they have to fuck with wonderful movies! Anyways, I
loved the beautiful imagery of the alien writing system, but they could
have made it look less than spheres on fire... at first, I thought they
trying to say that they need a new home due to fucked home planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kubo And The Two Strings</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kubo-and-the-two-strings/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kubo-and-the-two-strings/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It got some very nice visuals in moments where magic occurs. The dialog
also feels fresh, and I loved the character design of the evil sisters,
which is some of the best I&#x27;ve seen, complete with their animation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Miss Peregrine&#x27;s Home for Peculiar Children</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/miss-peregrine-s-home-for-peculiar-children/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/miss-peregrine-s-home-for-peculiar-children/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie may be great to look at (look at that house), and Ella Purnell
insanely desirable (she was an adult at the time, I checked), but I
loved the Hollows the most, the invisible monsters that takes the eyes
of Peculiar people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That bit about eyes is, now thinking about it, rather stupid actually.
It was not even justified in the movie... the writers just jumped to
it, all for the sake of dark.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ghostbusters</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/ghostbusters/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/ghostbusters/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s nothing new, but it was fun watching &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kristen_Wiig&quot;&gt;Kristen Wiig&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; oogle over
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chris_Hemsworth&quot;&gt;Chris Hemsworth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also enjoyed the nerdy performance of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Neil_Casey&quot;&gt;Neil Casey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
who plays the villain, and I wish he got more screen time. There is also
a brief performance by the ever-flawless &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Charles_Dance&quot;&gt;Charles Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. My most
favorite though is the super-fresh one of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Leslie_Jones_%28comedian%29&quot;&gt;Leslie Jones&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Florence Foster Jenkins</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/florence-foster-jenkins/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/florence-foster-jenkins/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you can get past the boring setting, you will find an unusual and
entertaining story of a lady that is too stupid to realise that she
can&#x27;t sing. It is also filled with decent performances, but the one
that makes the whole thing worthy of existence is that of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Simon_Helberg&quot;&gt;Simon
Helberg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who is embarrassed by being the pianist for the singer. He&#x27;s
flawless!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Doctor Strange</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/doctor-strange/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/doctor-strange/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Am not a fan of highly complicated action sequences, though luckily they
weren&#x27;t too long or loud in here. I also enjoyed the title character
before being transformed into a sorcerer, reminding me of the excellent
Dr House (the tv series), and also given a good performance. I did,
however, find his transformation into a great sorcerer rushed. The
bargaining scene was interesting, though I wish the set was a lot less
cartoonish. There were some other stupid things, like the sorcerers
running around chasing each other, when they had the powers to control
objects by mere willpower, one of those &amp;quot;why the fuck didn&#x27;t you do
that in the first place&amp;quot; moments. I wish the black shit on the faces of the
evil sorcerers should have been explained as well... it looks so
stupid, like kids playing with mud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Jason Bourne</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/jason-bourne/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/jason-bourne/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a worthy successor to the first 3 movies: whole thing feels stale,
last car chase too lengthy and uninteresting, father-was-involved story
silly, CIA director played by a boring actor, and that SWAT car is way
too resilient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain America: Civil War</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-civil-war/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-civil-war/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I really, really love the new character, Black Panther, as well as the
performance. The suit is amazing and so is the fighting style. He easily
is the most interesting character in the movie. I do wish that his
background was given more attention though (how did he learn to fight so
well, and how did he manage to own a suit that amazing).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Runner-up is Winter Soldier, who was also the most interesting character
of the previous movie in the series, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;captain-america-the-winter-soldier-2014&quot;&gt;Captain America: Winter Soldier&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3-person fight near the end was something special, though its
motivation was not very believable. It was rather dark for the movie,
and steers too far from what we&#x27;ve come to learn about the characters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like so many big action movies, the movies suffers from over-complexity
of the plot and action sequences, making it harder to follow and
appreciate. It doesn&#x27;t help that it had a ridiculous number of
characters, including 2 surprise additions. Having colorful characters
can be exciting, but they simply were not needed for the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Deadpool</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/deadpool/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/deadpool/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this the most fun (lots and lots of good humor) of all superhero
movies I&#x27;ve yet seen. I&#x27;m also tempted to call it the best, but a
revisit is required before dethroning &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;iron-man&quot;&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from that position. I
find it the most daring (the vulgarity), and has a great number of movie
firsts. In addition, the action direction is superb, and so are the
visual effects. The movie also offers some of the most delicious
instances of Breaking the Fourth Wall. I am also glad that the character
of Colossus (man of metal) was changed... the X-Men movies did a bad
job with theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complaints:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish the romantic interest was less of an action hero herself,
just to lend a bit of realism, as well as avoiding the
super-annoying formula.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Near the end of the movie, tough lady simply disappears without
explanation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
