<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/decent/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most interesting performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Rooker, playing Yondu, the leader of the bandits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Pratt, playing the playful lead&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bautista, playing Drax, the heavily-tattooed brute (amazing make-up)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed Groot, the tree-like humanoid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite character design is the lead villain, though I wish the mud
on the face was explained. I also wish he was a more convincing
villain... he needed deeper development than what he gets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is a lot more whacky than I expected, and does not suit
its epic name. It has lots of humor, and is very entertaining, but I
wish it was less of a passive movie. It also doesn&#x27;t offer anything
new, and the visual effects are merely decent... nothing
ground-breaking here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Miss Peregrine&#x27;s Home for Peculiar Children</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/miss-peregrine-s-home-for-peculiar-children/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/miss-peregrine-s-home-for-peculiar-children/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie may be great to look at (look at that house), and Ella Purnell
insanely desirable (she was an adult at the time, I checked), but I
loved the Hollows the most, the invisible monsters that takes the eyes
of Peculiar people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That bit about eyes is, now thinking about it, rather stupid actually.
It was not even justified in the movie... the writers just jumped to
it, all for the sake of dark.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ghostbusters</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/ghostbusters/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/ghostbusters/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s nothing new, but it was fun watching &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kristen_Wiig&quot;&gt;Kristen Wiig&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; oogle over
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chris_Hemsworth&quot;&gt;Chris Hemsworth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also enjoyed the nerdy performance of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Neil_Casey&quot;&gt;Neil Casey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
who plays the villain, and I wish he got more screen time. There is also
a brief performance by the ever-flawless &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Charles_Dance&quot;&gt;Charles Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. My most
favorite though is the super-fresh one of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Leslie_Jones_%28comedian%29&quot;&gt;Leslie Jones&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zatoichi and the One-Armed Swordsman</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zatoichi-and-the-one-armed-swordsman/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zatoichi-and-the-one-armed-swordsman/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;By the far the most interesting performance is the lead. He pretty much
the only thing that carries the movie, for the story is rather juvenile
and so is the choreography. There are good moments though, but they all
seem to involve him in the scene, my favorite being when he confronts
the gangsters about an abduction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only other performance I enjoyed is that of the prostitute that
falls for him. A darker movie with the same character is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;zatoichi&quot;&gt;Zatoichi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
(2003).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Doctor Strange</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/doctor-strange/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/doctor-strange/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Am not a fan of highly complicated action sequences, though luckily they
weren&#x27;t too long or loud in here. I also enjoyed the title character
before being transformed into a sorcerer, reminding be of the excellent
Dr House (the tv series), and also given a good performance. I did,
however, found his transformation of into a great sorcerer rushed. The
bargaining scene was interesting, though I wish the set was a lot less
cartoonish. There were some other stupid things, like the sorcerers
running around chasing each other, when they had the powers to control
objects by mere willpower, one of those &amp;quot;why the fuck didn&#x27;t you do
that in the first place&amp;quot;. I wish the black shit on the faces of the
evil sorcerers should have been explained as well... it looks so
stupid, like kids playing with mud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Jason Bourne</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/jason-bourne/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/jason-bourne/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a worthy successor to the first 3 movies: whole thing feels stale,
last car chase too lengthy and uninteresting, father-was-involved story
silly, CIA director played by a boring actor, and that SWAT car is way
too resilient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Martian</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-martian/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-martian/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a rare experience for me to watch a movie after reading the novel
it&#x27;s based on. There are so many comparisons, and those can result in
complaints. Anyways, this was a reasonably faithful adaptation, and also
very respectful one; there are many moments where things from the novel
occur briefly even though they don&#x27;t really add to the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one performance that I enjoyed, which happens to be superior to all
others, is that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm0938950&quot;&gt;Benedict Wong&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He felt amazingly realistic, and was
presented a very loving and admirable character. No one else impressed
me, and that includes the acclaimed one of Matt Damon in the leading
role.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Jurassic World</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/jurassic-world/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/jurassic-world/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though the story is shallow and full of shortcuts, the movie is very
enjoyable and got lots of exciting moments. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chris_Pratt&quot;&gt;Chris Pratt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, whose appeal
surprised me in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;guardians-of-the-galaxy&quot;&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, also gives a nice performance
here, though none tops the humorous one of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Irrfan_Khan&quot;&gt;Irrfan Khan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I was also
pleased to see &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Omar_Sy&quot;&gt;Omar Sy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; again (saw him first time in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;good-people-2014&quot;&gt;Good People&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Man from Earth</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-man-from-earth/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-man-from-earth/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For a movie that is almost entirely made of dialog, this is exciting.
It&#x27;s also the first time I saw the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tony_Todd&quot;&gt;Tony Todd&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; play an ordinary
character, which he does very well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish there would be more restraint: the overreaction by some of the
characters was ludicrous and felt forced, and the Jesus part even worse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Friends with Money</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/friends-with-money/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/friends-with-money/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as good as on first viewing (it felt a hell of a lot of fresh
back when I watched it in 2008), but it remains entertaining. I
especially love the performance of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Frances_McDormand&quot;&gt;Frances McDormand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, followed by
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm0564402&quot;&gt;Simon McBurney&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who plays her husband.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula Untold</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-untold/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-untold/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of those movies which choose not to distinguish themselves at all in
terms of story (so shallow, though I do like the vampire re-imagining)
and direction (nothing new), but it is entertaining at least. It also
got great visual effects and amazing make-up work, not to mention a
wonderful performance from the great &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Charles_Dance&quot;&gt;Charles Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Am Legend</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-am-legend/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-am-legend/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It offers among the most impressive sets in movie history: a Manhattan
so deserted that lions and impalas walk its streets. The city is also
filled with rusting vehicles, including military tanks and planes. Too
kool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emma Thompson, though appearing briefly, does offer the movie&#x27;s most
electrifying performance. Will Smith, on the other hand, shows a great
lack of acting skills, and is even embarrassing at times. He is,
however, interesting enough to lead the story well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie was a great first-time experience, but the revisits were
lesser by far.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Book Thief (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-book-thief-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-book-thief-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Rush gives a very touching performance as kindly guardian of a
girl who lost her family. He is as loving a character as I&#x27;ve seen in
movies. Emily Watson also shines as the angry wife. Both performances
are flawless, and the movie feels like a weird and horrid fable. It&#x27;s
not a pleasant watch, especially the second half.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Age of Extinction (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-age-of-extinction-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-age-of-extinction-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s the best in the series so far, but I don&#x27;t really see an
improvement in visual effects over &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I&#x27;m guessing
that&#x27;s because &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-2007&quot;&gt;the first movie in the series&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; set a ridiculously high
bar. In keeping to tradition, the movie is also noisy and has
overly-frantic action (WTF&#x27;s going on), and has way too much of it. It
also has a shallow story-line and none of the characters are very
interesting. Luckily, there is no &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tyrese_Gibson&quot;&gt;Tyrese Gibson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Josh_Duhamel&quot;&gt;Josh Duhamel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to
help spoil things. There is also no mention of why these primary human
characters were so drastically changed... sad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is entertaining throughout, despite running for over 150
minutes. The evil Transformers were scarily-violent, as they always were
in this series. The scariest of them, Megatron, was pretty much cast
aside in this movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How To Train Your Dragon (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was lots more impressive on first viewing. This time around, I found
the face animation terrible, the story recycled, complete with tired
humor, and a forced villain (why couldn&#x27;t it be trained as well, and
what&#x27;s the story... why is it so big). Luckily the whole thing is not
boring, and there are lots of scary moments and edge-of-seat action. The
concept of befriending dragons is also interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Appleseed Alpha (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-alpha-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-alpha-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;More a showcase of animation technology than a satisfying story for a
feature-length movie, it&#x27;s a prequel to the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-2004&quot;&gt;two&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-ex-machina-2007&quot;&gt;movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s got
some good things going for it:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lips of the little girl are amazing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The environments have wonderful detail&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cyborg lover of the lead character of the previous movies,
Briario, is a lot more pleasing to watch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, there is no noticeable 2D&#x2F;3D fusion, which helped made
me notice how sucky we still at at doing convincing human faces, unless
you have a massive budget I suppose. The movie doesn&#x27;t represent any
noticeable advancement of animation capabilities, even though it has its
moments. As regards the story, it&#x27;s interesting enough, but really has
nothing new. The giant robot thing is just stupid, and the leading lady,
who is not as a major a character as she was in the first movie, still
has unexplained physical prowess. She also too damn lucky, brushing off
highly dangerous situations like they are nothing. Sad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>300: Rise of an Empire (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/300-rise-of-an-empire-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/300-rise-of-an-empire-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The acting style of Eva Green worked far better in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dark-shadows-2012&quot;&gt;Dark Shadows&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and
is in fact is embarrassing here. She is as unconvincing as the other
tough gal character, the wife of Leonidas, who had to go as being on the
front-line in battle. It&#x27;s as if someone was desperate to do the girl
power thing, to disastrous effect. Did I say embarrassing?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I like the parallel story-line approach, where much of the
events in the movies take place at the same time as those from the
earlier, and far superior, movie. Sadly we do not have an appealing
lead, and in fact not a single character impresses. The battles still
look good, but nowhere near those from the original, nor are the visuals
as amazing. The sex scene was even more stupid than the one in the
original.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>RoboCop (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robocop-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robocop-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The new suit is a lot more interesting (think the 2008 &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), and
greater detail given to the workings of the man-machine combo. There is
good quality visual affects, and the movie was fun enough to have me
wish for a longer running length. I wish better actors were chosen for
the roles of wife and partner, and it would have been nice had this
partner been given a meatier role. Better still, it should have been a
woman, in honor of the 1987 movie. Or better still, get rid of the
partner. There&#x27;s enough other things to keeping things interesting. I
also wish someone else was chosen in place of the uninteresting Gary
Oldman, the same person who made the Nolan Batman trilogy less bearable
than it needed to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crime-fighting part was rather rushed, and the story not very solid.
I enjoyed watching Samuel L. Jackson play a commentator, and the first
scene was really good, though it felt like more was left to be said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a great reboot. I can&#x27;t tell if it&#x27;s better than the
original for it&#x27;s been too long, but I think it&#x27;s less scary, but also
less cartoonish. The lead actor is also not as interesting. Younger yes,
but a lesser actor, and a boring face actually.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mars Attacks! (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mars-attacks-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mars-attacks-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The deception by the aliens on humans is one of the interesting things
about the movie, and the other being the flirting between the Pierce
Brosnan and the Sarah Jessica Parker characters. The latter is actually
quite charming, especially as a dog. Other interesting characters are
the forgetful lady and the disguised alien.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is overall entertaining, but has just too much violence...
the attacks are prolonged. The sub-plot about the former boxer is
horrible, complete with bad acting and uninteresting characters (boxer,
wife, kids) and looks like it&#x27;s from some shitty B-movie. The whole
thing is also pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dead Man (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dead-man-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dead-man-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A bizarre and sleep-inducing work, this dark comedy has its moments:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene with Billy Bon Thornton is fun to watch, due to the
idiotic behavior of his character and its companions. It is my
favorite in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character of the native American feels more of a guardian angel
than anything real. One feels a sense of comfort having him around,
and his bravery commendable, not to mention his kindness. He is the
most unusual character of them all, or should I say the most
unconvincing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character of Crispin Glover is also bizarre. He gives a very
good performance, brief as it is.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know what the fuck&#x27;s up with the story though, what the point
of it all is. Why do people make movies like this? It does however
possess the honor of having an entire book written about it, by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;best-movie-critic-jonathan-rosenbaum&quot;&gt;the
great Jonathan Rosenbaum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pathology (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pathology-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pathology-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite an original story with a spectacular opening sequence, and a touch
here and there of wonderful shots (e.g. check the part where the lead
drinks water greedily, the day after his first experience).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is wonderful casting too, even though I&#x27;ll have to excuse the
lead and the villain. I most especially appreciate the role of the
middle-aged lead of the team, played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;John_de_Lancie&quot;&gt;John de Lancie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He was a
pleasure to watch. There was also another nice, but tiny, performance by
the guy playing the fiance&#x27;s father. There&#x27;s great characters, like
the massive black guy, as well as the trailer-trash fat guy. The dialog
is quite good too, and the make-up is even better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is quite silly, and rather pointless. The lead transforms
(participates in the game) way too quick to convince. There is also too
much (raunchy) sex, most of which is needless. The great jealousy the
villains portray is unconvincing, and so is their bullying. Also, the
ending feels rushed, as if there wasn&#x27;t much material to work with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2008&#x2F;film&#x2F;reviews&#x2F;pathology-1200535058&quot;&gt;this review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tree of Life (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tree-of-life-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tree-of-life-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of wonderful editing and gorgeous shots, most especially
in the beginning... the first 20 minutes, just before the pre-historic,
beginning of life section. My favorite of these shots is the waterfall.
It&#x27;s amazing. Also, in those 20 minutes, I enjoyed the Sean Penn
moments the most... I don&#x27;t remember corporate environments shot (and
edited) that way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not much else to celebrate, unfortunately: Brad Pitt is miscast
(i.e. unconvincing), the movie is mostly boring and unbearably
meditative, and much of mutterings (prayers and thoughts) of the
characters unintelligible, like I&#x27;m supposed to fill in the blanks. I
also don&#x27;t know what the point of the entire exercise is, though I
liked the fact that the strict father wasn&#x27;t presented in a shallow
manner... he had sweet moments, and even apologized for his shitty
behavior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In Time (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-time-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-time-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We here see a world where people stop physically aging when they reach
25 and have a year to live unless they get more (or less) time. Money is
replaced by time as currency, and the reason the setup is such is left
unexplained, though the hint given is population control. It also
appears as if the situation can&#x27;t be changed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This beautiful concept is fucked by a lazy plot and stupid casting
choices (the people were supposed to look 25). The best fun in the movie
can only be seen in the early scenes, but then the overly-courageous
acts and extra skills of the Justin Timberlake character were left
unexplained... lazy writing. Luckily it&#x27;s not boring, even to the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Family (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-family-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-family-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The two kids are a lot more interesting than the parents in this dark
comedy about a troublesome family that finds itself under witness
protection. It&#x27;s well-made (and well-shot) but not very well-written.
The over-the-top violence imposed the each of the family members are
supposed to be funny, but fall flat, and I don&#x27;t like how their cruelty
is downplayed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel Robert De Niro, the guy that gave &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-movie-performances&quot;&gt;the best performance in
history&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, should have retired over a decade ago. He hasn&#x27;t done
anything worthy of his skills, and is not interesting enough to keep me
interested. Or maybe he&#x27;s just overrated, and incapable of doing
anything beyond his usual bad guy persona. He&#x27;s boring, though the
movie isn&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Upside Down (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/upside-down-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/upside-down-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It got a great concept (the most original I&#x27;ve seen in a while) and
great visuals. But after the novelty wears off about half-way through,
there&#x27;s pretty much nothing left. I enjoyed the performance of Timothy
Spall, but his character was not well-developed. None of the other
characters are given quality treatment either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rush (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rush-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rush-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the Niki Lauda character quite unusual (and curious), making it
the most interesting thing in the movie. The movie doesn&#x27;t have much
else going for it: I did not enjoy watching the portrayal of the rival
and his drama (same old boring playboy), and I am not a big fan of
racing cars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Destination 5 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-5-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-5-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked a few things:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bridge sequence is a showcase of decent visual effects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The massage lady gives a quality performance, though brief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The homage paid to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;final-destination-2000&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the franchise is very
welcome, almost iconising it&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lead actor is damn beautiful and also not boring&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is sadly not offering anything new, and the sudden murderous
behavior of one of the survivors serious stupid... very unconvincing. I
did like the performance of Tony Todd, though it was laughably
creepy... stupid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dark Knight Rises (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-rises-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-rises-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in love with the voice and utterances of Bane, a physically
formidable villain in a mask. The movie is far bigger and more intense
than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-dark-knight-2008&quot;&gt;the immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also found it more entertaining (at
least on first viewing), and a lot less annoying, though nothing matches
the miracle that is Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker. The title character
sounds unconvincing with the silly voice, and the movie feels like a
mess. Maybe it&#x27;s just too long, and the writers too desperate to
impress. The stupid twist didn&#x27;t help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>MirrorMask (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mirrormask-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mirrormask-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very effective alternative to sleeping pills, but filled with curious
works of art, and some interestingly bizarre character designs. It is
pretty much pointless, but it was sort of interesting to watch the
super-cute gal go about her dreamy adventures. Of the creatures, none
was as annoying as the human-cat hybrids, none as scary as the bird-ape
hybrids, and none as original as the floating giants. I cannot remember
creatures as saddening as these giants. They alone make the entire movie
worth watching.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Now You See Me (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/now-you-see-me-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/now-you-see-me-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A ridiculous plot twist (I do not mind being fooled, but this is going
too far), some smart-ass characters (I don&#x27;t mind such, but this also
goes too far, or maybe they are just not well-written), and an
uninteresting back-story stop this one from being more than a cheap
fantasy-thriller. Luckily it&#x27;s very entertaining, and got decent
performances, not to mention an extra-desirable police lady. My favorite
performance is the lady who gets hypnotized in an early scene. She&#x27;s
incredible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Elysium (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/elysium-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/elysium-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is an entertaining movie, but lacks a well-developed story and
characters. Not even the acting is satisfactory, bar that of Matt Damon
(lead character) and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;William_Fichtner&quot;&gt;William Fichtner&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (his boss). The actions of the
violent villains are not justified, and so are those of the Jodie Foster
villain. The leader of the revolutionry criminals is very unconvincing.
The movie also feels rushed. It&#x27;s a pity because it starts well, and is
well-made (the director made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;district-9-2009&quot;&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; after all), complete with
great visual effects and action direction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>World War Z (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/world-war-z-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/world-war-z-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The family-focus thing is boring, and so is the overly-heroic antics of
the not-so-interesting lead. The story also feels incomplete, and I&#x27;ve
seen superior treatment of the subject matter (of pandemics)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive note, I have never seen zombies so vicious. Also, the
movie is not boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Escape From Planet Earth (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/escape-from-planet-earth-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/escape-from-planet-earth-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is reasonably entertaining, the animation is sophisticated, and
visual design is of good quality, but it suffers from relying too much
on recycled material, most notably from &lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;megamind-2010&quot;&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I must not fault it too much for its direction, which is
also typical of so many expensive 3D-animated movies, including the
above-mentioned ones. Even the character design is not fresh, though I
did like one character... the giant gal. She is also not an original
concept (see Eva in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;igor-2008&quot;&gt;Igor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), but then again I&#x27;m a sucker for misfits
like this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Serbian Film (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-serbian-film-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-serbian-film-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Less shocking than I expected, given how notorious it is. It&#x27;s also not
badly-made, and the story not so bad, though it would be nice to know
what the point of it all is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Adventures Of Tintin: The Secret Of The Unicorn (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-adventures-of-tintin-the-secret-of-the-unicorn-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-adventures-of-tintin-the-secret-of-the-unicorn-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The chase sequence in the Arab city is among the most complex action
sequences I have seen in any movie. This isn&#x27;t praise... &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;overly-complex-action-sequences&quot;&gt;I&#x27;m not a
fan of such excess&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and this must have been seriously expensive. The
rest of it is moderately interesting, and the animation highly-detailed,
and at times highly-sophisticated. It did not, however, result in any
wow moment, but I appreciate the one detail of the Captain&#x27;s convincing
eyes near the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pan&#x27;s Labyrinth (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pan-s-labyrinth-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pan-s-labyrinth-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not very interesting, except for the scene with the child killer, which
is a showcase of visual mastery... one of the best (and most original)
character designs I&#x27;ve seen. I also enjoyed the moments with the faun
character, who also represents good character design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Unknown (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/unknown-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/unknown-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;First review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a similar feel to &lt;em&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and is also set in dark Europe and
stars the very capable Liam Neeson. The storyline is solid and so is
the acting. There is a lack of gloss, and it&#x27;s very edgy. The twist
is pretty good and so is the action, although it&#x27;s not kool when you
see an untrained person suddenly capable of driving a car like a
stuntman. Writers this good could have come up with something better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels a lot worse, which is yet another instance of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;The case of
&#x27;The Matrix Reloaded&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s not as interesting, it does not feel
like &lt;em&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, it&#x27;s not set in dark Europe, the twist not too
interesting (unless it&#x27;s your first time), and the untrained life-saver
merely irritating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Iron Man 3 (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/iron-man-3-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/iron-man-3-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For my most anticipated movie of this year, this was
less-than-impressive. I did not like seeing Tony Stark having impressive
physical abilities (which was excused by some evidence of martial arts
training), or the uninteresting idea of flaming villains (though the
Pepper entrance was fun), or the whole story in general. Felt like mere
opportunism (milking the franchise), and the abilities of the suit keep
growing more and more, to ludicrous levels: In the second movie, the
portable suit idea was kool, and so was the &lt;em&gt;magnetic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; one in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-avengers-2012&quot;&gt;The
Avengers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The remote-driven one in this third one is also a nice touch,
but when it gets to the point of its individual parts flying themselves,
I get to wish the filmmakers put a reasonable limit to the fantasy.
Also, what&#x27;s with the boy genius thing? What&#x27;s the chances of
accidentally meeting such? Are the writers so untalented?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still a fun movie, but it makes me miss the freshness of the
first movie and the villain of the second; apart from being
unconvincing, the primary one here, played by Guy Pearce, is also not
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kinky Boots (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kinky-boots-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kinky-boots-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only due to the presence of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chiwetel_Ejiofor&quot;&gt;Chiwetel Ejiofor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who
provides what&#x27;s easily the movie&#x27;s most interesting performance. The
movie&#x27;s climax is rather outrageous, and bordering on embarrassing. The
movie remains a worthy addition to those which criticize oppression
based on gender. This Chiwetel guy is also kinda pretty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Good Night, and Good Luck (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/good-night-and-good-luck-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/good-night-and-good-luck-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s what a revisit felt like, back in 2010:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&#x27;t pack as much of a punch as before. It even felt barren.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping that the third viewing would be more pleasant, but it&#x27;s
still the same as the second. It is sad because I really enjoyed this
movie on first viewing. It remains an important movie of course, not to
mention being the best David Straithairn moment yet. The camerawork is
also simple, yet effective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Point Blank (1967)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/point-blank-1967/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/point-blank-1967/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you look past the ugliness of having been made in 1967 (awkward
direction and acting), it actually is interesting. This is partly with
the help of the lead, Lee Marvin (not exactly a good performance, but an
interesting one nevertheless), and partly with the help of his
character, due to his relentless pursuit for the money taken from him.
The flashbacks are badly made, complete with horrible editing. The scene
where his gal unleashes violence against him is memorable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was led to this after finding out it&#x27;s based on the same material as
the later &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-1999&quot;&gt;Payback&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a far superior take.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What&#x27;s Eating Gilbert Grape (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/what-s-eating-gilbert-grape-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/what-s-eating-gilbert-grape-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Answer involves 2 challenges:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with a close relative suffering from extreme obesity.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with another close relative, suffering from mental
retardation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the movie important, even though it&#x27;s not especially good.
The romance, or rather the gal (the sort of character that is Juliette
Lewis&#x27; now-dated trademark), is not interesting, and most everything
else that happens (e.g. the cheating wife episode) just feels random and
needless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however like Crispin Glover&#x27;s performance and I wish he was given
more screen time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Marley and Me (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/marley-and-me-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/marley-and-me-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing of note is the care regarding the impressive performance of
that dog; the training involved must have been quite involved. It&#x27;s
amazing. The movie&#x27;s best moment, though, is the fast-paced scene in
which the lead character narrates a summary of his writings (he is
newspaper columnist). I thought it was quite innovative, complete with
fun content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond embracing pets, I thought the whole excercise was pointless. I
kept wondering, &amp;quot;Is this it? You sure this is all this movie is
about?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It may be a B-movie, but it does get intriguing at times, with quality
bits of dialog here and there. My favorite moment is when the smart gal
explains to the cop the complexity of the calculation he tries to force
her to perform. Solid piece of performance there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst thing about the movie is the unexplained transformation into
villainy by one of the characters. Feels silly and desperate, as if the
writers were concerned the whole premise is not exciting enough, which
it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I was big fan of X-Men. That is why it was such a
disappointment to watch this movie (about a decade ago). I was hoping
for impressive effects and interesting characters, but instead got an
uninteresting Hugh Jackman as Wolverine, and too much of a focus on the
Anna Paquin character, Rogue. I remember been saddened by Halle Berry&#x27;s
performance, perhaps because I was not a fan, but also because I was
also a fan of the character she plays, Storm, and she just didn&#x27;t do a
good job. There are decent performances by the old men playing the
leaders of the opposing factions, Xavier and Magneto. But even then, it
was business-as-usual for them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Battle In Heaven (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/battle-in-heaven-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/battle-in-heaven-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Never in my movie-watching history have I seen a character as dull as
the lead character here. The only one that comes close is that of
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;crimson-gold-2003&quot;&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It also happens to be the most bizarre movie I have seen
this year. It explores sex in a way I have not seen before, in that we
get to see very unattractive characters (husband and wife) take part in
it. The way they are shot is also very suggestive, like the movie is
some sort of soft porn, only with superior direction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is also a more extreme form of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;romance-1999&quot;&gt;Romance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, in that it was
probably inspired by it, both in terms of explicit sexual shots and very
slow and pro-longed takes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only characters that seem alive are the young gal (fucking gorgeous)
and her friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shortbus (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shortbus-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shortbus-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The characters in this movie express sexual desire to levels most people
are not brave enough to, which is a bit of a plus. The peformances are
of decent quality, but the level of eccentricity of some of the
characters not so kool. Sure they are respectable for pushing the
boundaries, but there is also that thing called taste&#x2F;sense:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what the fuck is up with the girl with the shitty hairstyle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the club owner (smart but not so interesting)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or the therapist, whose outburst was not at all realistic, nor is
her stupid belief (women cannot orgasm) believable, especially for
someone who deals with workings of the mind.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is like the makers wanted something profound, but lacked the writing
talent. The ending is boring and the movie pointless, except insofar as
to push the boundaries in blurring the distinction between porn and
not-porn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Beowulf (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/beowulf-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/beowulf-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this old-fashioned and take on fantasy heroism a lot more
first time I watched it, though I did find it pointless, and still do.
Even the lead villain isn&#x27;t as seductive. The animation could be
better, but the worst of it was the human faces. They should have made
it live-action, or better still, not made it at all. Or it just needed a
better writer. Some of the imagery was worthy of notice, especially the
water-on-skin effects. It was not ground-breaking though, at least to an
untrained eye like mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Watchmen (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/watchmen-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/watchmen-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watchmen is bizarre in a delightful manner, though it has annoying black
spots all over the place. One major one is everything about the
too-powerful shining guy (Mr Manhattan), and another is the bad old-age
make-up, so bad it may be deliberate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bright spots make up for this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the performance of The Comedian, especially the moment when he kills
a pregnant lady, pregnant with his child&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the equally affective one where the disguised face is exposed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of brutality in the movie, including the supposedly-nice
protagonists breaking bones needlessly. The scene itself, where they get
attacked by some oriental guys, is stupid. Either that, or it is some
sort of parody, as is the case with the War Room thing, parodying a
(great) satire, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-1964&quot;&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one werid movie that I just don&#x27;t know how to place, so will
leave it here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Buffalo Soldiers (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/buffalo-soldiers-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/buffalo-soldiers-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My initial review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s surprising that a movie as radical as Buffalo Soldiers could be
distributed at all since it&#x27;s about the most effective anti-war movie
I&#x27;ve seen in a long time. It&#x27;s filled with fresh acting, though the
movie&#x27;s villain doesn&#x27;t really convince while the lead character
could have been portrayed by a better actor (Phoenix isn&#x27;t
interesting at all).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit was not so great, including the radicalness I felt, the
freshness of the acting (what was I thinking?), nor the anti-war
sentiment strong at all. I even went as far awarding it best story of
movies I watched first time in 2008, which is something a little
puzzling now. Instead, it just feels pointless and arbitrary.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Syriana (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/syriana-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/syriana-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is my initial review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syriana is an uncompromising examination of government-sponsored
corporate evil and an idiotic oil-rich monarchy that condones it, with
a surprise ending. It&#x27;s a minimalist, yet powerful, narrative.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit proved not as impressive, and I don&#x27;t remember what was
surprising about the ending. The quiet and distrinctive style of
direction gives it a fresh feel, although the quiet treatment tends to
make it boring in places.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all performances are interesting, especially the investigator with a
troubled housemate. I did not enjoy watching the middle-East kids
either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect 3 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-3-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-3-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far better than its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2-2006&quot;&gt;immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and a worthy successor to
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2004&quot;&gt;the original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is a well-made and well-acted thriller with a
well-written script. The twist is interesting, though not entirely
convincing... feels forced. I enjoyed the performances of the 2
detectives, though no one was as good as overweight plant-loving
character, a sort of wise guide for the lead character. The &#x27;rape&#x27;
scene is superbly made.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Total Recall (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/total-recall-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/total-recall-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is so different from the first same-titled one from 1990 such
that it cannot really be called a remake. It is not quite as
interesting, and so are the lead actors (there is no Schwarzenegger or
Sharon Stone), does not take place in Mars (sadly) and is a
straight-forward thriller without any mind-fuck qualities the first one
had. The action was really overlong, and had the too-many hero-luck
moments, making it nearly unbearable towards the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nice technology ideas I have not seen before:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necklace that allows one to change appearance; by the way, the guy
the protagonist turns into gives a nice performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transport that goes through center of the planet straight to the
other side.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small video cameras that attach themselves to surfaces, shot through
a gun.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some I have seen:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;levitating cars (a few movies)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a machine that gives one convincing but fake memories (the first
&lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Legend of the Guardians: The Owls of Ga&#x27;Hoole (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/legend-of-the-guardians-the-owls-of-ga-hoole-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/legend-of-the-guardians-the-owls-of-ga-hoole-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;intial-review&quot;&gt;intial review&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owls aren&#x27;t interesting animals at all, so I watched this in
preparation of moving on, but was captivated by the photo-realisitic
rendering of the birds&#x27; faces. I also enjoyed the humor offered by the
two birds that kidnapped the brothers, and that&#x27;s one other thing that
encouraged me to watch the rest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie runs for around 100 minutes, but it feels very epic. It lacks
the immediate and glossy excitement of a Disney&#x2F;Pixar movie, and feels
more stately and serious, as well as darker. The characters are
well-developed and it doesn&#x27;t feel like shortcuts were taken, well
other than that the repeat trips felt shortened, much like Timon and
Pumba&#x27;s when they followed Simba back home. The battles are very
well-made, and the ocean waves, though brief, were quite impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;revisit&quot;&gt;revisit&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not experience any epicness second time around, nor did I notice
any outstanding character development. The eye candy was also not as
impressive. I also noticed annoying coincidences, as well as a far less
enjoyable experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Breaking the Waves (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/breaking-the-waves-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/breaking-the-waves-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;All performances are of good quality, best of which is the best friend
of the protagonist, who also happens to be a nurse. The movie is
otherwise unbearably boring, and me wonders why people punish themselves
by constructing such painful movies, especially ones so pointless. The
experience is made even worse by the ridiculous length of around 150
minutes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Amazing Spider-Man (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not really a supreme reboot, but it is an okay one. It does have
some exciting effects, and I most especially love the fights between the
hero and the villain. The love interest is not interesting, nor is any
of the characters who fill the movie. Well, maybe except the villain,
but only when in lizard form. The story is merely okay, and is bad at
times, e.g. the help the hero gets near the end with the cranes and all
(WTF!).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/austin-powers-international-man-of-mystery-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/austin-powers-international-man-of-mystery-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is good humor here and there, some of which is unique. Check for
example the opening scene, and every musical and photo sequence. Trouble
is that some of the jokes just miss the spot, while the hilarity of some
totally disappear on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One low point of the movie is the miscast Elizabeth Hurley, whose
persona (or acting ability) simply does not fit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Devil in a Blue Dress (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/devil-in-a-blue-dress-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/devil-in-a-blue-dress-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a lot more enjoyable when I first watched it several years ago,
though I remember nothing else of the experience, other than the
performance of Don Cheadle. It is the one movie that made me respect him
acting skills, though he never again repeated a performance this good
(in my experience). The rest of the story is mildly entertaining and the
movie did not age well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zombieland (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zombieland-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zombieland-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts very well, with well-made visuals of zombie attacks, and a
nice play on &#x27;rules to survive&#x27;. It sadly gets messed when it&#x27;s clear
the writers did not know where to run with the story, and made even
worse by the sisters, who serve only to annoy, especially the older one.
Her failed attempt at sex appeal and sass does not help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do however have to appreciate the moment where the Woody Harrelson
character expresses great admiration for Bill Murray.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Vicky Cristina Barcelona (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/vicky-cristina-barcelona-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/vicky-cristina-barcelona-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those strange movies that I enjoy heavily on first
viewing and fall bad on a second one. For example, I found the character
of Javier Bardem incredibly appealing, but saw a cheap and pretentious
character second time around, as if the overly self-conscious Woody
Allen was desperate to appease. As for Penlope Cruz, I praised her
profusely for her portrayal of the crazy-but-gifted ex-lover. Well, the
performance is good, but the appeal wore off, but it remains &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;favorite-of-career-performances&quot;&gt;my
favorite of her performances&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I guess the main appeal of the movie is
the concept of open relationships (and frank sex talk).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Thor (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/thor-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/thor-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Does not live up to the hype, some parts of the shallow story are
embarrassing, and the humor is recycled. The visual effects are meh, and
so is the costume design of the Asgards. Their city has a nice design
though, excessive as it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title character is gorgeous as fuck. I also like the concept of the
mysterious gatekeeper, and the character. The silver robot is also
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the movie more on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Cabin In The Woods (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-cabin-in-the-woods-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-cabin-in-the-woods-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This must be the weirdest of horror movies I&#x27;ve seen, and also
surprisingly highly rated. It still has those abused horror elements me
hates so much, and the only fresh thing it adds to the genre is the
characters who watch the victims in excitement. The leading gal is
extra-desirable but a little low on acting talent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Igor (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/igor-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/igor-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much enjoyable, complete with an interesting lead and an even
more interesting creation in the form of a sweet oversized monster, Eva.
The character design is of good quality (check each of the mad
scientists for example), but the sad moment, that in which the lead
reveals lies he told, sucks as much as it normally does in, for example,
romantic comedies. This heavily taints an otherwise good fantasy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is one of those movies with a plot so complex that me got lost very
soon into it. It is also one of those movies that are so devoid of
excitement that it feels a bit like self-torture to watch to the end. It
didn&#x27;t help that the very uninteresting Gary Oldman is the lead
character, though it helped that there was a performance as fabulous as
that of Colin Firth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brothers (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brothers-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brothers-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of emotion, but mostly bearable due to quality direction. Toby
Maguire has never been this scary. The nurse girlfriend is gorgeous as
fuck. The movie is pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wrath of the Titans (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wrath-of-the-titans-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wrath-of-the-titans-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The visual effects are decent, the performance of Liam Neeson (Zeus) a
lot better than in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;clash-of-the-titans-2010&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the performance of Ralph
Fiennes a lot less menacing (and less interesting), and the movie itself
less exciting. The new character, the son of Poseidon, is interesting.
Andromeda, the queen of the human army, is given a miscast and
uninteresting performance by Rosamund Pike.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part 2</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-2/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-2/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots more action than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, perhaps more than all the
others too, though not really an interesting conclusion. The main battle
feels like a poor copy of that in &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings: The Return of the
King&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, though it&#x27;s not bad at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-goblet-of-fire-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-goblet-of-fire-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is no improvement on &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-prisoner-of-azkaban-2004&quot;&gt;the one immediately predeceding it&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but
is darker still, perhaps with even greater effects, though not as
numerous. The creature design of the baby-sized arch-villain deserves
respect, though it&#x27;s nothing new. The scenes in which it appears makes
for a darker movie than the previous ones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The careless passiveness of the movie is quite annoying. One glaring
example is that Harry Potter&#x27;s troubles with the dragon are given all
the attention, while those of his competitors are totally ignored.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One performance that I enjoyed a lot, a new character, is the super-tall
lady.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The battle between arch-villain and Dumbledore is the best action piece
so far in this series. It&#x27;s quite intense and has wonderful visual
effects. There are other good visual effect moments here and there. Even
the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dementors&quot;&gt;Dementors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which I so admired in the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-prisoner-of-azkaban-2004&quot;&gt;3rd movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, have been given
a facelift, though I prefer the original look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-chamber-of-secrets-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-chamber-of-secrets-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not as enchanting as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-sorcerers-stone-2001&quot;&gt;the first one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but scarier with far bigger
effects, though none is spectacular, much of which is clumsy: the
spiders, the snake, and the angry tree. More tiring than the first since
it&#x27;s more of the same thing. The new ugly slave-like character is
unbearably irritating. It is similar to the Smeagol&#x2F;Gollum character in
the Lord of the Rings trilogy, only a lot less interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one character I enjoyed much is that of the owner of the flying car.
Check especially the moment he accidentally celebrates the tale of the
boys&#x27; adventures in the flying car. My previous favorite character from
the first movie does not compare, and is a lot less interesting this
time around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&#x27;s Stone (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-sorcerer-s-stone-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-sorcerer-s-stone-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Two things I enjoyed most:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the performance of the guy playing step-father of Harry Potter; it
was however a recycled caricature&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the chess game, which had great character design and animation;
it&#x27;s a pity it was mixed with substandard editing, with shots
repeatedly cutting to the kids; also, the kids didn&#x27;t fit well in a
sequence so scary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most anything else is just standard, which is the sort of thing that
made it mysterious to me why the book&#x2F;movie series has had such
spectacular success.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Beginners (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/beginners-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/beginners-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The one thing fresh about this movie is the loving portrayal of an
elderly gay man, which is something I don&#x27;t remember seeing before. The
direction is also pretty competent, and so is the acting. Pity it&#x27;s
being boring, and it&#x27;s slight bizarredness (e.g. talking dog) help make
it real unbearable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Postal (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/postal-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/postal-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is special for being the first movie I saw poking fun at the
9&#x2F;11 disaster, where the plane crashing onto the skyscraper is portrayed
as an accident. The rest of it is seriously unconventional, some good,
too much of it uninteresting, and the whole thing pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Johnny English Reborn (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/johnny-english-reborn-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/johnny-english-reborn-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this a lot due to the delicious humor, best of which was the
out-of-control chair... absolutely hilarious. It was all nice, until
they had to do the stupid thing of bringing someone from the dead.
Instead of parodying the silly idea, they just fall prey to it. The end
is also lazy, and as uninteresting as the villain. Johnny&#x27;s sidekick is
a strange choice for a movie character, while Rosamund Pike seems a
goddess. How could anyone look like that! WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Infidel (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-infidel-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-infidel-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very different comedy with a very unlikely lead; I loved the
performance of the extremist Muslim leader, especially when in the house
of the infidel; the end, where a con-man is exposed, is a lousy cop-out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Confidence (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/confidence-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/confidence-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s too much of an attempt at doing kool, much like &lt;em&gt;Lucky Number
Slevin&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (which was made some years later), only with a lower budget and
less flash (production design, cinematography). It&#x27;s however a lot more
satisfying. I loved John Carrol Lynch&#x27;s performance. Morris Chestnut, a
not-so-competent actor, is miscast, and so is Dustin Hoffman, who
appears to be trying too hard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Avatar (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/avatar-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/avatar-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;good&quot;&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best thing in the movie is the tribal humanoid creatures; they
are given solid and believable personalities, as if they actually
exist. The best work is the leading lady, who also happens to be
damn fucking&#x27; desirable. I also loved the female spiritual leader
(she got presence).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire experience of those humanoids riding flying creatures is
pure movie magic. The creatures they ride are quite impressive
(check for example when our hero is to tame one for the first time).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of Avatars is quite unique and fresh... it would be
interesting to experience another body.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The human characters were not given quality treatment, all but the
lead (the image of him and his wheelchair is iconic). Most
unconvincing is the scarred military leader, followed by the
corporate representative (Giovanni Ribisi).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general feel of the alien world feels too artificial (there&#x27;s
too many bright-colored plants and animals). The creature design is
not satisfactory.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The helicopter driver lady should have been excluded. She is just
not an interesting actor, and cheapens the movie further.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-others-feel&quot;&gt;what others feel&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked this &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;12&#x2F;22&#x2F;opening-pandoras-box-the-arguments-over-avatar&#x2F;&quot;&gt;short analysis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One commenter &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;12&#x2F;22&#x2F;opening-pandoras-box-the-arguments-over-avatar&#x2F;#comment5&quot;&gt;correctly noted&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; stylistic similarities to the
much-deplored Jar Jar Binks of Star Wars fame.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also enjoyed a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.huffingtonpost.com&#x2F;ray-kurzweil&#x2F;reflections-on-iavatari_b_500226.html&quot;&gt;disapproving review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by a famous inventor and
futurist, Ray Kurzweil.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Batman Begins (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/batman-begins-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/batman-begins-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is sad that this turned out a lot less impressive on a revisit,
though it remains better than any of the Batman movies before it. The
lead actor is not interesting; the mini-villain, the old man running the
underworld, is a bit interesting, though a bit too self-conscious, and
therefore not believable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bob The Butler (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bob-the-butler-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bob-the-butler-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a recycled story of a guy who appears to be a loser, but happens
to be quite useful when put in some specific situation. I appreciate it
because, regardless of being formulaic and shallow, it feels fresh --
it has unusual, laid-back direction, and quality comic performances from
the lead and, most especially, the master butler. It screws up with
it&#x27;s needless use of slapstick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Ides of March (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-ides-of-march-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-ides-of-march-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected a far more hard-hitting story, considering this is a modern
and high-end political drama. What I got was not interesting enough to
deserve going straight to cinema. It feels unfinished. Any random
episode of &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is superior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gal is very wantable though, and the wife of the presidential
candidate (played by George Clooney) gives a decent performance, but is
denied screen appearance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It&#x27;s a Wonderful Life (1946)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/it-s-a-wonderful-life-1946/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/it-s-a-wonderful-life-1946/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s sprinkled with some fun moments and interesting performances, but
I cannot forgive some of its shallow writing, especially the fantasy
moments near the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s one especially gorgeous woman (the wife), and one especially
desirable one (the seductive near-lover). The lead has his moments,
though his character&#x27;s self-importance is often annoying, though it was
probably interesting to audiences of the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite performace is by the lady playing Miss &amp;quot;Could I have
1750?&amp;quot; Davis, though it&#x27;s a very small role, lasting just a few
seconds. That performance also feels out of place in the movie of this
age... it feels a lot more modern.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;ebb.org&#x2F;bkuhn&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2008&#x2F;12&#x2F;24&#x2F;capra-free-software.html&quot;&gt;A review that inspired me to watch this movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Addams Family (1991)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-addams-family-1991/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-addams-family-1991/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is showing its age (camerawork, direction, visual effects), but still
got its charms. Check for example the husband and wife team who head the
family in question, even though the female side appears underused.
Christina Ricci is also wonderful as the daughter, and I also liked the
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lurch_(The_Addams_Family)&quot;&gt;Frankenstein-like family butler&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. These are the only interesting
characters, and all others are either uninteresting, badly-developed,
annoying, or practically non-existent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is otherwise quite shallow and very passive, even for a
comedy. It&#x27;s not even funny, especially the first half of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Source Code (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/source-code-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/source-code-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though engaging, it&#x27;s not very exciting, but the leading guy, Jake
Gyllenhaal, gives a real nice performance. Check especially the moment
when he&#x27;s told an uncomfortable fact. The villain is amazing too, and a
very unusual choice. The guy running the Source Code program is given an
embarassing and unconvincing performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Appleseed Ex Machina (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-ex-machina-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-ex-machina-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead character from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-2004&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; takes a backseat somewhat,
making way for the cyborg friend and former lover, and to a lesser
extent, the lover&#x27;s clone, as well as to multiple other key characters.
It&#x27;s an interesting concept actually, and I haven&#x27;t seen it explored
before: that the clone looks and acts so much like the former lover
presents a challenge, and the conflict is apparent, but not overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director, who also directed the first movie, has worsened his
obsession with beautiful people. There&#x27;s a lot more of them here,
although I did really like a senior representative of some weapons
manufacturing company named Poseidon. She&#x27;s presented with greater
admiration than the lead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action does not offer any real improvement over the previous movie,
even though the budget is 3 times as large. It&#x27;s also not as
interesting. The animation is of more consistent quality than the first
movie, but there&#x27;s nothing really groundbreaking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Why the fuck did they have to drastically change the
physical look of Athena (basically the president of the city) so much?
She&#x27;s not even recognizable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Arthur (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/arthur-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/arthur-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A large part of this romantic comedy is quite enjoyable, and helped much
by the delightful and rather fresh performance by the lead, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Russell_Brand&quot;&gt;Russell
Brand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He also gave me &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;2011-movie-review&quot;&gt;one of 2011&#x27;s best performances&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;get-him-to-the-greek-2010&quot;&gt;Get Him to
the Greek&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), so it was great watching him offering similar acting style.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest happens to be &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-unbearable-hollywood-romantic-comedy-formula&quot;&gt;the formula that too many Hollywood romantic
comedies tend to adopt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it&#x27;s so fucking annoying. Nick Nolte&#x27;s
character was neither interesting nor portrayed well. In fact, he&#x27;s
embarassing. The lead girl is fucking desirable, but her character was
made annoyingly uptight, since it had to fit in with that formula I
mentioned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Horrible Bosses (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/horrible-bosses-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/horrible-bosses-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of hilarious moments, though none is as great as
the pregnancy one; Jamie Foxx does a nice bit performance; the character
of Kevin Spacey is rather overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is fun, but it sadly has a sketchy, amateurish feel of &lt;em&gt;The
40-Year-Old Virgin&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Office Space&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, both of which were also fun. It
just feels like a collection of antics, instead of one solid whole
worthy of being called a movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gladiator (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gladiator-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gladiator-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This time around, I enjoyed this over-rated movie more than previously,
where I noted thusly:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretentious and uninspiring; lacks the epic punch you&#x27;d get from a
Ben-Hur, despite being armed with more modern visuals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is still the case of course: there&#x27;s just nothing new. Luckily it
doesn&#x27;t bore and has some edge-of-the-seat moments. But there&#x27;s also a
bad performance from Djimon Hounsou, and none of the rest are actually
impressive&#x2F;convincing. There is also a lame attempt to eclipse a
&lt;em&gt;Braveheart&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, which must have provided some inspiration, beyond &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Gladiator_(2000_film)#Influences&quot;&gt;the
ones mentioned on the movie&#x27;s Wikipedia page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opening scene, which is meant to build suspense for the impending
battle, as well as show the kind of respect given the lead character, is
very well-made. The movie&#x27;s second-best moment is the quick turn of
events following the king&#x27;s death. It&#x27;s a very interesting portrayal
of how fast a respected person can fall, given a powerful-enough
opponent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oscars are embarassing to have honored the movie with Best Picture
Oscar. They deserve to be ignored, for there surely must have been
numerous superior movies that year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Battleship (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/battleship-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/battleship-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Real nice visual effects, some of the best I&#x27;ve seen yet:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the wheel-of-destruction and the destruction it wields make for some
of the most impressive character designs ever; the design isn&#x27;t so
fresh... it&#x27;s inspired by some similar machinery in one of the
&lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&#x27;s not groundbreaking, but the facial rendering of the aliens is
amazing; it&#x27;s not at the level of a Davey Jones or a Kong though&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie isn&#x27;t as big and loud as the &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie series, but
the concept is a lot less silly, and the story a lot less annoying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most surprising thing about the movie is the appearance of the
leg-less guy, some ugly big guy who gives a wonderful performance, the
most interesting in the movie. It&#x27;s surprising because I&#x27;ve never seen
the guy before, and that a crippled character would be given such a key
role. Sure there was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-1964&quot;&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but that was a comedy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was sad when the movie ended, both because it was too short, and
because there was no explanation on what the aliens wanted. What made
this even sadder is fact that they appeared not wholly evil, making them
more interesting. I even thought that, later in the movie, there would
be something like &lt;em&gt;stop fighting us; we come in peace&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Remember Me (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/remember-me-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/remember-me-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts in a very promising way, with a well-directed
robbery-and-murder scene, complete with great camerawork, pacing, and
acting. Sadly, the movie soon turns into some soppy, uninteresting
romance, with two uninteresting lovers, whose characters appear to
desperately feel interesting. Luckily we get good performances from
Chris Cooper (as always) and Pierce Brosnan, both playing the respective
fathers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire exercise feels pointless though, and the Sep 11 reference
needless. What the fuck is up with that?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Goodfellas (1990)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/goodfellas-1990/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/goodfellas-1990/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Heavily-overrated with not a single performance worthy of high praise.
Fairly-enjoyable, but my great lack of interest in the mafia doesn&#x27;t
help. It&#x27;s not hard-hitting enough (think &lt;em&gt;American Gangster&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, which
itself however has the advantage of being younger), and the direction
not satisfactory, which is very strange considering it&#x27;s done by Martin
Scorcese, the same guy who brought us both &lt;em&gt;Taxi Driver&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Raging
Bull&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>As Good As It Gets (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/as-good-as-it-gets-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/as-good-as-it-gets-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s touching moments:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the mother expressing her greatfulness&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the two great compliments the mother gets&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s funny moments:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the emitted sound when answering the phone&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of unusual behavior the author portrays&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie also boasts some unusual dialog, and an unusual (and
irritating) character played by Cuba Gooding, jnr.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that this was made by David Fincher, you know, the same guy who
made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fight-club-1999&quot;&gt;Fight Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;se7en-1995&quot;&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it was way too underwhelming, too
average. The story, the acting, the direction, none outstanding. I get
the vibe that the work the movie is based on is quite famous, so maybe
this movie doesn&#x27;t do it justice. This is easily Fincher&#x27;s least
interesting, perhaps with the exclusion of his first, &lt;em&gt;Alien 3&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I nearly forgot that the opening credits sequence was quite good.
That and the fact that I could not actually figure what was going on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>After the Rain (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/after-the-rain-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/after-the-rain-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the duels, especially the bloody one (the only such in the
movie). I enjoyed the music, singing, and rejoicing of the poor people
in the inn even more. The greatest moment in the movie, one thing that
brought tear to eye, is the act of kindness that the lead character
showed toward the unruly and disliked prostitute.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wife of the lead is a badly-developed character. The attempt to make
her angelic is nearly ludicrous, and the performer isn&#x27;t skilled enough
to help achieve the goal. Another bad character, though to a lesser
extent, is the political leader. His portrayal is too fierce to
convince.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the movie is rather empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Island (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-island-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-island-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There was some serious weaknesses with the plot (e.g. the clone of
Michael Clark Duncan was also a body builder, the two kids managed to
outsmart highly trained adults, why the clones had to be conscious was
merely brushed over). The action is too loud and frantic, as if the
makers were concerned that the excitement wasn&#x27;t enough. There&#x27;s also
way too much of it. The evilness of the guards wasn&#x27;t believable.
There&#x27;s also the very annoying thing of the lead villain turning action
guy near the end. So fucking silly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this shit is more annoying because of my love for the freshness of
the material. Among the responsible is the 2 lead characters, played by
Ewan McGregor and the beloved Scarlett Johansson. More freshness comes
from each of the other clones. It&#x27;s fun seeing seemingly-grown people
be themselves (i.e. kids). Not so fresh, but Steve Buscemi provides some
nice humor. The brutality he later on faces is sadly left unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Training Day (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/training-day-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/training-day-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a fairly interesting story of a rookie cop being driven around by
an experienced one, but it appears more a Denzel Washington &amp;quot;my acting
skillz rock&amp;quot; show than anything else. There is a visible attempt at
building something really good and exciting, but it&#x27;s somehow just
lacking. It&#x27;s intetesting enough to watch it to the end without it
feeling unbearable, but it just feels like it drags, telling a story
whose purpose appears non-existent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should also have chosen a more interesting actor than Ethan Hawke.
I enjoyed Macy Gray&#x27;s bit performance even though it was overdone. Dr.
Dre should have been excluded or taken more acting lessons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Company Men (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-company-men-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-company-men-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Smooth, laid-back direction, with nice sets; It&#x27;s a small peak at the
effects of a troubled company on the employees who lose their jobs;
it&#x27;s well-made, except that it gets tired within an hour, and there
isn&#x27;t much left for the rest of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>White Men Can&#x27;t Jump (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/white-men-can-t-jump-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/white-men-can-t-jump-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s about basketball, romantic relationships, and money, and it&#x27;s not
ambitious about it. It&#x27;s got some interesting performances here and
there, the best of which take place in the court. But it also got some
substandard ones, especially the lovers of the lead characters
especially. The direction is a little weird, and it appears the actors a
lot of freedom, and some scenes feel over-extended. Check especially an
early one, where the two leads meet for the first time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lorenzo&#x27;s Oil (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lorenzo-s-oil-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lorenzo-s-oil-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Offers some insight in medical science processes, but there is at least
one concept that was dumbed down too much (Why volume of specific
compound rises when intake of food containing it is reduced?). I&#x27;m sure
it was for the lay audience, but I don&#x27;t think the audience is that
stupid. Nick Nolte is annoying and unconvincing with the Italian accent
while Susan Sarandon&#x27;s character is annoying with her obsession and
selfishness. Their perseverance is admirable though, as well as their
efforts to help discover the treatment for the disease their son suffers
from.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balanced view of the scientific community vs. the parents is handled
quite well, and isn&#x27;t as simplified as you&#x27;d come to expect in movies.
The scientists and those who respect them aren&#x27;t viewed with
incompetence (let&#x27;s ignore the dumbed-down part) or laziness, only with
the eye that they do have other priorities which are not necessarily
less urgent&#x2F;important than the one faced by the parents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mississippi Burning (1988)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mississippi-burning-1988/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mississippi-burning-1988/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A mildly entertaining drama about some FBI guys investigating some
race-related violent crimes, which gets tiring about halfway through.
None of the characters are really interesting, nor is the acting, except
that Frances McDormand is a bit lovely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shoot &#x27;Em Up (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shoot-em-up-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shoot-em-up-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The main villain is annoying to watch and the gorgeous love prostitute
uninteresting. The lead character is interesting enough, and so is the
action. Some of the humor, none of which is actually funny, is taken a
bit too far (one guy kills another with a carrot).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the camerawork but not the negative view the writers have on the
customers of sex workers. It&#x27;s too shallow, just like the movie, though
luckily it doesn&#x27;t pretend not to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Real Steel (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/real-steel-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/real-steel-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The kid actor playing the lead&#x27;s son, Dakota Goyo, gives a real good
performance and his character is really interesting and unpredictable,
just the like the movie. The lady playing the lead&#x27;s love interest is
quite good too. The movie is strange, directed in an unusual manner,
such that I didn&#x27;t enjoy much of it, especially the first half. It
started being a little fun when I started seeing some action on stage,
but there wasn&#x27;t even enough of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asshole levels of the lead character (played by Hugh Jackman in a
surprisingly decent performance) are hard to bear, when he is being an
ass. The redneck is given a memorable performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Colombiana (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/colombiana-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/colombiana-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For almost it&#x27;s entire running length, it&#x27;s very fast-paced, a fact
that helps hide its incompetence, considering that there&#x27;s nothing new
or fresh, other than having the first young girl action hero I&#x27;ve seen
yet. Hers portrayal is not convincing, even when grown up. However,
there&#x27;s a good performance by the guy playing the lead FBI agent
(&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lennie_James&quot;&gt;Lennie James&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), who recently impressed me in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-next-three-days-2010&quot;&gt;The Next Three Days&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
The subplot involving the love interest was a waste of time, although it
was well-made, as is the movie in general.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Green Hornet (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-green-hornet-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-green-hornet-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of the movie is better than the latter, with the humorous
antics of the title character, and the excellence of his sidekick, not
least of which is the coffee-making. The lead villain is also fun to
watch, especially with his the constant (and humorous) concern of the
fearsomeness of his image&#x2F;presence. The split-screen moment, where
various bounty hunters are sent for the title character, is amazing, and
among the most innovative visuals I&#x27;ve seen in movies yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the movie gets a little annoying when this title character stops
being funny (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;unforgiving-characters-are-annoying&quot;&gt;and ungrateful&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), starting with the moment he shoots the
sidekick. There is also unexplained physical prowess, the sort that
makes the movie feel like passive entertainment, and the destruction
that happens in the movie&#x27;s final action sequence is way too much. Why
the noise?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brewster&#x27;s Millions (1985)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brewster-s-millions-1985/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brewster-s-millions-1985/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very delightful and shallow comedy about a guy who is to spend
millions within a month for an even bigger reward. Richard Pryor, the
lead, is fun to watch and so is the story, especially early on. The best
act in the movie is the lead&#x27;s political campaign. I can vaguely
remember it, so I consider among the funniest movies I&#x27;ve watched this
year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] Richard Pryor style of comedy makes Chris Rock look
like a sorry imitator.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In the Company of Men (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-the-company-of-men-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-the-company-of-men-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather captivating with unusual dialogue, making it feel realistic, and
with a really good performance by Aaron Eckhart as the biggest asshole
of them all. It&#x27;s also a real bleak look at the modern workplace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Atonement (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/atonement-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/atonement-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Superb performances by all 3 people playing the writer girl, my favorite
being the youngest, which happens to be among the best child
performances I&#x27;ve ever seen. One other nice performance is the young
girl who eventually gets raped. I like the rather lame use of
type-writer sounds during certain sequences; I also like the expansive
sets showing bombed (World War II) areas as well as the military camp
(that wasn&#x27;t cheap). Otherwise the main story (a man gets
falsely-accused of rape) is boring and often full of sentimentality, and
I enjoyed none of the other performances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pirates of the Caribbean - On Stranger Tides (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far less spectacular and less annoying (there&#x27;s no Keira Knighley or
Orlando Bloom) than the earlier movies, it does have nice humor,
gorgeous mermaids (wonderfully portrayed), and a totally enjoyable
performance by the fat guy who has Jack Sparrow brought in for
questioning, if we exclude the silly moment... the two-thumbs-up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sexy Beast (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sexy-beast-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sexy-beast-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good performances throughout and some of the best visualisations of fear
I&#x27;ve seen yet. Ben Kingsley is an amazingly adaptive actor, and his is
most likely the worst asshole I&#x27;ve seen in any movie... worse than Al
Pacino&#x27;s in &lt;em&gt;Scarface&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Where the Wild Things Are (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/where-the-wild-things-are-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/where-the-wild-things-are-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre movie with creatures, designed to look like dolls, done in bad
taste. Those creatures are however as realistic as it gets, and the
story tends to be spooky in places (e.g. one of them asks the
near-victim if he&#x27;d be good dinner). Catherine Keener, who plays the
mother of the lead character, is as impressive as always.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Castle (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-castle-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-castle-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An awkward but witty comedy about a simple (and dumb) family on the
verge of being forcibly removed from their home due to an airport
extension. The movie&#x27;s best performance, though brief, was that of the
lawyer who took over the case. It was fun to watch his perplexed
reactions to the dumbness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Life, Above All (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/life-above-all-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/life-above-all-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is much authenticity and freshness in the treament of poor South
African township experience, but there is also a lack of those since the
behaviour of some of the people is such that I&#x27;ve never witnessed (or
heard of, given the demographics of the setting) as a citizen of that
country... it&#x27;s little too westernized, and annoyingly so too. Also,
the language was a little too pure to be believable for anyone familiar
with it. The story is mildly interesting and acting decent, my favorite
being the prostitute teenager.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is more important than it&#x27;s good, because it effectively
showcases the negative effects of denial and idiocy: &amp;quot;It&#x27;s not HIV,
I&#x27;m just not feeling okay; maybe it&#x27;s witchcraft; Friend, find me a
good traditional doctor; In the meanwhile, I&#x27;ll try these herbal
thingies&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mulholland Drive (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mulholland-drive-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mulholland-drive-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A deliberately weird movie which is somewhat enjoyable, with some good
humor, some of which is rather silly, perhaps for the sake of being
bizarre. It&#x27;s nature also makes it hard to rate... I can&#x27;t call it
bad because there&#x27;s good direction (I was a bit captivated).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Clash of the Titans (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/clash-of-the-titans-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/clash-of-the-titans-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I like a few of the characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medusa: gorgeous, yet scary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kraken: among the largest of all movie monsters I&#x27;ve seen,
complete with superb facial design&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underworld creature that drives the boat, together with the two
others pulling the ship&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades: the entrance +++ when spreading his &#x27;wings&#x27; +++ is
entrancing and the performance (Ralph Fiennes) and body movement
befitting; this the movie&#x27;s best moment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some badly-designed ones:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scorpions aren&#x27;t convincing, nor are the battles involving them&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The charred-skin wizards have some presence, but what the fuck is up
with look&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The former king who got burned by Zeus&#x27; lightning got make-up that
looks like something from a B-movie; that character is not
interesting too&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the story, it is merely standard. Nothing to celebrate there.
Strangely, I enjoyed the movie more on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>One Day (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/one-day-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/one-day-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;What&#x27;s up with people making depressing movies? This one is pretty
well-made, but it drags on and on with a boring love story. One thing of
value it portrays is that life tends to turn out different (and worse)
to what we hope&#x2F;expect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shrek Forever After (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shrek-forever-after-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shrek-forever-after-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one, given that I find the series rather
overrated, bar the 2nd movie. But this one is quite an experience, and
far superior to any of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the kid that insists on Shrek screaming&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donkey was actually interesting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the warrior Fiona was great to watch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the villain was fun to watch, and his mannerisms reminds of that of
the title character of &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is a lotta fun&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Ogres species was fun to watch, and it was interesting to note
that he looked like nothing compared to some of them; character
design is amazing; check especially the cook&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great humor: the villain serving the witches; the cook proposing
serving food during battle; the meet between fat cat and donkey&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the early scenes in which Shrek harks back to the early,
freedom-filled, days&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movie revisits can be real strange. The first time I watched this one, I
deemed it a masterpiece, but a revisit proved it not much better than
the others in the &lt;em&gt;Shrek&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; franchise. It makes me wonder... maybe my
mood was different. It&#x27;s not as bad as the worst in the series (&lt;em&gt;Shrek
3&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but it doesn&#x27;t seem as good as the 2nd (&lt;em&gt;Shrek 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, it&#x27;s a little disappointing (the human faces are really
bad, not much better than the original &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (1995). None of the
visuals are any impressive either, well other than Donkey&#x27;s fur, which
sometimes look photo-realistic. Luckily the new ogres are interesting,
far more interesting than Shrek himself, my most favorite being the
cook. And of the previous elements I watched, Fiona was no longer
interesting, and villain not as much fun nor is the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Warrior&#x27;s Way (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-warrior-s-way-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-warrior-s-way-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is extreme brutality and violence, in this super-exciting fusion
of guns and swords. It&#x27;s rare to successfully mix Oriental and Western
fantasy. I don&#x27;t remember live-action fantasy martial arts so
impressively-executed (the ones that come close are &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;kung-fu-hustle-2004&quot;&gt;Kung Fu Hustle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;House Of Flying Daggers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). The costume design is amazing, for both West
and East. The final battle is exhilarating. Shit, I wish I had words to
describe it. Did you check the ninjas? The sound?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie&#x27;s best performance was the head of the ninjas, while Geoffrey
Rush&#x27;s was just business as usual (nothing challenging for him here,
nor was it required). The gal is okay, and not as annoying as she could
have been.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minor complaints I have is the unimpressive cowboy villain, and the
not-lethal-enough look of the lead (where&#x27;s Jet Li when you need him?).
I would also have preffered a less polished feel of the camerawork (it
feels too sanitised, too fantasy-like).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was again wondering if there was something wrong with considering
the generally negative critical reception of the movie. Maybe they
are the ones who have problems. Were we watching the same movie?
Perhaps I will understand on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.screendaily.com&#x2F;reviews&#x2F;the-warriors-way&#x2F;5021277.article&quot;&gt;a quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that does a good job of justifying its
negative conclusion.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am worried that this is another &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;Case of The Matrix Reloaded&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is indeed another &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;Case of The Matrix Reloaded&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It is far less
impressive than on first viewing, but I still love the fantasy-like
fight sequences of the ninjas, but most especially, their
characterisation (they look as menacing as fuck). The part of the story
where the lead character gets to meet a gal and exercise a more relaxed
life is boring and not too well done. It reminds me of a similar kinda
thing in &lt;em&gt;Fearless&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, where Jet Li&#x27;s character goes to chill in a farm.
As if that&#x27;s not enough, both the lead character and the Amercian
villain are unconvincing, while the movie&#x27;s best performance is that of
the guy playing head of the ninjas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Toy Story 3 (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/toy-story-3-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/toy-story-3-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the best &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie, and the only one I truly enjoyed.
The toys go through some elaborate adventures, ending up in some
seemingly hopeless situations, but luckily ending up surviving one way
or another. And the ending is as happy as can be. The environment, as
presented by the leader of the childcare toys, is so-gorgeous and
so-enchanting. The baby villain is quite scary, and the main villain is
unforgivably evil. My favorite characters are Rexx (the sweet dinosaur)
and the female cowboy (with her retarded voice). The clown, who makes a
first appearance here, is the best-designed character in the whole
series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A revisit was by far less enjoyable, but some moments remain
interesting (the Spanish mode), some charming ones (check the college
age toy owner with the toddler) and some great visuals (check the trash
sequence).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The First Grader (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-first-grader-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-first-grader-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Touching drama about the oldest person (84) to start formal primary
school education. Well, it so happens that he met opposition (there&#x27;s
isn&#x27;t a shortage of idiots in the world). The guy playing him gives a
very good performance, and just as impressive are the schoolmates,
especially the kid with an artificial leg. She also happens to provide
the movie&#x27;s most tear-jerking moment, where she mentions a future
career of choice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes these kids all the more impressive is that they were taken
from just two primary schools, which makes me assume they were
untrained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is paced a little too slow, although the horrendous past of
the old man is thrown in to help hold interest. Those flashbacks are too
frequent, unfortunately. Keeping the movie shorter would have been a
better solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mindhunters (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mindhunters-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mindhunters-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A bit disturbing with a gripping storyline. LL Cool J is an interesting
actor and so is the guy (in an interesting twist) who turns out to be
the villain. The setting (a simualtion of a small town, complete with
dolls&#x2F;statues for humans) is quite spooky, but the whole thing isn&#x27;t
satisfactorily justified, and the villain is too capable to convince (he
got too many things right in a very short period of time).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Secret of Kells (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-secret-of-kells-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-secret-of-kells-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s bizarre in a way similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-triplets-of-belleville-2003&quot;&gt;The Triplets of Belleville&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and has
some emotionally powerful moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the attack scene was quite painful; it&#x27;s some of sort of reminder
of the tough realities of the world&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the character development of Ashley, the forest creature that helped
the hero on a few occasions, was quite interesting; it was
especially sad when her great strength was challenged by some evil
creature of the same forest, especially when her form changed to
express the pain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the general character design&#x2F;development is quite good really; my
favorites are the strict leader of the town and the fat guy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the cat is among the most charming characters I&#x27;ve seen in movie
history&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, the movie is a little disturbing&#x2F;unsettling (okay,
that&#x27;s not a negative), and is also sleep-inducing. I also couldn&#x27;t
get what the point of it was. Maybe it&#x27;s kinda biblical, since it
centers around some all-important book (and the lead character looks
like Jesus when grown-up).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tsotsi (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tsotsi-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tsotsi-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead character has got talent (I&#x27;ve seen him on stage), but either
he&#x27;s just not good enough for this role or the director just didn&#x27;t
push hard enough. Also, I suspect that the movie would come off better
was I unfamiliar with the language used... if you ask any ordinary
black South African, it&#x27;s quite unconvincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First time I watched this, I was hoping that it would match the
excellent SA township tv series, Yizi Yizo, and it failed dismally. It
was still hard-hitting and skillfully portrays some of the poor township
realities of the country, but it turned more towards some sort of
morality play. I guess it&#x27;s a matter of taste, but it should at least
have been convincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;highlights:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the camerawork and the sets; I remember the music sounding superior
the first time I saw the movie&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the comic performance by one &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rottentomatoes.com&#x2F;celebrity&#x2F;kenneth-nkosi&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kenneth Nkosi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who plays the dumb,
yes-man gang member&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the scene regarding title characters&#x27;s childhood was quite good,
complete with excellent performances from the young boy and his
father&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice performance by Zola, who runs an operation where he strips and
re-sells stolen car parts&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cemetery Junction (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cemetery-junction-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cemetery-junction-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It got the same sort of camerawork and set design (set about the same
time?) as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-05-06&quot;&gt;*An Education*&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it also happens to be a coming-of-age
story, only a lot less serious and a lot more of a fairy-tale. The
acting is decent, but Ralph Fiennes isn&#x27;t convincing... more a
caricature than a shitty husband.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia: I don&#x27;t remember anyone mocking own father as the troubled kid
does here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Year One (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/year-one-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/year-one-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A fun and lazily-written movie set in ancient mythical times; there&#x27;s a
number of hilarious moments and fun characters, my favorite of which are
Caine (first biblical murderer) and the high priest. Sadly, the fun
isn&#x27;t very consistent (hence the work &#x27;lazy&#x27;), but it&#x27;s enough to
keep one interested. The most hilarious moments ought to be the one
involving foreskins.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dante&#x27;s Inferno: An Animated Epic (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dante-s-inferno-an-animated-epic-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dante-s-inferno-an-animated-epic-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An entertaining fantasy about some heroic warrior fighting demons in
hell in order to reach his loves. It&#x27;s moderately well-made and has
some interesting animation (check when Satan forcibly pulls that lover
towards self), but the storyline skimps through the details, and feels
shallow... it feels incomplete.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monty Python&#x27;s The Meaning Of Life (1983)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-the-meaning-of-life-1983/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-the-meaning-of-life-1983/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of excellent humor (&lt;em&gt;the machine that goes PING&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;welcome to the
middle of the movie&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;baby falling from pussy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, ...), perhaps even
funnier than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;monty-pythons-life-of-brian-1979&quot;&gt;Life of Brian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, though it was quite a surprise that it
resorted to vomit humor, and the most disgusting in memory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was also disorganised as a whole movie, though not as much as
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;monty-pythons-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975&quot;&gt;Holy Grail&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Whatever Works (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/whatever-works-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/whatever-works-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Its being very feel-good is ironic, given that its main character is as
pessimistic a guy as it gets, insulting people everywhere and getting
away with it (reminding of Gregory House from the series, &lt;em&gt;House&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).
There&#x27;s interesting acting, and I really like the part where the
characters look at the camera, perplexed at what they are supposed to
see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fresh as it feels, the movie really smacks of laziness. Woody Allen is a
talented movie maker, but he didn&#x27;t really put much effort here, or at
least it doesn&#x27;t feel like it. The movie feels like a glorified sitcom,
and it&#x27;s fantasy-like, with quirky happenings here and there, and
doesn&#x27;t feel like one solid whole. This isn&#x27;t what I want from
theatre.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Machete (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/machete-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/machete-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Goog ole-fashioned action movie, with a deliberately sgallow storyline
and two beloved leading ladies, one (Jessica Alba) of which has never
performed this well anywhere (in my experience of course). The leading
guy, an ugly motherfucker who I only ever saw doing secondary roles, if
fun to watch. He does look like a tough guy. Steven Seagal is as scary
as always, and I wonder what the fuck Robert De Niro is doing here.
Aren&#x27;t there more cerebral scripts for him out there?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Joneses (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-joneses-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-joneses-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Demi Moore is still so damn gorgeous after all these years! The movie is
a real good play on the concept of &lt;em&gt;kool neighbors&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; even though it fails
to end it well. It takes the concept a little far, meaning they fail to
make it believable, but luckily the whole thing is kept entertaining.
The subplots (cheating hubby and homosexuality) were left ununsed and
were therefore needless, as if thw writers didn&#x27;t have a filler...
lack of creativity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Semi-Pro (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/semi-pro-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/semi-pro-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very funny (favorite moment is the unloaded gun scene), and some of the
humor is very original. The movie is in the style (the goofiness) of the
other Will Ferrell vehicle, &lt;em&gt;Blade of Glory&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Andr%C3%A9_3000&quot;&gt;Andr 3000&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is
interesting to watch and, with talent like this, me wonders why he
isn&#x27;t working more regularly in movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>9 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/9-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/9-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A weird post-apocalypse movie about bizarre puppet-like creatures trying
to survive in a world where they are terrorised by some scary robot
whose goal is left untold. The action is top-class and the adventure
heavy, with many cliffhanger moments, but the central premise (mentioned
in the twist) is damn silly. Character design is pretty good (the main
villain is awesome and so are its minions) while character development
is typical.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The American President (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-american-president-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-american-president-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It feels dated and Annette Benning is so damn pretty. It was hard not to
compare the movie with &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; tv series (I saw the first two of
its seasons). The whole thing feels shallow. The &lt;em&gt;oh shit! it really is
the president&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; thing is so lame and boring. Ok, there was too much of it
in the tv series. Why do I feel like some episodes of that series were
actually better. Sure the debates and storylines of that series were
deeper and more complex, but some episodes were actually more exciting
than this movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Letters To Juliet (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/letters-to-juliet-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/letters-to-juliet-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exquisite cinematography, (excessively) loving characters, and some of
the best depictions of Italian food and romance. The lead character
looks so damn nice at the wedding. The movie is overlong (it drags) and
has some unbearable romance. I like romance, but not when it&#x27;s so
blatantly formulaic. Maybe if I was a stereotypical female, I&#x27;d melt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shadowboxer (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shadowboxer-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shadowboxer-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The main plot, that of an assassin softened by an innocent being, has
been done a number of times before. But the movie remains fresh. It&#x27;s
clear that the writer is politically liberal, bordering on provocative.
Most notable is the sexual relationship between a young black guy (Cuba
Gooding, jnr.) and an elderly white lady (the beautiful Helen Mirren),
something I don&#x27;t remember portrayed in movies before. As a sidenote,
it&#x27;s probably these two roles that got them in later movies (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-hit-list-2011&quot;&gt;The Hit
List&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;red-2010&quot;&gt;Red&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, respectively).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie pretty much weird, with the sort of direction I haven&#x27;t seen
before. It didn&#x27;t see much distribution, and I only watched it because
I deeply enjoyed the director&#x27;s later work, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;Precious&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Illusionist (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-illusionist-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-illusionist-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts impressively well (the backstage, complete with the bony lady)
but soon devolves into a drag that doesn&#x27;t really go anywhere. The
direction is good, and the lead character superbly-developed. It&#x27;s just
not a match for the director&#x27;s earlier masterful &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-triplets-of-belleville-2003&quot;&gt;Triplets of
Belleville&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rango (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rango-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rango-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the top-of-the-range quality of the animation and character
design, this is a largely unnteresting adventure story of an
annoyingly-deceptive reptile in thirsty Wild West town. Lucily there&#x27;s
some colorful characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the freedom-fighter gal with her heavy America South accent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the old and wise guy who got run over by a car, with his heavy
Mexican accent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the snake, whose creation must have been the single most complex
character in the whole movie, and perhaps among the most complex
digital characters ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s great voice talent, but the story, not so much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hit List (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hit-list-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hit-list-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s got some good elements, and the lead actor, Cole Hauser, is really
great on screen. The direction of the opening scenes (following the
stressed-out hero, nd his meeting with the killer) is pretty good. The
violence near the end is quite weird, and mentioning it would be a
spoiler.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have appreciated a better budget and superior camerawork. Cuba
Gooding jnr. is badly cast as the killer (he&#x27;s damn unconvincing). The
story is thing and shallow, and the cheating thing painted in a lighter
way was just unneeded, as if fucking is a greater cheating crime than
kissing. Really?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Headless Woman (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-headless-woman-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-headless-woman-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to watch this one a few times in pieces because it was too boring
to bear. It&#x27;s a sleep-inducing exercise, following an extremely
uninteresting semi-retarded lady who is suffering from an untold
incident, as well as the guilt of (potentially) hitting a human with her
car. We are led to keep hoping that something will actually happen, but
nothing does. Luckily the acting is good and so is direction and
camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] There is one critic who &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;08&#x2F;19&#x2F;movies&#x2F;19headless.html&quot;&gt;found it great&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, inspiring me
to give it a second look. It&#x27;s a better and deeper review than mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Grit (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality dialog throughout and decent acting. Some big names are
involved, but it&#x27;s interesting that they stayed away from expensive
gloss, and instead focused on the simple story of &lt;em&gt;we gotta find this
killer&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] One critic &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.observer.com&#x2F;2010&#x2F;culture&#x2F;year-end-roundup-what-see-and-skip-ball-drops?page=1&quot;&gt;complained&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;True_Grit_(2010_film)&quot;&gt;via&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) about Jeff Bridge&#x27;s
self-indulgent performance, and I totally agree. The guy is a fine
actor, but he really was getting too comfortable. I would not go as far
as saying the performance was any bad at all, as the critic claims. It
seems he disliked it so much that he decided to go all irrational on us.
It was probably just a lashback against the overwhelming (undeserving)
acclaim the movie got.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>WZ (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wdz-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wdz-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching the first half of the movie, I saw a &lt;em&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (urban decay and
the brutal violence on some of its citizens; the tough cops
investigating; oh, and the glorious ending). Yeah, it was quite intense,
with a different touch of a lower budget and less glitzy style, but very
effective. This was helped by an amazing cast, all well until the guy
playing the informant shows his shortcomings near the end. Wonderful
setup and script, until an unsatisfying (and unjustified) ending. The
horrid deeds are unjustified too, and the movie doesn&#x27;t offer the
intense emotional impact when the credits roll. You see, movie endings
are extremely important, because if they are shitty, they really mess
the glory that may have already been presented. I didn&#x27;t care much for
the resonation with &lt;em&gt;Saw&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies, for the story didn&#x27;t need it. This is
a movie that should have risen above that level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Orphan (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/orphan-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/orphan-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazing camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vera Farmica is immensely beloved (as usual).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her two kids are amazing, especially the daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The title character is quite good too, a superb child performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;C._C._H._Pounder&quot;&gt;CCH Pounder&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the lead nun; haven&#x27;t seen her in quite a while,
so this is sort of a nice comeback&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As often happens, especially with mystery-thrillers, the allure
doesn&#x27;t last beyond the setup. It&#x27;s tiring and repetitive, and the
motives of the villain are unconvincing. The running length should
also have been reduced.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Messages Deleted (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/messages-deleted-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/messages-deleted-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed all the performances, and this was helped by me being a fan of
Deborah Kara Unger (always a pleasure this god-damn desirable gal,
though she&#x27;s aging). The lead was nice as well, and his gal gorgeous
beyond words. The story is quite thin, and feels incomplete, but it&#x27;s
real weird that the movie didn&#x27;t get much attention at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>All About My Mother (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/all-about-my-mother-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/all-about-my-mother-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Sure it&#x27;s a decent offering, with good acting from all the females, but
why did it leave such an impression on so many critics? It was all the
rage years back when it was released, but seeing it again, I actually
wonder. I remember appreciating it much more in the first viewing, and I
don&#x27;t remember why.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes it worthy of promotion is it&#x27;s attempt at removing
prejudice against certain people in society (transvestites and
prostitutes), for there isn&#x27;t a single important character in the movie
that finds them distasteful. The dialog is pretty good and the character
of the lead tranvestite delightful, though I&#x27;m not sure about the
quality of the performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>According to Greta (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/according-to-greta-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/according-to-greta-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s well-made and has decent acting, but offers nothing new, with the
lead&#x27;s assholeness levels unbearable, and for far too long. The
boyfriend is given a nice (though not too skilled) performance and so is
the grandpa. The diary visual effects are nice (but I&#x27;ve seen them
elsewhere before). The message the movie offers, compassion, is
delivered quite well, although it&#x27;s made in an unconvincing manner
(it&#x27;s like fantasy).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hunger (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hunger-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hunger-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you put a few people in a hole in which they can&#x27;t escape, and
provide only water for a month, what would they do? The movie covers the
concept and quite effectively at that, with the ending, the sort I
normally don&#x27;t like in horror movie, quite satisfying. Oh, they do end
up eating each other. I kept thinking I&#x27;d rather die, but maybe that&#x27;s
becaue I don&#x27;t know the pain of hunger. But screws that, I&#x27;d commit
suicide first. That seems an easier solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is very low-budget and feels like its made by students, but
the acting is quite good. It would have benefited from decent
cinematography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>She&#x27;s Out of My League (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/she-s-out-of-my-league-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/she-s-out-of-my-league-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever enjoy romantic comedies because they tend to be cheap
recycled material and this one is no different, except that it&#x27;s
actually funny in many places (highlights are the moments with the
family), and full of good comic performances, most notably the fat guy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Waterworld (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/waterworld-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/waterworld-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s without any decent dialog, but the story makes it fun to watch.
Quite a big budget, and it&#x27;s evident. All those sets. Quite impressive.
I wish there was a better cinematographer to fully exploit them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the performances are really good (excluding the guy who was paid
to protect the soon-to-be-destroyed village out hero trades with),
though I enjoyed watching the guy flying the balloon. Check his excited
curiosity when meeting the mutated hero (he can breath under water). The
villains are nothing above cartoonish. Maybe it was so that the movie
was suitable for kids (post-apocalypse isn&#x27;t exactly a light subject).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of soil being the most-valued item on the water-covered
earth (as a result of global warming) is interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Animal Kingdom (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/animal-kingdom-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/animal-kingdom-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was expecting more from this (well-made) crime drama about a boy who
moves in with a criminally violent family following mother&#x27;s death. All
performances are good though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Antichrist (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/antichrist-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/antichrist-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple is going through a period of immense pain in their life,
triggered by the death of their toddler. A lot of the imagery is horrid
and bizarre (e.g. there&#x27;s an animal walking around with a stillborn
still attached to pussy), and the movie itself is rather dreamlike, with
the director exercising high levels of freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twist near the end is quite shocking; the love the man has for the
woman (who is mentally screwed by the loss) is impressive. This woman is
given is really good performance. The dialog is quite good as well. The
title is misleading, and is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Antichrist_(film)#Development&quot;&gt;a removed concept&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that was in an
earlier script.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Despicable Me (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/despicable-me-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/despicable-me-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The were moments of good humor (e.g. when lead character was stealing
the shrinking machine), but much of the time, the whole thing is
irritating; the writers worked hard at making this child-friendly (e.g.
being hit multiple missiles results only in a sad face covered in
smoke); the excessivley-advanced gadgets are nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Rainmaker (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-rainmaker-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-rainmaker-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to find that this movie was made by the legendary
Francis Ford Coppola. It&#x27;s not quite big and famous either, perhaps due
to its lukewarm story and direction. I&#x27;m however glad that it has these
nice elements:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enjoyable performance of Danny Glover, who plays the judge in
the case. I don&#x27;t recall enjoying any other of his performances.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie&#x27;s best performance is that of Jon Voigt, who plays the
defence lawyer. None of his other performances are as good or as
enjoyable, but my memory has been proven unreliable.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I watched this only cuz I read the book (the version
condensed by Readers&#x27; Digest).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Firm (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-firm-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-firm-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An reasonably enjoyable movie that is sadly showing its age. Luckily
there&#x27;s many nice performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holly Hunter: I didn&#x27;t even notice it was here, until I saw the
credits; it&#x27;s been a while I guess; she plays the lover of the
private investigator.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Gary_Busey&quot;&gt;Gary Busey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: He&#x27;s fun to watch as private investigator. He gets
some of the movie&#x27;s best dialogue. Also, I don&#x27;t remember enjoying
any of his performances, until now.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed Harris: This is one good actor, and I only wish he was given
enough great roles, instead of playing second fiddle to shitty
actors like Tom Cruise. The scene where he breaks in anger, where he
reveals the size of his balls to the Tom Cruise character is solid.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Strathairn: The character of the hero&#x27;s brother was rather
misplaced and was given too much importantance. It was just not
needed for the story. That however shouldn&#x27;t make us ignore the
fact that it was performed well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a bunch of desirable gals too, not least of which was the great
Holly Hunter herself. Another is the wife, and another (the most
desirable) is the lady who seduced our hero on the beach in what is
easily the silliest moment in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] Now, this Gary Busy guy is one prolific muthafucka,
with over 120 movie appearances! I think most are shit though, as is
often the case with actors this active. Remember &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dennis_Hopper_filmography&quot;&gt;Dennis Hopper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Erin Brockovich (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/erin-brockovich-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/erin-brockovich-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An okay and interesting enough movie about this heroic lady (Julia
Roberts) who plays a key role in a law-suit against a major corporation.
I saw it some years back, and it&#x27;s just forgettable. I don&#x27;t like the
fact that the story about the ex-husbands was so ignored, or even the
character of the angelic boyfriend. They just didn&#x27;t care to justify
why he was so kind, or even cover a little bit of his backgrounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia Roberts&#x27; performance got a lot of praise, and although it&#x27;s far
from bad, I find it overrated. There&#x27;s nothing spectacular about it.
Maybe these people should just admit that they loved the character she
played. I did too. She is far tougher than I&#x27;ll probably ever be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Informant! (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-informant-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-informant-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not really interesting, and that&#x27;s not helped by the rather untalented
(or should I say uninteresting?) Matt Damon who plays the title
character who reveals his company&#x27;s price-fixing activities. It drags
and drags, and really paints a bad picture of this informant guy to the
point where you (I) end up hating him. The plot is overly complex, and
the director attempts to keep it light with a comic touch or two, but it
doesnt work. I seriously didn&#x27;t enjoy this, even though I have to admit
that it&#x27;s well-made (direction, sets, camerawork, script).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Black Swan (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/black-swan-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/black-swan-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Excessively depressing and disturbing (all the blood and physical harm;
the annoying personality of the lead character; her possessive mom).
Also, like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;showgirls-1995&quot;&gt;Showgirls&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;all-about-eve-1950&quot;&gt;All About Eve&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before it, it&#x27;s main theme
is of a fresh stage performer hungry to be at the top, and the harms
resulting from that obsession. At the end, Darren Aronofsky is revealed
to be the director. Not that I would have guessed it, but it wasn&#x27;t
surprising, given the director&#x27;s other movies, &lt;em&gt;Pi&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream-2000&quot;&gt;Requiem for A
Dream&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which could hardly be called easy viewing. It&#x27;s very well-made,
but I seriously didn&#x27;t enjoy it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Last Man Standing (1996)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/last-man-standing-1996/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/last-man-standing-1996/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good stuntwork, especially the very first killing, even if it defies the
laws of physics. Should be forgiven because the movie is stylised. Bruce
Willis, the lead character, is interesting to watch in the beginning,
but we quickly get tired of him, especially because the whole thing
feels pointless, with him doing the same expressions, which don&#x27;t lend
any reality to the fantasy. He should have a got a better hairdo too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zombies of Mass Destruction (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zombies-of-mass-destruction-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zombies-of-mass-destruction-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie is very well-done and has very interesting characters,
most notably the ever-smiling candidate for mayor position.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freshness of the direction and cinematography reminds me of the
superior &lt;em&gt;Call Back&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, the best horror I saw for the first time
in 2009.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It covers issues of homosexuality and xenophobia very well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The treatment of the zombie side of things is really shitty. Perhaps
it&#x27;s a lack of a budget, but it&#x27;s done so bad, with bad make-up,
and shitty horror movie happenings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Music is the Weapon (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/music-is-the-weapon-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/music-is-the-weapon-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have deep respect for Fela Kuti&#x27;s musicianship, and more than any
other musician I&#x27;ve ever listened to. His intense love for the craft,
though I suspect that it may at times been detrimental to those
surrounding him, is hard to beat. His political views seemed relevant
too, as he mentions Nigerian government&#x27;s oppressive acts, one of which
resulted in the death of his mother. How he was going to help correct
these injustices is another thing altogether&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fela Kuti was an eccentric character, at least as portrayed. He had the
fearless attitude of an traditional activist, which is a quality I
admire (and lack). He also promoted and practiced traditional African
religion (while opposing Christianity and Islam), and polygamy, which is
okay in itself, until the fact that the women themselves would not be
allowed to have other partners. Maybe Fela didn&#x27;t mind it (he din&#x27;t
mention it), but I doubt it. That&#x27;s some double standards which I
really hate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary itself is pretty decent, but lacks the depth I was
hoping for. I guess I&#x27;m more interested in the musical Fela Kuti than
the politics, even though one heavily influenced the other, making it
hard to separrate the two. But check out &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.com&#x2F;review&#x2F;R28YF6P9MDOEPS&#x2F;ref=cm_cr_dp_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B000079DF9&amp;amp;nodeID=130&amp;amp;tag=&amp;amp;linkCode=&quot;&gt;this quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which is
far better and more detailed than I can muster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tron: Legacy (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tron-legacy-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tron-legacy-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre sci-fi taking place mostly in a computer system, about an
exciting wish for one computer program to escape into the real world.
There&#x27;s interesting artefacts, like a small rod that transforms into a
vehicle at will, while the simulation of Jeff Bridge&#x27;s face is
disappointing, especiallly considering the great work done to Brad
Pitt&#x27;s face in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;finchers-most-pointless-yet&quot;&gt;The Curious Case of Benjamin Button&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was
released in 2008. The imagery is very (too) stylish. None of the
performances are worthy of praise (did they have to cast Olivia
Wilde!?).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Stepfather (1987)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-1987/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-1987/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-stepfather-2009&quot;&gt;its remake&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An extra-gorgeous&#x2F;desirable daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better lead performance, though not quite award-worthy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good stunt work (the speeding car; the fall down the stairs).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suffers from lack of explanation for the villain&#x27;s deeds, as was
its remake..&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not fun enough... sleep-inducing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Legend of 1900 (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-legend-of-1900-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-legend-of-1900-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much enjoyable, with good dialogue, and a fun performance from
1900&#x27;s stepfather, and a lovely love interest, but what an oddball kind
of story? It&#x27;s like some sort of fantasy, and has a weird and
unconvincing competitor, and it&#x27;s as if the faster you can play piano,
the superior you are considered to be. It&#x27;s a pointless story, and I
don&#x27;t know why anyone who write it. Such a strange thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nanny McPhee And The Big Bang (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I just found out that this is a sequel. It&#x27;s a feel-good fantasy, made
for kids, with some decent moral lessons. Well, there&#x27;s also some shit
about &amp;quot;it&#x27;s okay to determine reality with your bones&amp;quot; bullshit. Not
good. Emma Thompson is always great to watch, even when under heavy
make-up. The encounter between the two boys and the father who is a
senior in the military was quite powerful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had it not been for the misleading title (I thought it had something
to do with the &#x27;beginning&#x27; of the universe), I would not have
bothered.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hate &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;nanny-mcphee-2005&quot;&gt;the original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tango &amp; Cash (1989)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tango-cash-1989/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tango-cash-1989/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A faity-tale of a story with plenty of holes, but is a whole lot of fun.
I hardly ever enjoy Kurt Russel&#x27;s performances, but this one was far
more bearable. Stallone has always been charismatic on screen, and the
gal playing her sister is ultra-gorgeous (though very unconvincing).
Some of the bad guys are mere comic relief (check the guy with massive
jaws; check they guy with a pony-tail, the one who looks constipated).
Good ole cheap action-comedy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Ministers (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-ministers-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-ministers-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An especially shocking first scene got me excited, and whatever happened
afterwards didn&#x27;t justify it&#x27;s magnificence. It has some really good
direction (very dark with high suspense; wonderful romance), acting, and
dialogue, but the ending is shiite. There was a need for a bigger
budget, as evidenced by the less-than-adequate production design. There
was also a need for a better plot; the story about the burning building
is just not enough, and the great jealousy of scarface is just juvenile.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nacho Libre (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nacho-libre-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nacho-libre-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is some oddball comedy, with highly-skilled direction, comic
acting, production design and camerawork. It has nice parodies of common
movie elements, but it gets tiring once it&#x27;s clear that the writers
don&#x27;t have any story tell actually; it&#x27;s fun initially, but it
doesn&#x27;t go anywhere as it &#x27;progresses&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Black Book (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/black-book-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/black-book-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Although there&#x27;s some interesting-enough stuff going on, helped much by
a quality performance by an immeasurably gorgeous leading lady, it just
feels like... there isn&#x27;t anything remarkable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Rosenbaum has an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jonathanrosenbaum.com&#x2F;?p=5780&quot;&gt;interesting comparison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;schindlers-list-1993&quot;&gt;Schindler&#x27;s
List&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, citing &lt;em&gt;Black Book&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to be morally more complex, and therefore
less escapist.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mention of the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mata-hari-1931&quot;&gt;Mata Hari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; inspired me to watch it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Invincible Iron Man (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-invincible-iron-man-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-invincible-iron-man-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was strange watching this one, for the story is so different from the
two live-action movies (father is still alive; some sprinkling of
supernatural stuff; Pepper is much older, Tony Stark is boring, ....).
It was a fun watch too, other than that the story is pretty much
shallow, and offers nothing fresh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dorian Gray (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dorian-gray-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dorian-gray-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a movie adaption of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Picture_of_Dorian_Gray&quot;&gt;novel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that had a rather interesting
concept: a painting is made of a pretty man, and instead of him getting
injured or aging, it&#x27;s the image of the painting that does. It&#x27;s fun
watching the title character&#x27;s deeds, though he sometimes does it at
the expense of the innocent. The negative influence his &#x27;mentor&#x27; has
on him is annoying, and worse still, the &#x27;mentor&#x27; complains when his
fuckin&#x27; daughter falls for Dorian - hypocrisy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paranormal Activity 2 (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paranormal-activity-2-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paranormal-activity-2-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Mother and daughter are sooo pretty; quality performances and dialogue;
very realistic direction; It just takes a bit of patience though, and I
wish the mystery was explained at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shinobi: Heart Under Blade (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shinobi-heart-under-blade-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shinobi-heart-under-blade-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Oriental fantasy is my kinda movie genre. The characters in this one are
as colorful as a peace-loving man effortlessly killing over a dozen
ninjas, or a super-sweet doll who happens to be among the top warriors
in the village. The story is rather silly, where self-sacrifice is the
order of the day. It&#x27;s edgy at the same time, but is too poetic for my
liking (think &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) and there&#x27;s
isn&#x27;t enough of great martial arts choreography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Seventh Seal (1957)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-seventh-seal-1957/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-seventh-seal-1957/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know if we were to take this as comic farce or serious fantasy
drama, but it turned out too eccentric and unfocused. Luckily it got
great cinematography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could not help but notice the physical resemblance between Max von
Sydow (lead character) and Hugh Laurie of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;House_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) fame.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bill &amp; Ted&#x27;s Bogus Journey (1991)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bill-ted-s-bogus-journey-1991/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bill-ted-s-bogus-journey-1991/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected this sequel to be junk, but was pleasantly surprised to find
it was about as exciting as the first, and perhaps funnier, and with
richer content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Grim Reaper was great fun to watch; one of the highlights was
him challenging the duo, who were playing for their freedom from
hell.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was fun to watch the evil Bill &amp;amp; Ted.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The novelty of freshness went away.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keanu Reeves still sucks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The genius scientist could have been more fun, and their melding
seemed to serve no purpose.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss the splattering of comic one-liners that the original had.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>All About Eve (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/all-about-eve-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/all-about-eve-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I only watched this one because it was said to be an inspiration
(ripped-off) for the underrated &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;showgirls-1995&quot;&gt;Showgirls&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and it certainly is. So
much of the story crept through (young and ambitious blood taking over
from the established; lawyers of the established getting involved; much
conniving involved in the process; etc). Luckily I did enjoy this one
throughout, which is quite a rare thing for a movie so old. But, the
movie is waaay &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;All_About_Eve#Critical_reaction&quot;&gt;overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gorgeous gals: Marilyn Monroe playing a small part of a young gal
trying to make it as an actor and Bette Davis playing the
established actor&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice dialogue here and there&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shitty (unconvincing) performance by the gal playing the title
character, Eve&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another shitty performance by the gal who introduces Eve to the
established&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stagey direction, as is common with movies this old; and we are
supposed to take these characters seriously?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Schindler&#x27;s List (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/schindler-s-list-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/schindler-s-list-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&#x27;t seen this one probably in over ten years, and it&#x27;s not quite
as good as I remember. I even found the performances rather lacking and
that includes Liam Neeson&#x27;s title character. I&#x27;m a fan of the guy, but
what he does here is almost embarassing, and he&#x27;s far outdone by the
movie&#x27;s best performer, Ralph Fiennes (the villain). One other
notably-bad performance is that of the lady playing the Jewish love
interest of our villain. Ben Kingsley, who plays the accountant, is as
uninteresting as usual. Nothing else stands out, although it was fun to
watch the cartoonish portrayal of the guy making a hinge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the movie is bearable throughout it&#x27;s entire 180+ min running
time. Also, stories of heroism are ever so appealing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparison with other movies set around the Holocaust:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sophie&#x27;s Choice&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; did a better job, even though the coverage of the
subject material was very brief.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life is Beautiful&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; offered a far more moving experience, even
though it was partly a comedy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>God On Trial (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/god-on-trial-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/god-on-trial-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s amazing that one can take a silly idea, and make a decent movie of
it. I&#x27;m not sure what the point was, but the some powerful moments, and
decent acting. My favorites were the physicist&#x27;s turn in the court, but
better still was the rabbi, whose encyclopedic knowledge of the Old
Testament made his argument all the more moving. Stellan Skarsgrd, who
plays the judge, is as great as usual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Am Love (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-am-love-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-am-love-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good quality but stale tale of forbidden romance. It has decent acting
throughout, especially from Alba Rohrwacher, who plays the lesbian
daughter. Tilda Swinton is quite good too, except that she overdows her
role a little too much (e.g. her restlessness is over-the-top). This
makes her portrayal rather unbelievable, even though she is a pleasure
to watch (as usual).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dark Matter (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dark-matter-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dark-matter-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story is quite original: our hero is a boy genius and the villain is
a professor he assists, who proves to be a hypocrite averse to being
challenged.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Meryl Streep doing here by the way? I mean her character? She
does add sweetness to the otherwise dull movie though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Air I Breathe (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-air-i-breathe-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-air-i-breathe-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie has three parts: the first got me excited due to superb
direction and nice storytelling; the 2nd doesn&#x27;t lose superb direction
but gets tedious; the 3rd makes me wonder why the writers bothered, but
luckily has one desirable gal, the one with a rare blood type.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing turns out pointless (and stupid) at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dark Knight (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t really express the excitement the movie induced into me, mainly
due to Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker, a great contender for the best ever
villainous character in movie history. This character is the centerpiece
of the whole movie, and actually makes everybody else pretty
uninteresting, including the Dark Knight himself. What makes the
character so interesting is beyond just the acting, but also its unusual
philosophical leanings, personality (no fear for death whatsoever),
genius-level smarts (extremely elaborate and effective plans), all of
which makes the material feel real fresh and making this character
thoroughly developed. The character is also fearsome, funny, and
seriously cunning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#x27;t say there&#x27;s anything outstanding about the visual effects (the
&lt;em&gt;Batman&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; series never impressed in this front) and the chase sequences
don&#x27;t rock so hard (EG the Knight&#x27;s super-sized motorbike could have
done with greater speed to enhance the feeling of adrenaline, but
instead felt like it was slouching around at 60km&#x2F;h). The single
greatest visual effect however is Two-Face&#x27;s ugly side. Though nothing
groundbreaking, it&#x27;s somewhat a first, combining a live face with some
very realistic effects. An early bank robbery scene is pure fun and much
of the action is so sophisticated and complex that it&#x27;s hard to keep
track of what happens. It&#x27;s the movie&#x27;s best.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s great length (over 150 minutes) allows room for some shit to creep
in (Two-Face shouldn&#x27;t have been afforded a sub-plot) but it&#x27;s so
amazing elsewhere that it&#x27;s easily the best ever comic book adaptation
(replacing &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, I&#x27;m pretty glad that the Knight&#x27;s romantic interest has
been recast cuz&#x27; the previous actress was the weakest point in the
magnificent &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second look at &lt;em&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; wasn&#x27;t favorable, all but:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker, the year&#x27;s performance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the bank robbery in an early scene&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not even the action saves the movie, which was mostly wasted cash since
it ain&#x27;t really good. And the last scene really is unbearable. And who
gives a shit about the cheap philosophical blah I so previously
cherished.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no, this isn&#x27;t the best ever comic book adaptation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Incredible Hulk (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-incredible-hulk-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-incredible-hulk-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;1st review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Incredible Hulk&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; has got a great fight between Hulk and &#x27;an
abomination&#x27; and is far better than its shitty predecessor. The
scenic (and abused) views of the massive Latin American slums are
memorable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2nd review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found William Hurt unbearable, while Liv Tyler and Tim Roth didn&#x27;t
help much. Not even the battle of monsters, which itself did lose its
appeal, saves the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
