<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2010-movie/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>How To Train Your Dragon (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was lots more impressive on first viewing. This time around, I found
the face animation terrible, the story recycled, complete with tired
humor, and a forced villain (why couldn&#x27;t it be trained as well, and
what&#x27;s the story... why is it so big). Luckily the whole thing is not
boring, and there are lots of scary moments and edge-of-seat action. The
concept of befriending dragons is also interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Afro Samurai: Resurrection (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/afro-samurai-resurrection-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/afro-samurai-resurrection-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The character design (from the title character to the colorful trio of
cyborgs) is quite good. The action fight choreography is among the most
brutal and intense I&#x27;ve yet seen, though it is often hard to figure
what is happening, a trick that is too common in action movies. The
movie also possesses a curious (and effective) mixture of two worlds
foreign to each other, hip-hop and oriental martial arts culture. It&#x27;s
nicely spiced with the Samuel L. Jackson character, which helps bring
some humanity to an otherwise dark storyline.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Memento (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/memento-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/memento-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very solid story with superb, but disturbing, direction. The concept
is among the best I have seen. The acting is top class, notably the
three leads: Guy Pearce, Carrie-Anne Moss, and Joe Pantoliano (in a role
that seems written especially for him). The twist sucks a bit
unfortunately, especially given that the lead appears to be a reasonable
character.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Spread (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/spread-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/spread-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality direction, production design, cinematography, and cast. A decent
story which luckily doesn&#x27;t end in the tired way romances tend to be. I
enjoyed this more the first time around, mainly due to the sexuality
surrounding the man-whore and the rich lawyer. I enjoyed the
open-mindedness that she expressed, though she later on became
attached&#x2F;possessive enough to find the jealousy unbearable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Vicky Cristina Barcelona (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/vicky-cristina-barcelona-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/vicky-cristina-barcelona-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those strange movies that I enjoy heavily on first
viewing and fall bad on a second one. For example, I found the character
of Javier Bardem incredibly appealing, but saw a cheap and pretentious
character second time around, as if the overly self-conscious Woody
Allen was desperate to appease. As for Penélope Cruz, I praised her
profusely for her portrayal of the crazy-but-gifted ex-lover. Well, the
performance is good, but the appeal wore off, but it remains &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;favorite-of-career-performances&quot;&gt;my
favorite of her performances&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I guess the main appeal of the movie is
the concept of open relationships (and frank sex talk).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Social Network (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-social-network-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-social-network-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A fun ride that is unlike anything done before it. Calling it a
masterpiece would however be a lot more than it deserves. Sure it was
made by the best director ever, it has the supercool Justin Timberlake,
has a superb lead, and has quality acting, incredible camerawork, an
amazing script&#x2F;dialog, but that is just not enough. Perhaps it was just
not gripping enough, or the story appealing enough. It ends decently,
though not in any way one would expect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Great Dictator (1940)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-great-dictator-1940/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-great-dictator-1940/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the set designs of the palace impressive as well as the costumes
worn by the people there, especially those having high ranks in the
military. I found the humor unfunny, and the directing tired, complete
with overlong scenes. Maybe Charlie Chaplin is interesting, but not
here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Alice In Wonderland (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/alice-in-wonderland-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/alice-in-wonderland-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a number of enchanting moments, and Alice is sweet to the eye;
she is also lovely in battle costume and battle movement; the hatter is
at times fun (my favorite moment, also the saddest, is when exclaiming
how good it would be that he dies looking good); the evil queen is the
most interesting of all, despite the fact that her deeds are at times
too evil to swallow (e.g. her usage of an animal as a golf ball, or her
castle being surrounded by heads she severed). The movie however feels
rushed and the characters underdeveloped.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Clash of the Titans (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/clash-of-the-titans-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/clash-of-the-titans-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I like a few of the characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medusa: gorgeous, yet scary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Kraken: among the largest of all movie monsters I&#x27;ve seen,
complete with superb facial design&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underworld creature that drives the boat, together with the two
others pulling the ship&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades: the entrance +++ when spreading his &#x27;wings&#x27; +++ is
entrancing and the performance (Ralph Fiennes) and body movement
befitting; this the movie&#x27;s best moment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some badly-designed ones:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scorpions aren&#x27;t convincing, nor are the battles involving them&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The charred-skin wizards have some presence, but what the fuck is up
with look&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The former king who got burned by Zeus&#x27; lightning got make-up that
looks like something from a B-movie; that character is not
interesting too&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the story, it is merely standard. Nothing to celebrate there.
Strangely, I enjoyed the movie more on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Secret of Kells (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-secret-of-kells-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-secret-of-kells-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s bizarre in a way similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-triplets-of-belleville-2003&quot;&gt;The Triplets of Belleville&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and has
some emotionally powerful moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the attack scene was quite painful; it&#x27;s some of sort of reminder
of the tough realities of the world&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the character development of Ashley, the forest creature that helped
the hero on a few occasions, was quite interesting; it was
especially sad when her great strength was challenged by some evil
creature of the same forest, especially when her form changed to
express the pain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the general character design&#x2F;development is quite good really; my
favorites are the strict leader of the town and the fat guy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the cat is among the most charming characters I&#x27;ve seen in movie
history&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the negative side, the movie is a little disturbing&#x2F;unsettling (okay,
that&#x27;s not a negative), and is also sleep-inducing. I also couldn&#x27;t
get what the point of it was. Maybe it&#x27;s kinda biblical, since it
centers around some all-important book (and the lead character looks
like Jesus when grown-up).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Precious (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/precious-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/precious-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is among the most emotionally powerful movies I&#x27;ve seen, a movie
with a social message, without the preaching; excellent direction,
superb cast. The story shown is the most horrific showcase of domestic
abuse I&#x27;ve seen yet (EG, mother yells something like &amp;quot;I should have
aborted your ass!&amp;quot;, and that&#x27;s not the worst of it). Character
development is top-class as well. The movie boasts supreme direction and
script (dialogue).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many wonderful performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenny Kravitz as the nurse; check especially his expression when she
checks out the lesbian(s).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mariah Carey as the welfare officer; her character looks like she&#x27;s
having some personal shit of her own, at the same battles to hold a
professional stance on learning the lead character&#x27;s shit life.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mo&#x27;Nique as the horrid mother; she very believable, but the
climactic scene, when she&#x27;s with Mariah Carey&#x27;s welfare officer is
hard-to-beat, in all of movie history! This is not your traditional
villain, and in the end, she does seem a victim (of her own idiocy).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sherri Shepherd as the lady who just can&#x27;t leave the telephone
alone.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The grand-mom; check the moment she expresses disgust against the
mother (Mo&#x27;Nique), once the social worker leaves.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chyna Layne so flawlessly plays an oh-so-kind Jamaican classmate,
and does it with an accent that makes me want her hard.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xosha Roquemore so flawlessly plays a lound-mouthed, yet loving,
classmate. I want her too.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amina Robinson is the more serious, scarfaced classmate, who I want
even harder than the rest. Shit, she&#x27;s fuckin&#x27; gorgeous, and that
whatever she&#x27;s wearing on her head doesn&#x27;t help my plight. Shit,
this was supposed to be a review about acting talent. Yeah, ummm,
she really rocks. I love her stree-wise sass. So god-damn charming.
I might be obsessed by my heavy attraction for her, but she really
pulls it together so god-damn-well. She&#x27;s not as pretty as Angelic
Zambrana, but beauty ain&#x27;t everything.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angelic Zambrana plays the prettiest of classmates. She&#x27;s also the
onyl real asshole of the class too, and does too well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grace Hightower plays the social worker, and has great presence.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gabourey Sidibe plays the lead character; she can certainly carry
the movie through, but I&#x27;m kinda split is she&#x27;s that good. On one
hand I just see a fat ass carrying her weight around, surrounded by
superior talent. On the other, I see someone who makes me look
forward to any little facial movement, because she&#x27;s that
charismatic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember a better cast in all my movie-watching years. This is
impressive, considering that these aren&#x27;t mostly veteran actors (all
faces are fresh to me, other than that of Mo&#x27;Nique). I truly commend
the director for this (I suppose he&#x27;s the niggah responsible). A lot of
these characters appear only briefly, but they leave quite an
impression. In fact, the one person who is out of place is the pretty
teacher. It&#x27;s the movie&#x27;s only average (if not worse) performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Eat Pray Love (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/eat-pray-love-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/eat-pray-love-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this one really unbearable and boring. There is decent acting,
but Julia Roberts is extremely uninteresting as a leading lady (I&#x27;ve
never enjoyed any of her performances). The story makes me curious if
the writers believe in the shit they are promoting (prayer; fortune
telling). On the bright side, the experiences in Italy were kinda fun,
and I felt longing for the warmth of the relationships created there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Somewhere (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/somewhere-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/somewhere-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead character of rich, famous, and easily fucks ultra-hot gals, yet
the only bright thing in his life seems to be her beloved daughter (who
is given a flawless portrayal). This feeling of purposelessness is
well-punctuated by Sofia Coppola&#x27;s superb direction of loong takes and
a story where nealy nothing happens. This movie is a greater favorite to
the director&#x27;s earlier &lt;em&gt;Lost in Translation&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, which covered similar
territory; the lead is far more interesting, and does not have that
irritating Japanese tv host.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Crazy Heart (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/crazy-heart-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/crazy-heart-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So this sweet lady (Maggie Gyllenhaal) falls for this alcoholic guy (and
I wonder why since the guy looks like he smells like shit; maybe it&#x27;s
because she a sucker for the guy&#x27;s music). She allows the guy to chill
with her kid with the condition that he not drink in front of him. Well,
it does happen, and the guy loses the kid while both are in a bar,
though the kid is found hours later. As would be expected, &#x27;sweet
lady&#x27; goes mad and despite repeated pleading, does not forgive the guy.
I think that&#x27;s harsh, even for him. One good outcome however was that
that was a wake-up call for him to actually quit drinking, and he even
accepted the break-up (I didn&#x27;t).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is good, but boring. The acting is even better, especially
from the lead, Jeff Bridges (who looks so much like Kris Kristofferson,
I thought it was him). Maggie is as desirable as usual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Confessions of a Shopaholic (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/confessions-of-a-shopaholic-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/confessions-of-a-shopaholic-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is formulaic and stale, but I loved the funny scene where a group of
shopaholics come together to help cure their obsession; I also loved the
flawless dummy visual effects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
