<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/politics/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>links 2014-06-04</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/links-2014-06-04/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/links-2014-06-04/</guid>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;loupgaroublond.blogspot.com&#x2F;2008&#x2F;12&#x2F;open-source-and-anarchism.html?showComment=1229842200000#c4468517513122259751&quot;&gt;An excellent description on why Anarchy is the best possible
society ever imagined&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.salon.com&#x2F;2013&#x2F;10&#x2F;25&#x2F;crowdsource_your_salary_an_economy_built_on_love&quot;&gt;Great write-up on Gittip&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration of an interesting concept... &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;building-gittip&#x2F;2c621dbd7541&quot;&gt;a balance between
resentment and guilt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;decorrespondent.nl&#x2F;541&#x2F;why-we-should-give-free-money-to-everyone&#x2F;20798745-cb9fbb39&quot;&gt;Why we should give free money to everyone&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; - a highly-detailed
read, which supports &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pipe-dream-basic-income-for-south-african-adults&quot;&gt;this dream of mine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>South Africa &#x27;will continue to function&#x27;</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/south-africa-will-continue-to-function/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/south-africa-will-continue-to-function/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Encouraging:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite Zuma, the country will continue to function - because the ANC
does not do everything wrong, because South Africa has a strong,
self-confident, heterogenous civil society as well as a sovereign,
independent legal system, a vocal media landscape, and a solid,
diversified economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;allafrica.com&#x2F;stories&#x2F;201405092216.html&quot;&gt;South Africa Postpones Radical Change&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - on 2014 Elections&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This slightly reduces my fears of great social instability since it does
not look like the next 5 years will be better than the last 5. It could
even be worse, given we are said to be among &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;List_of_countries_by_income_equality&quot;&gt;the most unequal countries
in terms of individual wealth&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. There is no predicting the future, but
it does not look to me there is much hope, short of some miracles. That
the landscape of political power is practically left unchanged is
worrying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>the one I revere most, after losing Madiba</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-one-i-revere-most-after-losing-madiba/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-one-i-revere-most-after-losing-madiba/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As far as I can remember, there was not a single living individual I
respected more than I did Madiba. That would explain the fact of my
weeping on the morning I heard of his death, which is something I never
did for any single individual. For some time now, I actually asked
myself which of his many deeds lead to such reverence, and I don&#x27;t
really know. I do strongly suspect though that it&#x27;s the key role he
played in ending government-sanctioned racism against non-Caucasians in
South Africa. Being a Black citizen of that country, this is something
that affected me personally, and something I will eternally be grateful
for. In addition to that, this man is also not just a hero (being a
freedom fighter), but also a saint (promoting reconciliation with the
oppressors). It&#x27;s not only that, but also the fact that he is
constantly hailed as an icon of peace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a number of times, I would ask myself if there was anyone alive who
garners greater respect, and the only person who came close is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;14th_Dalai_Lama&quot;&gt;the
current Dalai Lama&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but I must admit I don&#x27;t know much about him,
beyond his winning a Nobel Peace Prize. Another candidate is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Desmond_Tutu&quot;&gt;Desmond
Tutu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who frequently speaks against injustice, and also happens to be a
winner of that most prestigious of awards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one other candidate, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Noam_chomsky&quot;&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, whose intellect and
activism I deeply respect. Watching and listening to some of his
political work some time in 2012 led me to consider him the most
valuable person alive. His influence is likely smaller than that of the
above-mentioned candidates, but being the world&#x27;s foremost Anarchist is
quite something, especially given that it&#x27;s the most attractive of all
political theories I&#x27;ve yet encountered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with a disclaimer that I am largely ignorant of world events, Noam
Chomsky takes the place of Nelson Mandela as &lt;strong&gt;the living individual I
admire the most&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Valve appears anarchistic</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/valve-appears-anarchistic/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/valve-appears-anarchistic/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gamasutra.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;feature&#x2F;3408&quot;&gt;how this legendary game creator is run&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (or at least used
to be), I was pretty much reminded that&#x27;s kinda how an anarchistic
business would be run. I was pleasantly surprised to later encounter a
section named &lt;em&gt;The Workers Control the Means of Production&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; on the same
article. Kool stuff. [&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;assets.sbnation.com&#x2F;assets&#x2F;1074301&#x2F;Valve_Handbook_LowRes.pdf&quot;&gt;via&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>on Anarchism</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/on-anarchism/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/on-anarchism/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been many great benefits I got from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.debian.org&quot;&gt;the Debian project&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
among the most important being an introduction to Anarchism, a radical
political theory that opposes all forms of official hierarchy
(capitalism, communism, religion, etc), arguing that such things tend to
result in oppression.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I got access to that is via a package known as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;packages.debian.org&#x2F;stable&#x2F;anarchism&quot;&gt;anarchism&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a set of
documents formally known as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;anarchism.pageabode.com&#x2F;afaq&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;An Anarchist FAQ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s a very
comprehensive coverage of the theory, and going through it brought both
enlightenment and frustration, for it explained so many things that I
took for granted, while pointing out the causes. The theory is basically
presented as the best possible society humans could ever have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me, I&#x27;m not sure if it&#x27;s actually true, although I lean more
towards it than alternatives (and I haven&#x27;t read anything extensive on
competing theories, but intuition&#x2F;experience tells me that capitalism,
communism, and religion all suck tremendously). I need more study to be
more sure, especially because the objections to Anarchism are heavy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me it&#x27;s a scarier concept to introduce yourself as an anarchist than
as an atheist or a homosexual, because the implications are greater. In
fact, they are so great, that the word &lt;em&gt;anarchy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; itself has been
associated with chaos. That&#x27;s an expected knee-jerk reaction you&#x27;ll
get when you punt things like &amp;quot;I reject all forms of official
authority, including all governments!&amp;quot;. But it would be nice if people
who shudder at the concept to spend time with &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;anarchism.pageabode.com&#x2F;afaq&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;that great document&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My attraction to the theory perhaps is due to my radically liberal
tendencies (e.g., I don&#x27;t see anything wrong with fucking my biological
mother, provided it&#x27;s consensual, and there&#x27;s no pregnancy). I don&#x27;t
know where these tendencies originate, considering that I was a
religious nut back in my early teens, scared of the concept of hell and
similar forms of bullshit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Anarchism and the GPL</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/anarchism-and-the-gpl/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/anarchism-and-the-gpl/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reading some old Debian posts where there was an argument brewing
regarding the existence of anarchy within Debian. A notable point raised
was that the existence of the GPL, the leading FLOSS licence, would be
impossible because a licence&#x27;s existence requires laws to exist. The
argument was that, since anarchy is against law (due to the idea that
law is designed to defend the elites and oppress the majority), then
there can&#x27;t be free software.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#x27;s notable about the argument is that it&#x27;s pretty dumb. Now since
anarchy ain&#x27;t mainstream, it seems okay to use the current system to
enforce some form of anarchy by law (use what little you have). GPL
creator himself states that free software (subset of FLOSS) existed in
MIT without requiring licences and then states that it&#x27;s companies
which refused open access to code, forcing GPL creator (Richard
Stallman) to start a project to develop a truly free Operating System.
In an anarchistic society, there certainly seems to be no motivation to
develop non-FLOSS, but in today&#x27;s rogue society, there&#x27;s plenty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Anarchism and teen sexuality</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/anarchism-and-teen-sexuality/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/anarchism-and-teen-sexuality/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a well-researched document named The Anarchist FAQ (AFAQ)
included in Debian which I spent some time reading. This wasn&#x27;t a
first-time effort by the way, for the doc is very large. What prompted
the post is the very radical idea contained therein that parents should
encourage their teens to engage in sexual activity, defending such a
position by pointing to evidence that much social decay owes to sexual
taboos. It&#x27;s really amazing what I read and I haven&#x27;t been intrigued
so much by a philosophical theory in such a long time. Oh, and by the
way, anarchism is an extremely attractive theory, though I have very
many questions still. I&#x27;ll keep studying to understand more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
