<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2014/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Non-Stop</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/non-stop/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/non-stop/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Liam Neeson gets to be tough guy nearly as impressive as his character
in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;taken-2008&quot;&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and in a movie nearly as intense. More impressive, however,
is the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nate_Parker&quot;&gt;Nate Parker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; performance, whose incredible transformation near
the end of the movie is exciting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie has some of the best action sequences I&#x27;ve seen yet, as well
as impressive dialog and direction. The visuals are also wonderful
(check the descent of the plane as well as its landing).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do, however, wish:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The acts of the villain were given better justification&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More people should have died, given the rough landing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most interesting performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Rooker, playing Yondu, the leader of the bandits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Pratt, playing the playful lead&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bautista, playing Drax, the heavily-tattooed brute (amazing make-up)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed Groot, the tree-like humanoid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite character design is the lead villain, though I wish the mud
on the face was explained. I also wish he was a more convincing
villain... he needed deeper development than what he gets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is a lot more whacky than I expected, and does not suit
its epic name. It has lots of humor, and is very entertaining, but I
wish it was less of a passive movie. It also doesn&#x27;t offer anything
new, and the visual effects are merely decent... nothing
ground-breaking here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2014 review</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/2014-review/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/2014-review/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The best &lt;strong&gt;action&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; can be found in the fight scenes of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;non-stop&quot;&gt;Non-Stop&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but
the best &lt;strong&gt;visual effects&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; are in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dracula-untold&quot;&gt;Dracula Untold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The best
&lt;strong&gt;animation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;big-hero-6&quot;&gt;Big Hero 6&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a movie that also has my &lt;strong&gt;favorite
character&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, the inflatable robot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula Untold</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-untold/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-untold/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of those movies which choose not to distinguish themselves at all in
terms of story (so shallow, though I do like the vampire re-imagining)
and direction (nothing new), but it is entertaining at least. It also
got great visual effects and amazing make-up work, not to mention a
wonderful performance from the great &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Charles_Dance&quot;&gt;Charles Dance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-the-battle-of-the-five-armies/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-the-battle-of-the-five-armies/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the creature design of the dragon amazing; best dragon design
I&#x27;ve yet seen. Most everything else is stale, though I do love the
giants. The combat moments were annoying, where you see puny creatures
stand their own against the fearsome beasts. I wish these beasts were
given more than cardboard characters, given that they clearly were
intelligent beings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nightcrawler</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nightcrawler/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nightcrawler/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is overall well-made and got a story that feels fresh, and one
that&#x27;s seldom told: people taking video footage of gruesome events. The
scene that culminates in a police car chase is intense and feels
realistic; great direction and camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jake Gyllenhaal, the lead of the quality cast, is a highly skilled actor
(see &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;prisoners-2013&quot;&gt;Prisoners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;zodiac-and-david-fincher&quot;&gt;Zodiac&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), but I haven&#x27;t seen him this good. His
character is very unusual and scary, and pretty much a supreme asshole
you wish didn&#x27;t exist. His life is shit (he&#x27;s lonely, out of money,
and seems to have some mental problem), so I almost don&#x27;t blame him for
his criminal behavior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rene Russo also gives a great performance, and so does the lady
portraying the detective, Michael Hyatt. The latter is very imposing,
and pretty much towers above everyone in her (few and short-lived)
scenes. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-movie-characters#tough-women&quot;&gt;Great toughness portrayal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Big Hero 6</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/big-hero-6/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/big-hero-6/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The level of fantasy in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cloudy-with-a-chance-of-meatballs-2009&quot;&gt;Cloudy With A Chance of Meatballs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; went to
ridiculous levels, but this one is even worse. As was the case with
Cloudy, it started very well, mostly with the help of the cute, chubby,
and funny air-filled robot, but devolves into super-lazy writing with
too many holes, and an overly-skilled teenage engineer. Making things
worse is some bad recycled plot points, an example being the apologetic
moment our (very uninteresting) lead character gets to have after doing
something unbearably stupid. All this spoils the various good spots the
movie offers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Jimmy&#x27;s Hall</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/jimmy-s-hall/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/jimmy-s-hall/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My bad memory tells me that this is the first pro-socialist movie I&#x27;ve
yet seen. It&#x27;s also well-made, well-written, and got very good
performances, my favorite being the mother of the lead character. It
feels like an accurate description of what socialist strive would look
like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
