<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2014-movie/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wreck-It Ralph (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wreck-it-ralph-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wreck-it-ralph-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A highly-enjoyable fantasy about a bad-guy video game character who
yearns for some loving. His acting on this desire, however, messes
things up since he was designed to be villain. Along the way, he meets a
delightful character in a form of computer glitch, an outcast that he
reluctantly befriends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is typical Disney, but it&#x27;s all good formula. The
animation is good (check the racing cars and the high-resolution game)
and the story enchanting, and it&#x27;s all predictable of course.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Good People (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/good-people-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/good-people-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It has good direction and acting (I&#x27;ve never seen Tom Wilkinson this
good, and I enjoyed watching the ultra-cool Omar Sy). But, it&#x27;s yet
another example of a well-made movie that ends not so well. It&#x27;s too
smart and fresh for such improbable things to happen, worst of which was
having the detective drive into a bad guy just-in-time. Regardless, the
critics gave it more hate than it deserved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Fault in Our Stars (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-fault-in-our-stars-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-fault-in-our-stars-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most exciting moment is the encounter with the author of the a
favorite book of the leading character. It was quite intense, and rather
surprising, though not entirely unpredictable. Willem Dafoe gives the
character some justice, even though the characterization feels recycled,
some sort of a caricature.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, this is yet another movie that starts off well and fucks
up later on. The fuck-up this time around happens around halfway through
the movie, which is around the end of the Amsterdam trip. The rest of it
drags on, and just feel overlong. I even got tired of watching the
leading lady, Shailene Woodley, despite her excellent performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How To Train Your Dragon 2 (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/how-to-train-your-dragon-2-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved the character design of the mother, and that includes both the
look and movements. She was even better when masked, possessing
awe-inspiring presence, a feeling enhanced by her great skill of the
dragons. &#x27;Her&#x27; dragons, which are newer designs from those from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;how-to-train-your-dragon-2010&quot;&gt;the
earlier movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, also received great design, most impressive of which is
the Alpha. Exploring the home of these dragons was quite an experience,
which is weird, given the careless character design elsewhere (e.g. most
of the human characters). The epic feel is among the greatest I&#x27;ve
experienced of any movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is full of quality humor. Among my favorites is the romantic
attraction expressed by the girl for the new guy. It&#x27;s recycled stuff,
but well executed. There was also good humor (and charms) from the
dragons; check how playful they are with each other.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish more time was spent with the mother, since she is easily the most
interesting character in the movie. Instead, she&#x27;s later reduced to a
secondary character, and not even instrumental in the victory her son
emerges from. Also, the writers mostly neglected the promise she made to
teach this son about the dragons. Instead the movie rushes too quickly
to the son (and his dragon) being pretty much the sole hero of the
movie. So shallow, so sad. Wasted opportunity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lucy (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lucy-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lucy-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s surprising to have a movie with A-list starts be this wacky. It&#x27;s
exciting and feels fresh for the first 30 minutes or so, right up until
the moment the lead character, Lucy, gets the drugs removed from inside
her. The phone call to mommy was especially wonderful. The villain was
also very scary. Most of the rest is gibberish, bordering on stupid. By
the time the whole thing ends, I was tempted to call the move bad, but
there&#x27;s still that first 30 minutes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other thing to praise was the WTF that Morgan Freeman expressed on
the first phone call to this Lucy character. I don&#x27;t recall such a
level of wonderment in all of my movie-watching experience (but I have
shitty memory).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story concept is similar to that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;limitless-2011&quot;&gt;Limitless&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but with far less
restraint, and a much lesser script.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Edge of Tomorrow (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/edge-of-tomorrow-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/edge-of-tomorrow-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting ride, all until the too-implausible elimination of the villain.
Could have been better if the humans lost actually, instead of the lazy
resolution, where the two heroes receive way too much pounding. The
enemy was also too advanced (faster, bigger, and better weaponry) for
them to make through that final showdown. Everywhere else if fine,
because the two heroes get multiple opportunities against this
impressive enemy. I also wish the enemy was explored more. The
single-super-villain-controls-all-others thing is just too stupid and
recycled (think &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). and not worthy of a quality
offering such as this gem. Not even Tom Cruise is a blemish, and the
visual effects are supreme, even though they were showcased mainly at
the beginning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Book Thief (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-book-thief-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-book-thief-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Rush gives a very touching performance as kindly guardian of a
girl who lost her family. He is as loving a character as I&#x27;ve seen in
movies. Emily Watson also shines as the angry wife. Both performances
are flawless, and the movie feels like a weird and horrid fable. It&#x27;s
not a pleasant watch, especially the second half.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Purge: Anarchy (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-purge-anarchy-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-purge-anarchy-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Intensely brutal story about a United States where, on one night of the
year, murder is made legal. It&#x27;s a fresh idea, and is executed well,
though a bit over-the-top at times. It&#x27;s also not a plausible idea, or
rather, it deserved better justification.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performances are of decent quality, best of which are the rich
characters near the end, who view killing others as entertainment. My
favorite, though brief, is the leader of those who deliver the victims
to these rich killers: scary, yet somewhat sympathetic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Age of Extinction (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-age-of-extinction-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-age-of-extinction-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s the best in the series so far, but I don&#x27;t really see an
improvement in visual effects over &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I&#x27;m guessing
that&#x27;s because &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-2007&quot;&gt;the first movie in the series&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; set a ridiculously high
bar. In keeping to tradition, the movie is also noisy and has
overly-frantic action (WTF&#x27;s going on), and has way too much of it. It
also has a shallow story-line and none of the characters are very
interesting. Luckily, there is no &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tyrese_Gibson&quot;&gt;Tyrese Gibson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Josh_Duhamel&quot;&gt;Josh Duhamel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to
help spoil things. There is also no mention of why these primary human
characters were so drastically changed... sad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is entertaining throughout, despite running for over 150
minutes. The evil Transformers were scarily-violent, as they always were
in this series. The scariest of them, Megatron, was pretty much cast
aside in this movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Enough Said (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/enough-said-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/enough-said-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead gives an amazing and charming performance. James Gandolfino is
impressive too, and they are both very believable. The direction and
editing are wonderful, all so smooth and out of the way, focusing very
much on the characters. It&#x27;s all blessed with an amazing script, a
rather unusual story (fresh), quality humor, and one of the best
on-a-date moments in movie memory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with it is that the second half doesn&#x27;t feel as solid as the
first, and the whole thing doesn&#x27;t feel like it has good re-watch
value. It feels more like (a really good) TV series, something like
&lt;em&gt;Girls&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting discovery that the director responsible for this
one (Nicole Holofcener) also made two other movies I love: &lt;em&gt;Friends With
Money&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;please-give-2009&quot;&gt;Please Give&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For that reason, they deserve a revisit, more
so than this one :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Expendables 3</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-expendables-3/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-expendables-3/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked a few things:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not remember enjoying Antonio Banderas this much; his character
and performance are superior to all others (not hard) in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I initially felt that Mel Gibson was miscast as villain, but he
proved worthy: a fearsome personality (well-developed, and deserving
a better movie) and a really good performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed watching Dolph Lundgren; he gives a decent, humorous
performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jet Li and Arnold Schwarzenegger give awful performances, but it was
interesting to see them play homosexual partners; I proud.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other performances range from substandard to merely okay. They are
not interesting, and neither is the story. The movie is too loud, extra
shallow, and offers nothing new at all. I wish they don&#x27;t make another,
because I&#x27;m gonna have to watch it as well :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Spectacular Now (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-spectacular-now-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-spectacular-now-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The stellar cast is led by the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Miles_Teller&quot;&gt;Miles Teller&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;rabbit-hole-2010&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;),
armed with a superb script. The whole exercise still left me wondering
what the point was. Feels random. I wish it was more fun, but it was
engaging enough to not leave me feeling too punished.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>13 Sins (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/13-sins-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/13-sins-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A brilliant concept, clearly inspired by &lt;em&gt;The Game&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; thriller and &lt;em&gt;Saw&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
series of horror movies. I am a fan of Ron Perlman, so long as he&#x27;s not
given shit roles like in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pacific-rim-2013&quot;&gt;Pacific Rim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He does great work here, him and
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rutina_Wesley&quot;&gt;Rutina Wesley&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The &#x27;happy&#x27; ending thing is also stupid. The voice
acting of the evil guy on the phone is wonderful, and so is his script.
What a pleasure!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story concepts this good seldom have great conclusions, and this one is
no exception. The twist is just not needed at all (it&#x27;s too much of a
stretch, both the father and brother thing). It would have also been
nice to have more of a reveal of the villains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Godzilla (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/godzilla-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/godzilla-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this so unpleasant that it made me miss the 1998 movie. None of
the creature designs was any good. This includes the title character,
who, in an effort to resemble the original Godzilla (1960s) ended up
clumsy as fuck. You don&#x27;t emulate shit costume design just to pay
homage, unless you are making satire maybe, or you are a plain better
director. It was also laughable having this Godzilla character be a
friend to humans (stupid twist) and having it spit fire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human characters (and the performances) were also not interesting.
Not one of them were convincing, and some were even unbearable at times
(check the guy playing the heroic son, or the Japanese scientist).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is noisy and the story not interesting. The all-too-common
Hollywood thing about family values was hard to bear. So cheesy, so
stale. Sigh!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Appleseed Alpha (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-alpha-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-alpha-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;More a showcase of animation technology than a satisfying story for a
feature-length movie, it&#x27;s a prequel to the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-2004&quot;&gt;two&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-ex-machina-2007&quot;&gt;movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s got
some good things going for it:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lips of the little girl are amazing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The environments have wonderful detail&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cyborg lover of the lead character of the previous movies,
Briario, is a lot more pleasing to watch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, there is no noticeable 2D&#x2F;3D fusion, which helped made
me notice how sucky we still at at doing convincing human faces, unless
you have a massive budget I suppose. The movie doesn&#x27;t represent any
noticeable advancement of animation capabilities, even though it has its
moments. As regards the story, it&#x27;s interesting enough, but really has
nothing new. The giant robot thing is just stupid, and the leading lady,
who is not as a major a character as she was in the first movie, still
has unexplained physical prowess. She also too damn lucky, brushing off
highly dangerous situations like they are nothing. Sad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain America: The Winter Soldier (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-winter-soldier-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-winter-soldier-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far superior to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011&quot;&gt;the disgusting original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this one is even better than
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-avengers-2012&quot;&gt;The Avengers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, even without Hulk and Iron Man. The action sequences are
intense, though excessive (think &lt;em&gt;The Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but not too
frantic. My favorite action sequence is the Fury chase. The abilities of
the Winter Soldier matched that of Captain America, making him fun to
watch. I would have done without the flying guy (Falcon), who happens to
be overly skillful, like he was some super-human, which he&#x27;s not. Same
applies to the Black Widow character. The story is okay but does not
rise above the feeling that it attempts nothing other than keep the
franchise going. There&#x27;s lots of shortcuts, and not much depth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Noah (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/noah-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/noah-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I think there isn&#x27;t much to the Noah story, so the writers added a few
things, like talking rocks, a magical grandfather (and pregnancy), a
pointless king (at least in the latter part of the movie), and a God
that sucks at communication. If I was tasked with creating a basic
story-line, I would have had the Noah family actually go find those
animals themselves instead of them magically be brought onto the ship.
In addition, I wouldn&#x27;t do the lazy thing where they are all put to
sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised (and disappointed) that the movie was directed by the
great Darren Aronofsky, who gave up &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pi-1997&quot;&gt;Pi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream-2000&quot;&gt;Requiem For A Dream&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
There is nothing interesting&#x2F;provocative enough to deserve such a
skillful person. The visual design may be interesting, but not by much.
It is dark and desolate, which is typical of his movies, but it&#x27;s too
bland a story. It&#x27;s epic, yes, but it&#x27;s also based on one of the most
nonsensical of all stories in the Bible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men: Days of Future Past (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-days-of-future-past-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-days-of-future-past-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite character is the super-fast mutant, and my favorite scene is
one where it stops security guards from killing his accomplices. The
humor is good and his abilities impressive. The time travel part wasn&#x27;t
done bad and Wolverine is interesting. The Sentinels are fearsome and
the power of Magneto ridiculous, much like he had in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;x-men-3-the-last-stand-2006&quot;&gt;X-Men 3: The Last
Stand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this received better reviews than any of the movies in the
franchise, but I think the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;x-men-2-2003&quot;&gt;X-Men 2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>300: Rise of an Empire (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/300-rise-of-an-empire-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/300-rise-of-an-empire-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The acting style of Eva Green worked far better in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dark-shadows-2012&quot;&gt;Dark Shadows&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and
is in fact is embarrassing here. She is as unconvincing as the other
tough gal character, the wife of Leonidas, who had to go as being on the
front-line in battle. It&#x27;s as if someone was desperate to do the girl
power thing, to disastrous effect. Did I say embarrassing?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I like the parallel story-line approach, where much of the
events in the movies take place at the same time as those from the
earlier, and far superior, movie. Sadly we do not have an appealing
lead, and in fact not a single character impresses. The battles still
look good, but nowhere near those from the original, nor are the visuals
as amazing. The sex scene was even more stupid than the one in the
original.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>RoboCop (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robocop-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robocop-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The new suit is a lot more interesting (think the 2008 &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), and
greater detail given to the workings of the man-machine combo. There is
good quality visual affects, and the movie was fun enough to have me
wish for a longer running length. I wish better actors were chosen for
the roles of wife and partner, and it would have been nice had this
partner been given a meatier role. Better still, it should have been a
woman, in honor of the 1987 movie. Or better still, get rid of the
partner. There&#x27;s enough other things to keeping things interesting. I
also wish someone else was chosen in place of the uninteresting Gary
Oldman, the same person who made the Nolan Batman trilogy less bearable
than it needed to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crime-fighting part was rather rushed, and the story not very solid.
I enjoyed watching Samuel L. Jackson play a commentator, and the first
scene was really good, though it felt like more was left to be said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a great reboot. I can&#x27;t tell if it&#x27;s better than the
original for it&#x27;s been too long, but I think it&#x27;s less scary, but also
less cartoonish. The lead actor is also not as interesting. Younger yes,
but a lesser actor, and a boring face actually.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Amazing Spider-Man 2 (2014)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2-2014/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2-2014/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is even worse than the 2002 movie, which I considered
the least interesting in the previous series of 3 movies. It was highly
disappointing because I heavily anticipated it (I&#x27;m a sucker for
super-hero movies). It is poorly written, and got cheesy romance and (I
wish Gwen died a lot earlier in the movie). It also has uninteresting
villains (Paul Giamatti is miscast, and so is Jamie Foxx). Not even the
visual effects impress, being worse than those of its predecessor &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-amazing-spider-man-2012&quot;&gt;the
2012 movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the action is too frantic. I do like, however, the
relaxed manner to this Spider-Man. However, his skills are ridiculously
high, and he survives way too much current flowing through his body.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monsters (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monsters-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monsters-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Although directing&#x2F;editing style is not new, it still feels fresh. The
visual effects are also done well, but the aftermath of the damage done
by both the title characters and the military is done even better. One
thing that&#x27;s impressive about the whole production is that it&#x27;s very
expansive for a budget of less than $1 million. You would not even
notice. Sadly, there is a point where the lead characters are tiring,
such that I&#x27;d appreciate if at least one of them got killed at some
point. They are also too damn lucky.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Human Centipede 2 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-human-centipede-2-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-human-centipede-2-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I do not remember watching a more extreme movie, in terms of
(hard-to-watch) gore. The director also tried real hard to make the lead
character as repulsive as possible, a character lucky enough to get a
wonderful performance by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;name&#x2F;nm4030776&quot;&gt;Laurence R. Harvey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (his first movie).
Interestingly, this character cannot be blamed for the harms he inflicts
on others, given he&#x27;s mentally disturbed, complete with a rather
unhappy toddler-hood. It&#x27;s a pity three of the other characters were
just lazily-developed, making them unconvincing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mommy was a cheap copy of the one in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;Precious&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The story went too
far by having her try to kill her own child, though the reaction of
this child, the lead character, was super-kool... so damn oblivious
to what just occurred. Did I mention I love this character?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The horny guy with a large beard should have been given more of a
story. He is interesting, but his actions were just left
unexplained... his sexual attraction to the lead character. It was
also real stupid placing him near the workplace of this lead
character.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The loud neighbor was too much of an ass-hole, going as far as
assaulting the lead character for practically no reason. That was
just stupid.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I though it was quite daring to include the pregnant woman among the
victims. Worse still, her giving birth like that. Wow! Talk of pushing
boundaries. Also, the movie may not be as fresh as its predecessor, but
it&#x27;s a lot better (direction, cinematography, acting).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Flight (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/flight-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/flight-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I find it daring to have Denzel Washington play a character this broken.
Not evil, just broken. I don&#x27;t know what was the point of drug addict
lover; maybe it was added in order to have the viewers sympathize with
this Washington character (he cared for her even though she was also
broken), but his saving of lives already put him in our favor. No, she
wasn&#x27;t needed, at all, but she was welcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High quality direction, performances, and dialog; an unusual and rather
unpredictable story; an unneeded, but colorful, character (John
Goodman); an exciting airplane incident; a very fitting ending.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Adjustment Bureau (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-adjustment-bureau-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-adjustment-bureau-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A well-made and unusual sci-fi about some humanoid super-beings that run
the world. They remain unexplained, and they attempt to get the Matt
Damon character (good job) to be American president. Part of achieving
that is getting him away from his favorite gal, and although they give
something of a flimsy excuse, it makes the plot interesting. That&#x27;s
despite that fact that the romance is overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tree of Life (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tree-of-life-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tree-of-life-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of wonderful editing and gorgeous shots, most especially
in the beginning... the first 20 minutes, just before the pre-historic,
beginning of life section. My favorite of these shots is the waterfall.
It&#x27;s amazing. Also, in those 20 minutes, I enjoyed the Sean Penn
moments the most... I don&#x27;t remember corporate environments shot (and
edited) that way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not much else to celebrate, unfortunately: Brad Pitt is miscast
(i.e. unconvincing), the movie is mostly boring and unbearably
meditative, and much of mutterings (prayers and thoughts) of the
characters unintelligible, like I&#x27;m supposed to fill in the blanks. I
also don&#x27;t know what the point of the entire exercise is, though I
liked the fact that the strict father wasn&#x27;t presented in a shallow
manner... he had sweet moments, and even apologized for his shitty
behavior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Prisoners (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/prisoners-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/prisoners-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugh Jackman gives his best performance I&#x27;ve seen, and none of the
others are lacking. The movie is also very well-made, and I could smell
the skill (and freshness) in the opening scenes, just before the girls
disappear. The rest of it remains interesting, despite the running
length of over 140 minutes. I would have preferred something shorter,
especially since the ending bits are not quite as impressive. The twist
was also a big let-down, with the (newly-revealed) villain unconvincing.
Also, some key plot points were left unexplained, or maybe I just missed
them. One example: why did the suspects keep quiet?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Red 2 (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/red-2-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/red-2-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot more enjoyable than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;red-2010&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it has one amazing
performance by Anthony Hopkins in a rather fitting role. Luckily his
talent wasn&#x27;t wasted here as was the case in the two super-hero movies,
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;thor-2011&quot;&gt;Thor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;thor-the-dark-world-2013&quot;&gt;Thor: The Dark World&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also enjoyed watching the Asian guy
(he looks lethal), as well as the romantic antics of the female assassin
(Helen Mirren) and his Russian lover.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot of the movie is complicated and some of the humor works (see
the Helen Mirren paying with her feet while unleashing her violence).
But the movie is too much of a fantasy, and is way too loud. Some of it
was good though, and my favorite was the first, in which the hero
escapes from some especially unfeeling government agent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Incendies (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/incendies-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/incendies-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very rough twist&#x2F;revelation happens near the end, and that alone makes
the whole movie worthy. It&#x27;s also well-made, well-written, and got
decent acting, my favorite being the lady that plays the twin daughter.
It is also one of those rare movies that let a tear escape from my
eyes... the bus deception incident.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie took things a little far by having this mother be an assassin.
Also, her old age make-up could be better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain Phillips (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-phillips-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-phillips-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever enjoy Tom Hanks performances, but this one was very
watchable, though his best moments are only at the very end, after his
rescue. I also enjoyed watching the lead of the pirates, which is a
rather unusual casting choice. He is also the most interesting character
in the movie, a villain that provides comfort for his victim, and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;caring-about-villains&quot;&gt;a
villain we get to care for&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One other special thing about the movie is the subject matter, which I
don&#x27;t remember ever seeing explored before in movies: modern-day ship
piracy. Another special thing is the attention to detail regarding the
cargo ship, which is also a rare sight. The direction is of decent
quality and so is the tension.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie could be shorter though, and the numerous attempts by the
title character to prevail are tiring. The movie also moves too quick
from Somalia to the seas... there is not enough exploration of the
background of our villains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Doubt (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/doubt-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/doubt-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Possessing some of the best works of cinematography and production
design ever, the movie also boasts some of the most intense dialogues
I&#x27;ve seen yet, and an amazing performance from Philip Seymour Hoffman
as a Catholic priest. His enemy is one of the most relentless characters
in movie history, played by a miscast Meryl Streep. Her lack of fear for
confrontation and her quick-to-act attitude are admirable, but her
brutality is rather unreasonable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Counselor (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-counselor-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-counselor-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The direction is very unusual, the performances are of high quality
(Brad Pitt is amazing, and so is Penélope Cruz, not to mention the guy
that played Hitler in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;downfall-2004&quot;&gt;Downfall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and the story gets more edgy as it
progresses. I need to see it again to understand it better... it&#x27;s
complex, and much of what&#x27;s going on is only implied.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Excision (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/excision-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/excision-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;skymovies.sky.com&#x2F;excision&#x2F;revie&quot;&gt;a good review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about this, a movie that starts with more
promise than it delivers. The imagery is provocative, but not really
shocking. The movie done and written quite well, complete with quality
performances, my favorite of which is that of the lead. She&#x27;s also damn
beautiful, though nearly as much as the gal across the street... wow!
The ending is a let-down... too unrealistic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked this bit in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.fearnet.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;review&#x2F;sundance-2012-excision-review&quot;&gt;another quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which will become relevant
one you are done watching:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...she&#x27;s quickly blossoming into quite the amateur surgeon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Funny Games (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/funny-games-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/funny-games-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lady playing wife gives an amazing performance, most visible in the
moments of mental torment and physical exhaustion. She&#x27;s also so damn
pretty, her and the rest of her family. Another good performance is the
almost comic one by the lead perpetrator, whose few moments of talking
with the audience (us) represent a rather daring directorial choice,
given the seriousness of the situation. It&#x27;s also a very welcome
choice. The direction is excellent: see how the aftermath of a great
loss is done, and see how touching the love between husband and wife is.
The pacing is slow at times without being boring for a moment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gangster Squad (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gangster-squad-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gangster-squad-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Mireille Enos, who plays the wife, gives a really nice performance. Sean
Penn, on the other hand, gives the worst of his career, perhaps due to
the shitty make-up and bad character development. The movie starts off
well, with the superbly-made heroic antics of the Josh Brolin character,
complete with excellent cinematography and production design. But soon
after, it feels like a failed attempt at an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;l-a-confidential-1997&quot;&gt;L.A. Confidential&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and got
unfunny humor and misguided romance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Iceman (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-iceman-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-iceman-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Shannon_(actor)&quot;&gt;Michael Shannon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gives an excellent and unusual performance as a
fearsome contract killer, in a movie with excellent cinematography and
production design, and excellent writing. Another notable performance is
that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ray_Liotta&quot;&gt;Ray Liotta&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, even though he plays one of his usual characters,
only this time I really enjoyed him, perhaps even more than in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;smokin-aces-2006&quot;&gt;Smokin&#x27;
Aces&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. There is not one other performance that is lacking, and even
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chris_Evans_(actor)&quot;&gt;Chris Evans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; helped by hiding his not-too-talented face behind a large
beard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In Time (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-time-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-time-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We here see a world where people stop physically aging when they reach
25 and have a year to live unless they get more (or less) time. Money is
replaced by time as currency, and the reason the setup is such is left
unexplained, though the hint given is population control. It also
appears as if the situation can&#x27;t be changed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This beautiful concept is fucked by a lazy plot and stupid casting
choices (the people were supposed to look 25). The best fun in the movie
can only be seen in the early scenes, but then the overly-courageous
acts and extra skills of the Justin Timberlake character were left
unexplained... lazy writing. Luckily it&#x27;s not boring, even to the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butler (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butler-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butler-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most shocking thing about this overrated bore is that it was made by
Lee Daniels, the same guy who made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;the most impressive movie made in
the last few years&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s fucking weird! It&#x27;s among the most
surprising things in all of my experiences watching movies. Not even a
wonderful actor like Forest Whitaker pulled off a decent performance.
He&#x27;s embarrassing even, though not as much as Oprah Winfrey, who was
supposed to be a quality actor, given her &lt;em&gt;Color Purple&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; performance
(though I haven&#x27;t seen that in over 10 years). Something must have gone
seriously wrong. Maybe it was a troubled production?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it&#x27;s not utter trash. I liked the concept of the heroic
activists being prepared for racist taunts, which was quite fresh. Not
that it was particularly well-made, but that it&#x27;s just something I
haven&#x27;t seen before in a movie. Another highlight is the character of
the younger brother of the activist at the dinner table, specifically
the &lt;em&gt;party&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; moment. It was beautiful. Sadly, not much else was. None of
the other performances were good (and I&#x27;m not exaggerating), and the
old-age make-up was even worse. Ridiculous!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Family (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-family-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-family-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The two kids are a lot more interesting than the parents in this dark
comedy about a troublesome family that finds itself under witness
protection. It&#x27;s well-made (and well-shot) but not very well-written.
The over-the-top violence imposed the each of the family members are
supposed to be funny, but fall flat, and I don&#x27;t like how their cruelty
is downplayed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also feel Robert De Niro, the guy that gave &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-movie-performances&quot;&gt;the best performance in
history&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, should have retired over a decade ago. He hasn&#x27;t done
anything worthy of his skills, and is not interesting enough to keep me
interested. Or maybe he&#x27;s just overrated, and incapable of doing
anything beyond his usual bad guy persona. He&#x27;s boring, though the
movie isn&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Stand Off (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/stand-off-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/stand-off-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice performance by Brendan Fraser as the lead, and an even better one
by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;David_O&amp;#x27;Hara&quot;&gt;the guy playing the villain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The film is quite enjoyable (not a
boring moment) and the romance beautiful. I don&#x27;t remember a woman
fearing her own child as is the case with mother of gangster. Good
direction and acting there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blogs.indiewire.com&#x2F;theplaylist&#x2F;review-stand-off-is-an-insufferable-comic-take-on-the-british-gangster-movie-20130221&quot;&gt;This quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was not as positive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Premium Rush (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/premium-rush-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/premium-rush-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of exciting street shots, a very interesting (and immensely
desirable) female lead, some quality performances (the villainous
detective most especially), and nice production design. The movie did
not also need the political sob story involving some child. The two
instances of rivalry were done well: that between the lead and the
co-worker, and between him and the police bicycle rider. The action is
over-the-top, and downplays the dangers these bicycle riders impose on
others, and on themselves. It could have been just as exciting had it
been more realistic I think.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Thor: The Dark World (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/thor-the-dark-world-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/thor-the-dark-world-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An improvement over &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;thor-2011&quot;&gt;the original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it has far superior visual effects
(the evil dark energy and the epic duels), a far more interesting
villain, and superior character design. Sadly, we are still stuck with
two very uninteresting characters: those played by Natalie Portman (the
stale love interest) and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kat_Dennings&quot;&gt;Kat Dennings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (the unfunny comic relief).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The History of Future Folk (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-history-of-future-folk-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-history-of-future-folk-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An unusual and somewhat dull movie which has the lead tell a the story
of his alien origins, a story so ridiculous it has people think is just
made-up as part of his entertainment set as a musician. This character
is played by a guy with an interesting face, a Jet Li lookalike, making
him a pleasure to eye. The other alien that later befriends him is fun
to watch, and the female police officer is pretty as fuck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Wolverine (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-wolverine-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-wolverine-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot better than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;x-men-origins-wolverine-2009&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it is even more unusual in that it
doesn&#x27;t feel like part of the &lt;em&gt;X-Men&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; franchise, both in terms of story
and direction. It starts off quite well, with decent family drama where
you wonder WTF&#x27;s goin&#x27; on. It proceeds to some intense gritty action,
and some cheesy romance, and finally gets a not-so-exciting ending. It
left me wishing there were more mutants, for what we have here isn&#x27;t
very interesting (the poison lady is curious, but she isn&#x27;t very
interesting, and neither is her powers).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of the performances are interesting, most especially the gal with
the deformed face, though she&#x27;s too much of a curiosity than an
essential character. The son of the dying man gets a commanding
performance, though the characterization is rather stale... done so
damn many times before. I am no fan of Hugh Jackman, but this one is his
best attempt at doing the title character so far. The design of the
giant samurai armor is amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish the cinematography and production design felt less stagey, and
the sounds less retarded (e.g. metallic sounds emanate from swords
cutting through human flesh).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dogtooth (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dogtooth-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dogtooth-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I kept waiting for an explanation of why the couple kept their kids
isolated from the world beyond the family. I was even more curious why
the father, a very unpleasant character, went to the trouble of
supplying the son with regular pussy. None of that is explained, sadly
(unless I missed it). This father character annoyed me most about the
violent lashing at this regular pussy at some point (I find such
arrogance unbearable). The earlier lashing was not as saddening since
the girl, the most rebellious of the three kids, happens to be an
asshole.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is well-made, and got unusual dialog, and a weird story. The
acting is all good as well, and so is character development.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Safety Not Guaranteed (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/safety-not-guaranteed-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/safety-not-guaranteed-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Decent humor and an interesting lead make this watchable. There is good
anticipation of whether or not the guy under study is a lunatic. The old
girlfriend is desirable (as is the lead), and the carefree boss gets
sweet at times, even if he is cardboard character. Weird small movie.
Loved the ending. Romance was done okay, even if it is too typical of
romantic comedies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Passion of Joan of Arc (1928)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-passion-of-joan-of-arc-1928/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-passion-of-joan-of-arc-1928/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A well-made and entertaining dark comedy with interesting performances.
The lead performance also brought pleasure to eye, though it was never
quite convincing. The character is admirable though: she maintained
courage despite the mental torture (threats, harsh accusations, and
deception), though I wish she should have said more... too often she
kept quite while questioned. The direction is powerful, and so is the
story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hunger Games: Catching Fire (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-catching-fire-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-catching-fire-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;More bearable than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-hunger-games-2012&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with amazing visual designs: check
the Rome-like arena and the city. Not much else is interesting, least of
which is the soppy romance. The twist is lack-lustre, and the leading
lady remains unconvincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>12 Years a Slave (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/12-years-a-slave-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/12-years-a-slave-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected a lot more, and got disappointed by the less-than-impressive
direction and script. Not even Chiwetel Ejiofor saves it, and he in fact
exposes his limitations as an actor, which is sad given I am something
of a fan... see him in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;redbelt-2007&quot;&gt;Redbelt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Four Brothers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; for example.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one interesting subplot is one involving the sex pet, whose fate is
less than desirable. Not that her performance is any excellent, nor her
scenes particularly well-made. She just happens to be in a rather unique
situation, and I like her face :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may end up the most overrated movie of the year. There&#x27;s not much
value in here. Find something else. If in a mood for some Black American
slavery stuff, check out the far superior &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mandingo-1975&quot;&gt;Mandingo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;goodbye-uncle-tom-1971&quot;&gt;Goodbye Uncle
Tom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;django-unchained-2012&quot;&gt;Django Unchained&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gravity (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gravity-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gravity-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very well-made, with good attention to detail, and a unique story-line.
The suspense is too much for my liking. I enjoyed performance of George
Clooney much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Upside Down (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/upside-down-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/upside-down-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It got a great concept (the most original I&#x27;ve seen in a while) and
great visuals. But after the novelty wears off about half-way through,
there&#x27;s pretty much nothing left. I enjoyed the performance of Timothy
Spall, but his character was not well-developed. None of the other
characters are given quality treatment either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rush (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rush-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rush-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the Niki Lauda character quite unusual (and curious), making it
the most interesting thing in the movie. The movie doesn&#x27;t have much
else going for it: I did not enjoy watching the portrayal of the rival
and his drama (same old boring playboy), and I am not a big fan of
racing cars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
