<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2007-movie/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Last King of Scotland (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-last-king-of-scotland-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-last-king-of-scotland-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The are three performances that stand out:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forest Whitaker gives &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;best-of-career-performances&quot;&gt;the best one of his career&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; playing the title
character. His is also a very well-developed character.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James McAvoy gives an excellent one as the advisor, though his
character is not very fresh... tis been done before.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kerry Washington is both a desirable and very capable actor, and
there isn&#x27;t a lack of those two qualities here.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is very well-made, complete with quality production design and
an interesting story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pan&#x27;s Labyrinth (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pan-s-labyrinth-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pan-s-labyrinth-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not very interesting, except for the scene with the child killer, which
is a showcase of visual mastery... one of the best (and most original)
character designs I&#x27;ve seen. I also enjoyed the moments with the faun
character, who also represents good character design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shortbus (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shortbus-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shortbus-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The characters in this movie express sexual desire to levels most people
are not brave enough to, which is a bit of a plus. The peformances are
of decent quality, but the level of eccentricity of some of the
characters not so kool. Sure they are respectable for pushing the
boundaries, but there is also that thing called taste&#x2F;sense:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what the fuck is up with the girl with the shitty hairstyle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the club owner (smart but not so interesting)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or the therapist, whose outburst was not at all realistic, nor is
her stupid belief (women cannot orgasm) believable, especially for
someone who deals with workings of the mind.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is like the makers wanted something profound, but lacked the writing
talent. The ending is boring and the movie pointless, except insofar as
to push the boundaries in blurring the distinction between porn and
not-porn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Beowulf (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/beowulf-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/beowulf-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this old-fashioned and take on fantasy heroism a lot more
first time I watched it, though I did find it pointless, and still do.
Even the lead villain isn&#x27;t as seductive. The animation could be
better, but the worst of it was the human faces. They should have made
it live-action, or better still, not made it at all. Or it just needed a
better writer. Some of the imagery was worthy of notice, especially the
water-on-skin effects. It was not ground-breaking though, at least to an
untrained eye like mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bourne Ultimatum (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-ultimatum-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-ultimatum-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If we ignore the more spectacular car chase&#x2F;crash, the movie is overall
lesser than the 2nd, but superior to the 1st of course. It&#x27;s not the
best because it feels like a mere rehash, and doesn&#x27;t bring much new to
celebrate, despite the fact the we get to know of Bourne&#x27;s past, but
even that is told in some badly-made flashbacks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie got camerawork and production design very similar to the 2nd
movie, with similar intensity fo story, except that I got a bit bored
(remember the rehashness of it). It&#x27;s kinda strange because I remember
praising this concluding episode as superior to the rest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia Stiles should not have been given a bigger role. She is not an
interesting enough actor. Even worse (worst performance in the trilogy)
is the guy playing the biker assassin. Other performances are decent
enough... nothing spectacular. Luckily, the last assassin here is
played quite well, better than any in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] One uncomfortable aspect of this movie is that Bourne
really takes too much physical punishment to continue going. It was
forgiveable in the previous 2 movies, but in here it&#x27;s way too much (he
experiences so many heavy car crashes, and then simply walks out of
then). It&#x27;s sad because the series has been as close to convincing as
action movies are allowed, and that added to the fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Apocalypto (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/apocalypto-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/apocalypto-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a bunch of movies that showcase primitive cultures, the kind
that wear skimpy clothes and use heavy body modification, and this one
is the best of them. There is also excellent casting and directing, and
an interesting story that&#x27;s spoiled by some plot holes:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how far can a human outrun a jaguar?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how close can a 30m+ waterfall be to an ocean?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how long can a human run with a wound that bad?.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back to the good stuff: The environment where the human
sacrifices take place is among the richest ever committed to screen, and
the silly traditions aren&#x27;t embarassingly executed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Munich (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/munich-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/munich-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s what I wrote over 3 years ago:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with superb-handling and wonderful acting, it lacks intrigue (bar
the memorable scene where the femme fatale gets uncomfortable
treatment), so I&#x27;m only left with great cinematography and excellent
sound.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;d like to take away the &amp;quot;it lacks intrigue&amp;quot; part. It&#x27;s more
accurate to say it&#x27;s not intriguing enough. That&#x27;s because it was fun
watching the planning, buying info, and even the executions themselves.
Also, I choose just two performances as outstanding (Geoffrey Rush and
Daniel Craig); Eric Bana (playing the lead character) isn&#x27;t interesting
enough to be alone on screen. The movie gets dull after that femme
fatale incident due to the slower pacing. As realistic as the story
feels, the info salesmen were rather romanticised. I found the aging
leader, papa, a mere caricature. Not fresh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Fracture (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/fracture-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/fracture-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A notable element from this movie is the performance of the lead by Ryan
Gosling, who is sort of like a hit from nowhere since I haven&#x27;t seen
him before. Yet another notable element is the sophisticated and
humorous dialogue, though the script itself falls short near the end,
incapable of justifying various activities done by the villain.
Fortunately there wasn&#x27;t any formulaic non-sense common in movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story proved a bit sketchy and not so brilliant on second look,
while Rosamund Pike remains a goddess, while Anthony Hopkins pulls off a
great and effortless performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-review-2007&quot;&gt;first review (2007)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching this spectacle, the greatest so far this year, I kept
wondering which has superior visual effects if compared to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;pirates-of-the-caribbean-3&quot;&gt;Pirates of
the Caribbean 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It wins in terms of spectacle due to the far larger
activity going on all over the screen and it&#x27;s really unbelieavable how
seemingly no cash was spared, and it&#x27;s only since King Kong (2005) have
I been so overwhelmed by sheer size. Interestingly, I can&#x27;t single out
a favorite effect because they are all over the place (the scorpion
battle, the city battle, the transformers).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead performer is quite impressive and so is the mother, who
provides among the movie&#x27;s finest comic moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the movie isn&#x27;t pretentious (say the ridiculous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;spider-man-3-2007&quot;&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)
about its seriousness, feeling like a mere crowd-pleaser, and what a
crowd-pleaser it is! This fact allows one to enjoy it pretty well,
disregarding plot-holes and other deficiencies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;second-review-2008&quot;&gt;second review (2008)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This revisit turned into a frustrating exercise since I noted too many
compositing errors, unimpressive production design (especially for such
an expensive movie), worse cinematography (unbearable and overdone
lighting), and cardboard characters, none being believable. This is not
even mentioning some really bad casting choices (Anthony Anderson
playing the best computer cracker; the entire heroic soldier crew).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformations are overwhelming (as if that&#x27;s supposed to be an
advantage) and there&#x27;s way more action than necessary... I could not
keep up. Worse still, none of it is believable (e.g. we get our nerdy
hero getting serious physical pounding without getting hurt, or acting
all calm while a multi-ton machine falls very close-by).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, the entire concept is god-damn silly, but then &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
managed to get away with its own silly concept (machines &#x27;farming&#x27;
human energy... WTF!) by being better elsewhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Spider-Man 3 (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/spider-man-3-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/spider-man-3-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this one with greater expectations than it managed to fulfill,
emerging to be worse than the first two in the series. I was hoping for
ground-breaking visual effects, only to end up preferring those of
&lt;em&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
