<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2006-movie/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dead Man (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dead-man-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dead-man-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A bizarre and sleep-inducing work, this dark comedy has its moments:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene with Billy Bon Thornton is fun to watch, due to the
idiotic behavior of his character and its companions. It is my
favorite in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character of the native American feels more of a guardian angel
than anything real. One feels a sense of comfort having him around,
and his bravery commendable, not to mention his kindness. He is the
most unusual character of them all, or should I say the most
unconvincing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character of Crispin Glover is also bizarre. He gives a very
good performance, brief as it is.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know what the fuck&#x27;s up with the story though, what the point
of it all is. Why do people make movies like this? It does however
possess the honor of having an entire book written about it, by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;best-movie-critic-jonathan-rosenbaum&quot;&gt;the
great Jonathan Rosenbaum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A History Of Violence (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-history-of-violence-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-history-of-violence-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Well-made and interesting, but pointless. Maria Bello is as good as
usual while Virgo Mortensen gives a poor performance. The kid playing
their son is impressive, and so was the brutal duo, who ended up trying
to rob the wrong guy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lord of War (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lord-of-war-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lord-of-war-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Scathing, well-made satire; excellent and exciting during its first
half, and a slow-down in the second, with the usual consequences thing,
not to mention the annoying Jared Leto character. If only the movie kept
the delicious pace, and if only it kept the length at 100 minutes or
so...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Eamonn Walker&#x27;s best role, even though his performance didn&#x27;t
excite me as much as it did first time around; It was my most favorite
from among &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;2006-movie-review&quot;&gt;the movies I saw first time in 2006&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pi (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pi-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pi-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Darren Aronofsky, the director, uses the same unsettling camerawork and
editing style he later used in (the superior) &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream-2000&quot;&gt;Requiem for A Dream&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
with the aid of superb dialog and acting, notably Sean Gullette in a
lead role and Mark Margolis who plays the friend, and gives my most
favorite of his performances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some unexplained things (e.g. the bleeding man, the brain),
unless it is a way of showing the mental suffering the lead character is
experiencing (&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;stackexchange.com&#x2F;a&#x2F;9540&#x2F;105&quot;&gt;an explanation was given&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). The movie starts
a lot better than it ends, and although made by a stylistic
master-director, there was at least two sleep-inducing moments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Perfume (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/perfume-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/perfume-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The impression from the first viewing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disgusting scenery and painful story found in this one-of-a-kind
movie reminds me of &lt;em&gt;Delicatessen&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, only amplified, and treated with
far superior skill, and a more engaging storyline. The sort of emotion
this sort of movie instilled in me is quite rare, and has similar
intensity to what is found in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;apocalypto-2006&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apocalypto&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The costume design is
perhaps even better than what can be seen in the (lesser) &lt;em&gt;Pirates of
the Caribbean&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impression from a revisit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perfume&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; remains magnificent but got a few warts (sleep-inducing,
disorganised and overlong storyline, smallish events which don&#x27;t
serve the story, a very uninteresting Alan Rickman and an unconvincing
daughter) which can&#x27;t effectively be hidden by its strengths (an
original story, superb costume design and direction, superb lead
performer, great cast).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all know, each repeat viewing of a movie is a different
experience, and in the case of this movie, each revisit proves I&#x27;ve
overrated the movie the previous time. In this case, for example, I
didn&#x27;t find the costumes that great, the lead performance so super, the
direction so laudable, nor the cast so great. Sure it remains way better
than your average movie, but the novelty just wears off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dogville (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dogville-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dogville-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s hard to imagine the movie having as much impact had it been told
in a more conventional way (there entire thing is done on a small stage,
which doesn&#x27;t change throughout it&#x27;s entire 3-hour run, except at the
very end). It&#x27;s an effective experiment that proves that, with good
directorial skill, a movie experience can be satisfying with almost no
budget. I however expect that only serious movie buffs would watch the
entire thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first viewing of this was among the most impactful I&#x27;ve had of any
movie, to a point where I called a masterpiece. A revisit wasn&#x27;t so
kind though because of diminished impact. I still love the narrator&#x27;s
style of storytelling (told like a children&#x27;s fable). I found the
character of the philosopher quite annoying (and I&#x27;m sure that was the
intention), a character developed and performed similar to that of the
scientist in Battlestar Galactica tv series (the one made in the
2000&#x27;s). There is not one other character that is interesting, that is
if we ignore James Caan. The movie is also frustratingly long and I&#x27;m
curious why it was made (why portray such brutality), and even more
curious, why was the annoying philosopher character added.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I once hailed this as a masterpiece, and though it remains excellent,
the emotional punch it carries has been reduced. The movie feels like
it&#x27;s cut short even though it&#x27;s nearly 2 hours long. I enjoyed the
story so much, with it&#x27;s multiple alternate-reality stories concept,
that I wanted more and more of it. It&#x27;s done quite well, but none of
the stories are given enough treatment, resulting in the movie feeling
too short.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7-year old boy gives one of the best child performances I&#x27;ve seen
yet, but the movie&#x27;s best is that by the fat friend in college, while
my most favorite was the religious guy who sharing a cell with the lead
character. It was quite interesting to have the actors take different
roles in each alternate reality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have preferred superior camerawork, not the shitty tv-like one,
which was most evident in the very first scene.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Butterfly_Effect#Reception&quot;&gt;negative critical reception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; surprising.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I later found out the version I watched on a revisit was an
alternate ending, one that ends with a suicide. I don&#x27;t think the
de-facto one would have made the movie much better&#x2F;worse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
