<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2013-movie/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Django Unchained (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/django-unchained-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/django-unchained-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of humor, brutality (the suffering of the slaves is just too
intense), violence, and heroism. The movie has the rare quality of being
entertaining throughout, a feat more impressive given the movie&#x27;s
running length of over 150 minutes. Tarantino also decided to go a bit
lazy on us (as he did with the &lt;em&gt;Kill Bill&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies) by sprinkling fantasy
over his script, where for example we find the heroic Django
highly-skilled with a gun, without a lot of training. Another example is
the number of men the DiCaprio character has at his command, an excuse
to spill liters of blood, as well as showcase the Django excellence. If
only the lead was a better (or more interesting) actor than Jamie Foxx.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite (and best) scene is one where the great Tarantino appears. I
find it the best directed of all, even though there are more showy and
complex ones. My favorite performance there is the oldest of the white
guys, played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Parks&quot;&gt;Michael Parks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also enjoyed watching the guys in the
cage, not to mention Tarantino himself (good actor this guy). As a
sidenote, it seems he was not comfortable sayig the word &lt;em&gt;nigga&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,
resorting to &lt;em&gt;blackie&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Final Destination 5 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-5-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/final-destination-5-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked a few things:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bridge sequence is a showcase of decent visual effects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The massage lady gives a quality performance, though brief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The homage paid to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;final-destination-2000&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the franchise is very
welcome, almost iconising it&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lead actor is damn beautiful and also not boring&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is sadly not offering anything new, and the sudden murderous
behavior of one of the survivors serious stupid... very unconvincing. I
did like the performance of Tony Todd, though it was laughably
creepy... stupid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>MirrorMask (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mirrormask-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mirrormask-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very effective alternative to sleeping pills, but filled with curious
works of art, and some interestingly bizarre character designs. It is
pretty much pointless, but it was sort of interesting to watch the
super-cute gal go about her dreamy adventures. Of the creatures, none
was as annoying as the human-cat hybrids, none as scary as the bird-ape
hybrids, and none as original as the floating giants. I cannot remember
creatures as saddening as these giants. They alone make the entire movie
worth watching.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Now You See Me (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/now-you-see-me-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/now-you-see-me-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A ridiculous plot twist (I do not mind being fooled, but this is going
too far), some smart-ass characters (I don&#x27;t mind such, but this also
goes too far, or maybe they are just not well-written), and an
uninteresting back-story stop this one from being more than a cheap
fantasy-thriller. Luckily it&#x27;s very entertaining, and got decent
performances, not to mention an extra-desirable police lady. My favorite
performance is the lady who gets hypnotized in an early scene. She&#x27;s
incredible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Elysium (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/elysium-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/elysium-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is an entertaining movie, but lacks a well-developed story and
characters. Not even the acting is satisfactory, bar that of Matt Damon
(lead character) and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;William_Fichtner&quot;&gt;William Fichtner&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (his boss). The actions of the
violent villains are not justified, and so are those of the Jodie Foster
villain. The leader of the revolutionry criminals is very unconvincing.
The movie also feels rushed. It&#x27;s a pity because it starts well, and is
well-made (the director made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;district-9-2009&quot;&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; after all), complete with
great visual effects and action direction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Star Trek Into Darkness (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/star-trek-into-darkness-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/star-trek-into-darkness-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept of a spaceship that can double as a submarine is
interesting, but there&#x27;s not much else to celebrate in this otherwise
not-boring movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Goodbye Bafana (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-bafana-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-bafana-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013&quot;&gt;Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; led me to check this one out,
whose existence I&#x27;ve been ignoring for a few years now. Sadly, I have
to say I didn&#x27;t miss much... it&#x27;s about as dull as they come, and
none of the elements are worthy of celebration (cinematography,
direction, acting, script, ...). The concept of exploring the life of
an icon through someone else&#x27;s eyes is something I appreciated about
&lt;em&gt;Cry Freedom&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but then it helped if that someone else is actually
interesting (a heroic journalist). It&#x27;s not the case here (a
sympathetic prison guard). As for the icon in question (Nelson Mandela),
it doesn&#x27;t look like much effort was expended really. Not even an
attempt to make him look older, beyond some white shit on the actor&#x27;s
hair. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also not much effort on the part of the two actors to speak
Xhosa (a major language in South Africa) in a half-convincing manner.
Most of the world won&#x27;t notice of course, but it still does matter...
it&#x27;s embarassing if you have any passing familiarity of the language.
Lazy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mandela-long-walk-to-freedom-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good cinematography, production design, sound, and performance of the
lady playing Zinzi. Horrible old-age make-up (check mom of Mandela, or
worse still, check the Mandela face when Zinzi visits him in jail...
embarrassing and unwatchable). Also, I didn&#x27;t see Mandela in the lead
performance (Idris Alba is not a very good performer, and is not
credible in the role).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was very rushed, and it leaves one feeling too many details
were left out (there was no mention of Oliver Tambo or Albert Luthuli,
for example), and some very significant moments merely given passing
attention (Sharpeville and Soweto killings, for example). One thing that
could have helped is narration, or even flashbacks. One can argue that
you can&#x27;t fit everything in a single movie, but that would be an
excuse... I&#x27;ve seen biopics in which feel like they do justice to a
legend, recent examples being &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-iron-lady-2011&quot;&gt;The Iron Lady&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;lincoln-2012&quot;&gt;Lincoln&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pacific Rim (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pacific-rim-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pacific-rim-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For a movie this expensive, I found none of the visual effects
impressive. Not even the designs, both creature and mechanical, deserve
applause. The battles were entertaining, but too erratic to keep track
of what&#x27;s goin on. The story concept is retarded, making it a blatant
excuse to put giant robots on screen who didn&#x27;t happen to be
&lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I also wish there was an explanation for the whole
thing, beyond the too-brief and nonsensical alien invasion story. Not
one performance was beyond average, nor was any of the humor effective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is there anything to celebrate here? Well... it&#x27;s not boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Man of Steel (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/man-of-steel-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/man-of-steel-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The visual design is amazing, and it made sense seeing that it was Zack
Snyder at the top, the same director who brought us the visual
masterpiece that is &lt;em&gt;300&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. The movie has a weird feel to it, being such
a dark (and dull) re-imagining of the world&#x27;s most recognizable comic
superhero. It has incredible visual effects, some of which represents
the most epic hand-to-hand combat sequences ever put on screen. The
Superman suit looks amazing!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The villain (Zod) performance is very fitting, and so is the lead
(Superman). I wish the reporter lady died at some point, or at least not
placed in situations so dangerous. Regardless, it&#x27;s also a good
performance. I wish they had cast different people in place of Kevin
Costner and Russell Crowe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>World War Z (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/world-war-z-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/world-war-z-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The family-focus thing is boring, and so is the overly-heroic antics of
the not-so-interesting lead. The story also feels incomplete, and I&#x27;ve
seen superior treatment of the subject matter (of pandemics)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive note, I have never seen zombies so vicious. Also, the
movie is not boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Escape From Planet Earth (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/escape-from-planet-earth-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/escape-from-planet-earth-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is reasonably entertaining, the animation is sophisticated, and
visual design is of good quality, but it suffers from relying too much
on recycled material, most notably from &lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;megamind-2010&quot;&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I must not fault it too much for its direction, which is
also typical of so many expensive 3D-animated movies, including the
above-mentioned ones. Even the character design is not fresh, though I
did like one character... the giant gal. She is also not an original
concept (see Eva in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;igor-2008&quot;&gt;Igor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), but then again I&#x27;m a sucker for misfits
like this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Serbian Film (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-serbian-film-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-serbian-film-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Less shocking than I expected, given how notorious it is. It&#x27;s also not
badly-made, and the story not so bad, though it would be nice to know
what the point of it all is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Adventures Of Tintin: The Secret Of The Unicorn (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-adventures-of-tintin-the-secret-of-the-unicorn-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-adventures-of-tintin-the-secret-of-the-unicorn-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The chase sequence in the Arab city is among the most complex action
sequences I have seen in any movie. This isn&#x27;t praise... &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;overly-complex-action-sequences&quot;&gt;I&#x27;m not a
fan of such excess&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and this must have been seriously expensive. The
rest of it is moderately interesting, and the animation highly-detailed,
and at times highly-sophisticated. It did not, however, result in any
wow moment, but I appreciate the one detail of the Captain&#x27;s convincing
eyes near the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Warrior (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/warrior-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/warrior-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The two toughest guys, the brother and the Russian guy, are scary as
fuck. The military back-story felt a little tired, and if anything, just
made the movie longer. It was done quite well though, so am not
complaining (much).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The teacher guy gives a very nice performance, and so is the wife. Nick
Nolte (the father character) does the usual, boring, business-as-usual
performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion feels far-fetched, with the predictable-ness that is all
too common in sports movies, but the entire thing is very well-made and
has real nice fight choreography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lincoln (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lincoln-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lincoln-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very well-made, with solid dialog. This dialog (and script) is also
unusual, an example being the opening scene which, though interesting,
felt like an attempt to be different. It did work for sure, since I
enjoyed it enough to think the movie was going to end up excellent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story focuses on the greatest accomplishment of Abraham Lincoln, a
man who I have, for a long time, greatly admired. One thing that&#x27;s
strange is that this guy appears to be just one of the guys,
distinguishing himself only through his smarts when he speaks. It also
doesn&#x27;t help that there is no visible security surrounding him to
indicate he is indeed the most powerful person in a country of millions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Olympus Has Fallen (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/olympus-has-fallen-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/olympus-has-fallen-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is unique in that movies showing The White House being attacked are
very rare. I can only remember one in fact, &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I also
saw this concept explored only once elsewhere... one of the seasons of
&lt;em&gt;24&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (a favorite of mine). The amount of violence is quite unexpected,
and very sudden, though it could have went even further (e.g. killing
son of president). The overall movie, however, feels... inadequate. It
lacks interesting performances, and the acts of the villains are left
pretty much unexplained. The pro-American stance, &amp;quot;we will emerge
victorious no matter what&amp;quot;, is intensely annoying, though not to the
levels of &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Smeagol&#x2F;Gollum is among the legendary movie characters, and I felt he
was a welcome addition to the movie. He&#x27;s as annoying as usual, but I
did like the faces he made during the game he played with the title
character, which I think were more varied&#x2F;complex than he had in &lt;em&gt;The
Lord of the Rings&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; trilogy. I also enjoyed the character of the
eccentric animal-lover wizard. The trolls (ugly, disgusting giants)
represent great character design and so do the orcs, complete with their
wolves. Pity none of it is actually new. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;overly-complex-action-sequences&quot;&gt;I dislike the excessive
complexity of the battle scene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;... serious waste of money and effort. I
also hate it when characters go through way too much physical pounding,
as in when the rock giants fight (a ridiculous and unexplained moment),
and the Dwarf escape.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Iron Man 3 (2013)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/iron-man-3-2013/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/iron-man-3-2013/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For my most anticipated movie of this year, this was
less-than-impressive. I did not like seeing Tony Stark having impressive
physical abilities (which was excused by some evidence of martial arts
training), or the uninteresting idea of flaming villains (though the
Pepper entrance was fun), or the whole story in general. Felt like mere
opportunism (milking the franchise), and the abilities of the suit keep
growing more and more, to ludicrous levels: In the second movie, the
portable suit idea was kool, and so was the &lt;em&gt;magnetic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; one in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-avengers-2012&quot;&gt;The
Avengers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The remote-driven one in this third one is also a nice touch,
but when it gets to the point of its individual parts flying themselves,
I get to wish the filmmakers put a reasonable limit to the fantasy.
Also, what&#x27;s with the boy genius thing? What&#x27;s the chances of
accidentally meeting such? Are the writers so untalented?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still a fun movie, but it makes me miss the freshness of the
first movie and the villain of the second; apart from being
unconvincing, the primary one here, played by Guy Pearce, is also not
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Devil&#x27;s Double (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/devil-s-double-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/devil-s-double-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one has the special distinction of having a body double being the
lead character, something I haven&#x27;t seen before. It&#x27;s just sad that
the performance (all them actually) isn&#x27;t so good, and neither is the
story and direction. It&#x27;s a second-rate production.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dirty Pretty Things (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dirty-pretty-things-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dirty-pretty-things-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exposing the shit life of being an illegal immigrant (and the associated
poverty, where people go as far as selling own body parts). I watched
this due to the appearance of Chiwetel Ejiofor, who plays the lead
character. The character development is pretty good (check the friend
that works at the morgue, or the guy infected by some sexually
transmitted disease).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kinky Boots (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kinky-boots-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kinky-boots-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only due to the presence of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chiwetel_Ejiofor&quot;&gt;Chiwetel Ejiofor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who
provides what&#x27;s easily the movie&#x27;s most interesting performance. The
movie&#x27;s climax is rather outrageous, and bordering on embarrassing. The
movie remains a worthy addition to those which criticize oppression
based on gender. This Chiwetel guy is also kinda pretty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Redbelt (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/redbelt-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/redbelt-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a nice find. I bumped onto it by accident. The first scene got
me sold (gritty, with good performances, especially the amazing Chiwetel
Ejiofor, as well as good direction). It does not disappoint throughout,
and it&#x27;s amazingly unpredictable. I wish it could have been longer,
with more of the loose ends tied.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Savages (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/savages-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/savages-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is entertaining throughout its entire 140+ minute run-time, but it
feels like a desperate attempt to be trendy&#x2F;stylish. See for example
going for the gorgeous Salma Hayek as lead villain, or the three-some
thing. Brutality is fine in movies (scary shit keeps me on
edge-of-seat), but the rape scene was just not needed. Anyways, this
isn&#x27;t serious film-making.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Goodbye Uncle Tom (1971)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-uncle-tom-1971/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/goodbye-uncle-tom-1971/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The most brutal slavery movie I&#x27;ve seen yet, though peppered with humor
all over the place: it&#x27;s a dark comedy&#x2F;satire, which is a rather daring
approach considering the subject material. It&#x27;s interesting to note the
cruelty Black people here face, which isn&#x27;t better than that of farm
animals. Makes me feel guilty for eating meat, much like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rogerebert.com&#x2F;reviews&#x2F;farewell-uncle-tom-1972&quot;&gt;Roger Ebert
makes me feel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for calling this movie good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish more effort should have been made to make the blood more
convincing. The weirdness of the final scenes, those shot in modern
days, isn&#x27;t welcome either. They are too eccentric and meaningless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Henry: Portrait of a Serial Killer</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/henry-portrait-of-a-serial-killer/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/henry-portrait-of-a-serial-killer/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very enjoyable story with some very interesting performances, most
notably that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tom_Towles&quot;&gt;Tom Towles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who plays a rather disgusting character,
Otis. AFAIR, this is the only one of his performances I ever enjoyed,
and he&#x27;s just perfect. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Rooker&quot;&gt;Michael Rooker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is also a joy to watch, and
despite his incredible cruelty, remains a guy we all care for, perhaps
due to his care for the (delightful) leading lady.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Town (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-town-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-town-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Well-directed robbery scenes and well-written story, but nothing really
new. I liked the nun costumes, and loved performance of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Jeremy_Renner&quot;&gt;Jeremy Renner&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish a different movie title was chosen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cleanskin (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cleanskin-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cleanskin-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This would have been excellent had it not dwelled so much on the
terrorist guy. I did find his appearance refreshing at first (a fresh
and beautiful face, and a solid performance), but he&#x27;s simply not lead
character material. This is unlike the Sean Bean character, who gives a
very fitting character and performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first several moments are entrancing, and compete favorably in terms
of execution (and grit) against far more expensive productions like
those in the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Bourne_(film_series)&quot;&gt;Bourne series&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one weak spot in the movie is the beheader character. He was
supposed to be menacing and heartless, but he looks more fit for a
lesser movie, and the moment involving the baby was simply needless.
Luckily there is no shortage of superb acting, most notably from the
lady in charge, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Charlotte_Rampling&quot;&gt;Charlotte Rampling&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Thaw (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-thaw-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-thaw-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very edgy take on existential risk, this time the villain being a
parasite, which is a fresh break from the usual global war or virus.
Watching it, I thought of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;contagion-2011&quot;&gt;Contagion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (virus), an overall superior
movie, which was on a far grander scale (and budget). But this one is
more unsettling given it&#x27;s various horror movie elements, except
handled with far greater skill than horror movies normally get.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All performances are of at least decent quality, my favorite being that
of Val Kilmer. He was always good, but he seems to get better with age
(see him in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;felon-2008&quot;&gt;Felon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). I also liked the Asian gal and the Black guy (an
unusual performance, and a fresh face).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Freelancers (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/freelancers-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/freelancers-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My brother trashed this one, so I watched anticipating the badness, but
it just didn&#x27;t come. Sure 50 Cent (playing Jonas) struggles to speak,
but I thought he is a formiddable figure enough to forgive the lack of
talent. The rest of the performances are pretty good, but I&#x27;m tired of
watching the no-longer-interesting Robert De Niro. The character
development is also of good quality, and was best expressed when Jonas&#x27;
friends were shown around on their first day at work. The movie did feel
rushed though, and I was actually hungry for more of the racist guy. The
direction is very edgy, keeping me tense for a large portion of the
movie. The storyline is also unusual, and the middle-aged lady totally
edible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Drag Me to Hell (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/drag-me-to-hell-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/drag-me-to-hell-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If we ignore certain arbitrary and stupid happenings, this movie is
quite well-made and has some decent dialog. It also feels fresh,
especially in the first half. It&#x27;s also the scariest movie I&#x27;ve seen
in a few years (if memory serves well), even though some of the scares
use tired techniques like loud sounds and sudden appearances of scary
figures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish the lead could have been chosen for her talent instead of her
cuteness level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Payback: Straight Up (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/payback-straight-up-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/payback-straight-up-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the most extensive Director&#x27;s Cut I&#x27;ve seen yet. There is so
much that is different:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most regretful is the absence of the Kris Kristofferson character,
whose role of head of The Outfit is replaced by a female voice. This
itself isn&#x27;t so bad, if we ignore that Kris was amazing to watch,
most especially the moment he first appeared on screen (amazing
direction).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one moment of domestic abuse that is rather hard to
swallow. I thought it was quite daring (and surprising), especially
because a character we are supposed to like is the perpetrator. This
moment alone makes it understandable why it was edited out.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending is a lot different and more involved (and perhaps a bit
over-the-top), but superior overall.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two of the bodyguards were totally removed from the original cut,
which is rather sad for they given wonderful performances (they look
mean as fuck). I am referring to the two who drive the Val Resnick
character about.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could be wrong, but I felt like there were more shots of the
city&#x27;s environment, which makes me appreciate the great production
design both movies display. Wonderful.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first scene from the earlier movie, the one in which Potter is
getting bullets removed from his body, is missing. It&#x27;s among my
favorite scenes, and displays very well the darkness the movie
explores, complete with a curious medical practitioner.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lead character&#x27;s voice-over is missing, and was actually quite
good. This version proves it wasn&#x27;t essential though.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I find &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-1999&quot;&gt;the earlier release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; superior, but not by a big margin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Silent Hill: Revelation (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-revelation-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/silent-hill-revelation-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Pyramid_Head&quot;&gt;Pyramid Head&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is back, this time with someone tough enough to fight
him. This someone is the superbly-designed blade-headed slasher
character, known as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Missionary_(film)&quot;&gt;The Missionary&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (and obviously deserving of a
better name). This is among the most impressive creature&#x2F;character
designs I&#x27;ve yet seen in movies, and nearly as innovative as Mr. Head,
and arguably more dangerous, given her speed. The murderous &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;silenthill.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nurse&quot;&gt;nurses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are
also back, this time even more glorious than before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, there is nearly nothing else to celebrate... the direction is
quite bad (deceptive and erratic camerawork and editing with annoying
overuse of the tired trademark of horror movies... loud sounds). The
leading lady, and his boyfriend, are not interesting. Sean Bean is a
good actor, but is seriously miscast, as he was in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;silent-hill-2006&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
There&#x27;s lots of meh dialog, but I really did love the leading lady&#x27;s
moment in the classroom, which is something I&#x27;ve never seen before in
movies. But because the script isn&#x27;t solid, her attitude (and strength
of character) was left unexplained, and is simply over-the-top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Point Blank (1967)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/point-blank-1967/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/point-blank-1967/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you look past the ugliness of having been made in 1967 (awkward
direction and acting), it actually is interesting. This is partly with
the help of the lead, Lee Marvin (not exactly a good performance, but an
interesting one nevertheless), and partly with the help of his
character, due to his relentless pursuit for the money taken from him.
The flashbacks are badly made, complete with horrible editing. The scene
where his gal unleashes violence against him is memorable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was led to this after finding out it&#x27;s based on the same material as
the later &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;payback-1999&quot;&gt;Payback&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a far superior take.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What&#x27;s Eating Gilbert Grape (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/what-s-eating-gilbert-grape-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/what-s-eating-gilbert-grape-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Answer involves 2 challenges:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with a close relative suffering from extreme obesity.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Living with another close relative, suffering from mental
retardation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the movie important, even though it&#x27;s not especially good.
The romance, or rather the gal (the sort of character that is Juliette
Lewis&#x27; now-dated trademark), is not interesting, and most everything
else that happens (e.g. the cheating wife episode) just feels random and
needless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however like Crispin Glover&#x27;s performance and I wish he was given
more screen time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>John Carter (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/john-carter-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/john-carter-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre story (powerful beings screw around with affairs of entire
planets), and a hero with unexplained powers and flashbacks (unless I
missed the explanation). I do, however, appreciate superb character
design of the four-arm humanoids, even though their look and behavior is
similar to that of the giants of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;avatar-2009&quot;&gt;Avatar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hotel Transylvania (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hotel-transylvania-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hotel-transylvania-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing fresh here as I expected, judging by the trailer. There is also
that annoying and all-too-common thing of someone lying and later
regretting and apologising in public. Movie is shallow too, and each
character recycled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did like some of the dance sequences though (regardless of the badness
of the music), and I thought the dirty chef character was very
well-animated, and is a showcase of quality character design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Marley and Me (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/marley-and-me-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/marley-and-me-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing of note is the care regarding the impressive performance of
that dog; the training involved must have been quite involved. It&#x27;s
amazing. The movie&#x27;s best moment, though, is the fast-paced scene in
which the lead character narrates a summary of his writings (he is
newspaper columnist). I thought it was quite innovative, complete with
fun content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond embracing pets, I thought the whole excercise was pointless. I
kept wondering, &amp;quot;Is this it? You sure this is all this movie is
about?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Skyfall (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/skyfall-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/skyfall-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is overall a disappointing experience, considering I watched with
anticipation, given its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;quantum-of-solace-2008&quot;&gt;solid predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I however have to give
kudos to Daniel Craig&#x27;s befitting performance. I liked also the first
chase scene, which must have the most daring motorbike stunts I have yet
seen in movies, not to mention an unexpected ending. Most of the rest of
the movie does not live to the expectations set by that opening. The
story is not good either, nor the villain interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In Bruges (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-bruges-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-bruges-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far better than the more expensive and colorful later work of this
talented director, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-psychopaths-2012&quot;&gt;Seven Psychopaths&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Great camerawork, enjoyable
acting (including even from Colin Farrel, which must be my most favorite
of his career), superb script (and dialog), a gorgeous and intensely
desirable gal, unusual storyline, and, and... what a gem?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a bit of a lull partway through it, but soon after, the fun
continues, and builds up to an intense and unpredictable last act, which
does not feel rushed at all... it&#x27;s amazing. It&#x27;s also helped a lot
by the superb Ralph Fiennes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the above-mentioned movie, one can sense a work of a liberal
writer&#x2F;director, where there is also some mention (and elevation) of
inter-racial relationships, and condemnation of a racist character. More
importantly, there is an important character in a form of a dwarf (real
nice performance there, reminiscent of that of the superb &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Peter_Dinklage&quot;&gt;Peter
Dinklage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the excellent TV series, &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), though,
ironically, he is the racist in question (but later apologises for it).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Taken 2 (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/taken-2-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/taken-2-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A lame and desperate attempt to milk off the success of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;taken-2008&quot;&gt;the first&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It
did succeed though, but not artistically. It is a let-down in a number
of ways:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The classic silliness that is seen in too many action movies, like
leaving the hero unwatched for large periods of time, so as to give
him a chance to escape.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having inexperienced people perform miracles, like the supreme
driving skill of the daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lazy, overly-frantic editing technique that gives the illusion
that some hard-core action is taking place... the sort where you
cannot figure out exactly what is happening. You will often notice
continuity errors in such sequences.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The villain was also very uninteresting, and his utterances extremely
stupid and performance very unconvincing. A person at his level needs a
better script (or at least that is my idea of a high-ranking criminal).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I appreciated though is the great suspense the director
managed to pull off, especially during the first half. Also, I did not
find Liam Neeson as fearsome and convincing as the first time, but the
great efficiency of his character still impressed in a way, like when he
was guiding his daughter to find him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Seven Psychopaths (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/seven-psychopaths-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/seven-psychopaths-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite utterance from the movie:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hooker comes out of the bathroom in a beautiful red dress. She says,
&amp;quot;Would you like to make love? Or, should we have an intelligent
conversation instead? I&#x27;ve been reading a lot of Noam Chomsky lately;
I think he&#x27;s a marvel&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a very well-made dark comedy with some wonderful performances. My
favorites are &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tom_Waits&quot;&gt;Tom Waits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the Vietnamese psychopath. The latter also
happens to be the lucky guy who gets to experience some moments with
that one special hooker. I also loved the old lady in hospital, who also
happens to be gorgeous. Sam Rockwell, Christopher Walken, and Woody
Harrelson are impressive, but this is business-as-usual for them, so
nothing novel there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politically, the movie is important in that it does, in a rather subtle
way, condemn homophobia. It also promotes interracial romantic
relationships, which I always find beautiful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;in-bruges-2008&quot;&gt;The earlier movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, written and directed by the same person, is a
superior work of art in many ways, though not as funny.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube Zero (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-zero-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-zero-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A rather disappointing, and possibly last, sequel of the series. I
suspect, when the writers set out to explore the intrigue in the
preceding movies (more &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-1997&quot;&gt;the first&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, since &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-2-hypercube&quot;&gt;the second&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was just a
needless rehash), they did not actually have a solid idea how to explain
it... the actual purpose of the Cube. It is sad. Surely one could setup
brainstorming sessions about these things, especially if you are going
to spend a few million?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the execution in this case is not disgusting bad, and there is
okay acting, but the fascination is largely gone, and the excuse of an
explanation is merely a passing reference to patriotism and religion.
Also, the villain is not very impressive, despite a desperate attempt to
portray an eccentric evil character. It&#x27;s a far less successful attempt
than the a character he reminds me of: the genius scientist in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;afro-samurai-resurrection-2009&quot;&gt;Afro
Samurai: Resurrection&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube 2: Hypercube</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-2-hypercube/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-2-hypercube/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;cube-1997&quot;&gt;first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; had the advantage of freshness, and this one... well,
being a sequel can be real tough for movies, since they are often not
judged strictly as separate pieces of work, but rather something of a
continuation. That is, a movie can be superior technically (acting,
directing, writing) but still feel worse, due to lack of innovation&#x2F;loss
of novelty, or too much comparison with the first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one sequel feels like a desperate attempt at continuing the
intrigue. It does have better acting, but worse dialog (or at least, not
as much fun). It feels desperate because now the Cube is like way too
advanced, bringing in some rather unfamiliar physics concepts into play,
feeling too unrealistic. The ending is weird, leaving me with questions,
and me wonders if it was delibarate on the part of the filmmakers, or if
I simply am not smart enough to figure WTF&#x27;s happenin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cube (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cube-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cube-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It may be a B-movie, but it does get intriguing at times, with quality
bits of dialog here and there. My favorite moment is when the smart gal
explains to the cop the complexity of the calculation he tries to force
her to perform. Solid piece of performance there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst thing about the movie is the unexplained transformation into
villainy by one of the characters. Feels silly and desperate, as if the
writers were concerned the whole premise is not exciting enough, which
it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cloud Atlas (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cloud-atlas-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cloud-atlas-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre treat, far more enjoyable in its first half. Lots of
bad&#x2F;uninteresting performances, even from established actors like Halle
Berry, Tom Hanks, and Hugo Weaving. Lots of brutality, pointlessness,
and... what the fuck is the movie about?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the interview though, and it helps carry the movie along. I
enjoyed watching the guy asking the questions... decent performance
there. The guy rescuing the heroine is admirable too, though the action
he finds self in is just cartoony. Is this not supposed to be close to
reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some interesting quotables sprinkled all over the place. My
favorite is one uttered by a master composer after an attempt at a piano
by one apprentice:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must have misheard me! I said I had a melody, not a malady!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dredd (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dredd-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dredd-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not really a remake, nor even an alternative take, but more like &#x27;based
in the same universe&#x27;. Far smaller than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;judge-dredd-1995&quot;&gt;the 1995 movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and a lot
less ambitious (and a lot better, which was not a feat at all). Much
lower budget, and visibly so, as well as poorer visual design. Could do
with a better director&#x2F;producer combo. But, the story is actually pretty
decent, and the suspense well-executed. The movie could do with a better
cast. The guy with the eyes does give a decent performance though, even
though he has too much of a Frodo character in LOTR (i.e. not fresh).
Also, the psychic lady is at least as pretty as she could act. The
villain, on the other hand, is not so convincing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should be grateful that I didn&#x27;t get to see lead actor&#x27;s untalented
face, though I was exposed to the embarassing mimicry of the Sylvester
angry mouth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
