<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tshepang logs</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tshepang.net/feeds/arts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tshepang.net/</id><updated>2013-09-29T18:46:48+02:00</updated><entry><title>top tracks: Fela Kuti</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-fela-kuti" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-29T18:46:48+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-09-29:top-tracks-fela-kuti</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="landmarks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 landmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lady&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Shakara&lt;/em&gt; - 1972)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confusion&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Confusion&lt;/em&gt; - 1975)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Igbe (Na Shit)&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Gentleman&lt;/em&gt; - 1973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Agreement&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;No Agreement&lt;/em&gt; - 1977)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shakara&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Shakara&lt;/em&gt; - 1972)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gentleman&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Gentleman&lt;/em&gt; - 1973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egbe Mi O&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Fela's London Scene&lt;/em&gt; - 1970)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fefe Naa Efe&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Gentleman&lt;/em&gt; - 1973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who No Know Go Know&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Everything Scatter&lt;/em&gt; - 1975)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just Like That&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Beast of No Nation&lt;/em&gt; - 1989)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pansa Pansa&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Underground System&lt;/em&gt; - 1992)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eko Ile&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Afrodisiac&lt;/em&gt; - 1973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alu Jon Jonki Jon&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Afrodisiac&lt;/em&gt; - 1973)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Man's Cry&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Live!&lt;/em&gt; - 1971)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water No Get Enemy&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Expensive Shit&lt;/em&gt; - 1975)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zombie&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Zombie&lt;/em&gt; - 1978)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teacher Don't Teach Me Nonsense&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Teacher Don't Teach Me Nonsense&lt;/em&gt;
-1986)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ikoyi Mentality Versus Mushin Mentality&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Why Black Man Dey Suffer&lt;/em&gt;
-1971)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="honorable-mention"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;honorable mention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Black Man Dey Suffer&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Why Black Man Dey Suffer&lt;/em&gt; - 1971):&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Not in the above lists because it gets spoiled by the vocals about halfway
through. The instruments are incredible, and almost the only saving
grace of the song, but they start to sound repetitive several minutes
in. The beginning parts of the song, including its vocals, would earn
this one a msterpiece had the rest been kept at that level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trouble Sleep Yanga Wake Am&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Roforofo Fight&lt;/em&gt; - 1972)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="top-tracks"></category></entry><entry><title>top musicians</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-musicians" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-29T18:46:48+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-09-29:top-musicians</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The best musicians in history,
created with the help of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/simple-point-system-for-rating-music"&gt;a simple point system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-fela-kuti"&gt;Fela Kuti&lt;/a&gt;, 27&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-burning-spear"&gt;Burning Spear&lt;/a&gt;, 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/letta-mbulu-vs-miriam-makeba"&gt;Letta Mbulu&lt;/a&gt;, 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-salif-keita"&gt;Salif Keita&lt;/a&gt;, 14&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-bob-marley"&gt;Bob Marley&lt;/a&gt;, 13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-fugees"&gt;Fugees&lt;/a&gt;, 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/letta-mbulu-vs-miriam-makeba"&gt;Miriam Makeba&lt;/a&gt;, 11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-the-roots"&gt;The Roots&lt;/a&gt;, 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For quite a while, this list of grandmasters consisted of just three
musicians (Fela Kuti, Bob Marley, and Burning Spear); I was only
surprised that the later entrants, Salif Keita and Letta Mbulu beat
mighty Bob, and that was based on just my thinking without actually
making a list of tracks. Intuition isn't always reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Person of Interest - Season 2 Episode 16</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/person-of-interest-season-2-episode-16" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-09-06:person-of-interest-season-2-episode-16</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of the series, &lt;em&gt;Person of Interest&lt;/em&gt;. There is much to
celebrate, among which is the wonderful portrayal of the brilliant
creator of the machine that (illegally) looks for patterns in society
so as to predict, with high certainty, the people will be involved in
violent crimes, either as victims or perpetrators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series' normal formula is that our heroic, bespectacled hero would
mention the details of the new person, and his very capable sidekick,
a former assassin, would go follow this person, to try avert the
impending crime. In the 16th episode of the 2nd season, however, this
formula isn't followed (by the camera). Instead we follow the person
who would be victim, and our heroes only appear midway through, like
they were secondary characters. It's beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love it when such breaks from normal routine occur, especially when
they are as well-made. Not to say this is the best episode of this
series so far (I can think of a few which were superior), nor was this
the first time such a break from normal routine occur (there were some
in the earlier episodes of the season), but it felt fresh enough to be
worth a mention in this blog of mine. What added to the excitement is
that it was the first time in the series that a so-called Relevant &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="#id2" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;
crime prevention was showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label" /&gt;&lt;col /&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;This means &lt;em&gt;relevant&lt;/em&gt; to (U.S.) national security. This is as
opposed to the sort solved by our heroes, which only involve
civil cases.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="tv"></category><category term="very-good"></category></entry><entry><title>Letta Mbulu vs. Miriam Makeba</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/letta-mbulu-vs-miriam-makeba" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-08-25:letta-mbulu-vs-miriam-makeba</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been wondering for years which of these two music legends is
superior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miriam Makeba&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 masterpieces (&lt;em&gt;Gauteng&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;A Luta Continua&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Welela&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 excellent works (&lt;em&gt;Mam Ndiyalila&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Meet Me At the River&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Goodbye
Poverty&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Jolinkomo&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Olili&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letta Mbulu&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 landmark (&lt;em&gt;Jikijela&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 masterpieces (&lt;em&gt;Not Yet Uhuru&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Nomathemba&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Zimkile&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 excellent works (&lt;em&gt;Music In the Air&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Ndi-Phendule&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Buza&lt;/em&gt;;
&lt;em&gt;I Need Your Love&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Maru a pula&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Kube&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/simple-point-system-for-rating-music"&gt;simple point system&lt;/a&gt; gives Makeba 11 points and Mbuli gets a
whooping 15. That's a scary number since it would mean &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-musicians"&gt;she's superior
to Salif Keita&lt;/a&gt; and just a point below Burning Spear! This I should
revisit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;/strong&gt;] Oh, and I'm sure there's a lot of Miriam's work that I
haven't trawled through. Either that or Miriam Makeba is, though
excellent, is overrated, since I suspect she becomes a common answer to
the question &amp;quot;who's the greatest female South African musician?&amp;quot;. That's
the answer that I also once had until I savoured much of Letta Mbulu's
work and walked away amazed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>'God of War' trilogy</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/god-of-war-trilogy" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-05-31:god-of-war-trilogy</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last time I played any of the 3 games from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/God_of_War_(series)"&gt;God of War&lt;/a&gt;
trilogy was nearly 2 years ago, but the experience still lives vividly
in my mind; they offered among the greatest gaming experiences I ever
had. I haven't played any of the other 4 games in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have known about the first game for years, before playing it, and it
was among the top of my wishlist. The appeal was simply the imagery of
the angry lead character (Kratos), the giants he was portrayed to
battle, the setting (ancient Greek mythology), as well as the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally managed to get my hands on the games (about 2 years
ago), they did not disappoint. The epic feel of it all, the character
design (the best ever that covers ancient Greek mythology), and (as
regards &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/God_of_War_III"&gt;God of War III&lt;/a&gt;) impressive realism, makes for a fantastic
series. Sadly, this trilogy is only available for PlayStation (2 &amp;amp; 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite characters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hercules (demigod, son of Zeus), who appears in the 3rd game of the
trilogy, is a mini-giant with an massive muscle structure and an
interesting attitude, not to mention armed with some awesomely
large and powerful weapons, that the playable character (Kratos)
luckily gets to play with. The moment where this Hercules character
appears is among my most favorite battle scenes in the whole
trilogy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hades (God of the Underworld), who we also only get to fight in the
3rd game of the trilogy, is another great design, and his
underworld the best environment of the whole trilogy. His
assortment of weapons is also quite impressive, but the battle
involving him, though quite good, could be more epic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://godofwar.wikia.com/wiki/Centaur#Centaur_General"&gt;Centaur General&lt;/a&gt; (human-horse being) were quite a presence. Not
only were they rather tough to beat, but they were also the most
charming characters in the whole trilogy. One wishes they had a
greater screen time. Note that there were other Centaurs in the
trilogy, but these particular ones were most interesting, and their
slaying most... beautiful. They appear first time in the 3rd game
in the trilogy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poseidon (God of the Sea), is an interesting one. His represents
the most complex (and hardest) fight sequence in the entire
trilogy, it it also happens on the third installment of this fine
trilogy. It's not exactly my favorite, but his character has a
certain level of charm, and the final kill is particularly brutal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kratos, the protagonist, was most impressive in the first game, but
he was getting less interesting later on and the novelty of his
anger was wearing off. He was also getting petty at times, and too
bloodthirsty to be convincing. Regardless, he is a work of superb
character design, and this well-enhanced by the pale color and red
stripes on his skin, as well as a body that makes him look like pure
lethal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://godofwar.wikia.com/wiki/Stone_Talos"&gt;Stone Talos&lt;/a&gt; are a one-of-a-kind character... muscular stone
statues that come to life to incur damage on our protagonist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome as it is, the series does have weaknesses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one notable bad work of character design, which is
Ares, the original god of war (a title Kratos took from him after
defeating him). He is totally uninresting (and clumsy), and the battle
in which the two fight is the worst in the trilogy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One other horrible character was the goat-snake-lion combo
character. It was probably a first in gaming history, but it was a
real stupid idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were also some particilarly hard stages to pass, where I had
to ask for help from a friend to proceed to the next level. I hate
stuff like that... I normally pick the easiest difficulty level in
games, for I hate to struggle for too long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="excellent"></category><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>Enter the Wu-Tang (36 Chambers)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/enter-the-wu-tang-36-chambers" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-05-23:enter-the-wu-tang-36-chambers</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed listening to this album, which also happens to be
the first by the group, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wu-Tang_Clan"&gt;Wu-Tang Clan&lt;/a&gt;. My favorite tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 04: &lt;strong&gt;Wu-Tang: 7th Chamber&lt;/strong&gt;; also redone (track 12)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 09: &lt;strong&gt;Method Man&lt;/strong&gt; - me loving the playfulness; also redone (track 13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 07: &lt;strong&gt;Wu-Tang Clan Ain't Nuthing ta Fuck Wit&lt;/strong&gt; - some more playfulness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="very-good"></category></entry><entry><title>'How Many' by Busta Rhymes</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/how-many-by-busta-rhymes" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-04-28:how-many-by-busta-rhymes</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Busta_Rhymes"&gt;Busta Rhymes&lt;/a&gt; has a mixtape named &lt;em&gt;Cut Master C With Busta Rhymes&lt;/em&gt;,
and in there is a version of &lt;strong&gt;How Many Mics&lt;/strong&gt; from the album, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Score_(album)"&gt;The Score&lt;/a&gt;
(simply titled &lt;strong&gt;How Many&lt;/strong&gt;).
Busta Rhymes is among the most highly-skilled of all rappers, ever,
but hardly ever performs in supreme tracks,
so was excited to listen to his take on one of the best hip-hop tracks ever
(from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-fugees"&gt;the best ever hip-hop album&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>top music videos</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-music-videos" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-04-24:top-music-videos</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Excellence in the track concerned contributes to the magnificence
of its video. I'm a fan of nearly all the following tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Movement&lt;/strong&gt; (The Roots)
The odd positions that our stars take and the overall beauty of it
makes it an eternal favourite of mine,
not to mention fact that the track is among my hip-hop favourites.
The simplicity of the video contributes and so is the fact it
remains entertaining despite that it's shot in just one room,
which is the kind of inventiveness I admire in art.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That Thing&lt;/strong&gt; (Lauryn Hill)
Flawlessly merges the views of two eras on one screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Got Till It's Gone&lt;/strong&gt; (Janet Jackson)
Great direction and cinematography as well as the casting makes
this an eternal masterpiece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stranger in Moscow&lt;/strong&gt; (Michael Jackson; Director - Nick Brandt)
Among the best camerawork and editing with magnificent slow-motion
scenes.. towards perfection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sixth Sense&lt;/strong&gt; (Common)
Excellently capturing an unexplained event which looks like some
sort of chaos, causing looks of despair and wonder among the
characters conecerned, some catching it on tv,
some near the event... powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything is Everything&lt;/strong&gt; (Lauryn Hill)
Great VFX showcasing NYC as a turntable are hard to beat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey Ya&lt;/strong&gt; (OutKast)
The high energy the video invokes, the appeal of seeing
a member of OutKast perform, and the VFX makes for an
exciting experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respiration&lt;/strong&gt; (Mos Def &amp;amp; Talib Kweli feat. Common)
Beautiful images of them great rappers strutting their style enhanced
shot by the black and style camerawork with some wonderful busy city
images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Egumnandini&lt;/strong&gt; (Doc Shebeleza)
Few videos were aver able to capture the township party scene with
such energy and believability. The cinematography is quite good too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who We Be&lt;/strong&gt; (DMX)
I usually like DMX's music videos because of their craftsmanship and the
messages they portray -- staying away from the annoying booty-shows
that so many succesful other rappers employ. This one is armed with
some excellent editing, some good visual effects, and some real-life
footage all put in the mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love of My Life&lt;/strong&gt; (Erykah Badu)
Erykah Badu's perfomance, as is the case in her videos, draws
one's attention, despite a huge anti-climactic slow-down in
the middle of the song.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All 'n my Grill&lt;/strong&gt; (Missy Elliot)
This could have been higher in the ratings had its mighty New York
settings -- with the dark lighting and that famous yellow-taxi
scenery -- not been interrupted by the boring dancing that Missy
likes so much in her videos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel It Boy&lt;/strong&gt; (Beenie Man ft. Janet Jackson; Dir: Dave Meyers)
Gorgeous, mellow, and digitally-manipulated envionment which offers rare
warmth. It boasts perhaps the largest collection of gorgeous gals of any
music video I've seen. Jackson doesn't look comfortable though, with
unnatural poses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Six Shooter (2005)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/six-shooter-2005" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2013-02-24:six-shooter-2005</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This 27 minute short is worthy mainly due to the loud and fascinating
young guy sitting next to the lead character on a train trip. He happens
to be the most insensitive character I have seen anywhere (if my poor
memory serves me well), and is funny at times. The ending is strange
though, and I guess deliberately pointless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was inspired to watch this due the director, who later on made the
weird and wonderful &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://movies.tshepang.net/seven-psychopaths-2012"&gt;Seven Psychopaths&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="good"></category><category term="short"></category></entry><entry><title>top tracks: Fugees</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-fugees" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2012-12-21:top-tracks-fugees</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Many Mics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fu-Gee-La&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mask&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cowboys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready Or Not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zealots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Beast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manifest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these are in one album, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Score_(album)"&gt;The Score&lt;/a&gt;, the best hip-hop album ever
made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="top-tracks"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>top tracks: The Roots</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-the-roots" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2012-12-21:top-tracks-the-roots</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="masterpiece"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1 masterpiece&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Music [Game Theory]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lesson - Part III (It's Over Now) [Come Alive]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distortion to Static [Do You Want More?!!!??!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't Feel Right [Game Theory]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond/React [Illadelph Halflife]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section [Illadelph Halflife]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wot They Do [Illadelph Halflife]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next Movement [Things Fall Apart]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push Up Ya Lighta [Illadelph Halflife]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my most favorite of all hip-hop groups. The intensely-talented
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Thought"&gt;Black Thought&lt;/a&gt;, its lead vocalist, is my most favorite of all hip-hop
artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="top-tracks"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Zero Punctuation rocks</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/zero-punctuation-rocks" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2012-07-10:zero-punctuation-rocks</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered an incredibly entertaining and scathing game reviewer,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.escapistmagazine.com/videos/view/zero-punctuation"&gt;Zero Punctuation&lt;/a&gt;.
None of the reviews I've seen so far are any shallow,
and there's even solid social commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>Dry And Heavy (1977)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/dry-and-heavy-1977" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2012-05-09:dry-and-heavy-1977</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A very laid-back Burning Spear album, with a mere 9 short tracks, the
best of which is a re-imagining of one of my eternal favorite tracks of
all time, &lt;em&gt;Creation&lt;/em&gt; (live versions). It's named &lt;em&gt;It's A Long Way
Around&lt;/em&gt;, and I could not stop myself from repeating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the other tracks is quite good, though not catchy at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="excellent"></category></entry><entry><title>Battlestar Galactica - Season 3 Episode 20</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/battlestar-galactica-season-3-episode-20" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-12-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-12-29:battlestar-galactica-season-3-episode-20</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever write anything about tv productions regardless of how many
times I tend to get impressed, and there hasn't been a shortage of that.
That's mainly due to laziness/motivation, but this time I just have to
mention this one gem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very last episode of the Season mainly focuses on the trial of one
former president who is accused of treason due to surrendering to the
cylons (a species created by humans) as well as giving them official
approval to execute dozens of people. The defence given by an assistant
lawyer is a masterpiece, and would match well with any court thing I've
seen in my tv/movie-watching history. The performance matches as well,
and that's interesting because the performer/character combination is
among the least interesting in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a sidenote, I find this Season to be the best (in a series of
four), because it covers more interesting events (the capturing of the
humans, the resistance, their eventual rescue, and a lot more, best of
which was the trial of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This positiveness could make it look like I'm a huge fan of the series,
but I'm not. In fact, I too often tend to hate it. There's a whole lot
of religious non-sense that I can't bear, some seriously annoying
characters, at least overly eccentric one, too much day-dreaming, some
too-stupid plot decisions... but Episode 20 goes some way to help me
forgive the rest of the shit.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tv"></category></entry><entry><title>top tracks: Bob Marley</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-bob-marley" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-11-02:top-tracks-bob-marley</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="landmark"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1 landmark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Woman, No Cry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2 masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stir It Up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;One Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Waiting in Vain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kaya&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sun is Shining&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Satisfy My Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Redemption Song&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rastaman Chant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="top-tracks"></category></entry><entry><title>top tracks: Burning Spear</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-burning-spear" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-11-02:top-tracks-burning-spear</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="landmark"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1 landmark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old Marcus Garvey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tradition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invasion&lt;/em&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;Black Wa-da-da&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marcus Garvey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Give Me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creation Rebel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wilderness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slavery Days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Civilise Reggae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Live Good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jordan River&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="honorable-mention"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;honorable mention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Children of Today (&lt;em&gt;Living Dub - Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt; - 1993); longer version: We
Suffer (Original Mix) (&lt;em&gt;Rare and Unreleased&lt;/em&gt; - 2001)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="top-tracks"></category></entry><entry><title>top tracks: Salif Keita</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-tracks-salif-keita" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-11-02:top-tracks-salif-keita</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5 masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandjou (&lt;em&gt;Folon... The Past&lt;/em&gt; - 1995)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inigiche (&lt;em&gt;Mouffou&lt;/em&gt; - 2002)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Souareba (&lt;em&gt;Soro&lt;/em&gt; - 1987)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cono (&lt;em&gt;Soro&lt;/em&gt; - 1987)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yamore (&lt;em&gt;Mouffou&lt;/em&gt; - 2002)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent-works"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4 excellent works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nyanafin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tekere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seydou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Madan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sina (aka Soumbouya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="top-tracks"></category></entry><entry><title>Music is the Weapon (2004)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/music-is-the-weapon-2004" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-03-05:music-is-the-weapon-2004</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have deep respect for Fela Kuti's musicianship, and more than any
other musician I've ever listened to. His intense love for the craft,
though I suspect that it may at times been detrimental to those
surrounding him, is hard to beat. His political views seemed relevant
too, as he mentions Nigerian government's oppressive acts, one of which
resulted in the death of his mother. How he was going to help correct
these injustices is another thing altogether&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fela Kuti was an eccentric character, at least as portrayed. He had the
fearless attitude of an traditional activist, which is a quality I
admire (and lack). He also promoted and practiced traditional African
religion (while opposing Christianity and Islam), and polygamy, which is
okay in itself, until the fact that the women themselves would not be
allowed to have other partners. Maybe Fela didn't mind it (he din't
mention it), but I doubt it. That's some double standards which I really
hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary itself is pretty decent, but lacks the depth I was
hoping for. I guess I'm more interested in the musical Fela Kuti than
the politics, even though one heavily influenced the other, making it
hard to separrate the two. But check out &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/review/R28YF6P9MDOEPS/ref=cm_cr_dp_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B000079DF9&amp;amp;nodeID=130&amp;amp;tag=&amp;amp;linkCode="&gt;this quality review&lt;/a&gt;, which
is far better and more detailed than I can muster.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="decent"></category><category term="documentary"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Floetic (2002)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/floetic-2002" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-02-28:floetic-2002</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love the smooth melody that is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floetic"&gt;*Floetic*&lt;/a&gt; by Floetry. It is the sort
of sound you find in Jill Scott's near-masterpiece of an album, &lt;em&gt;Who's
Jill Scott&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 5: &amp;quot;Getting Late&amp;quot; – not nearly as seductive as &amp;quot;Say Yes&amp;quot;, but
what it's a masterwork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 8: &amp;quot;Say Yes&amp;quot; – it's most notable thing is the sensual play by
one them gals; makes me wanna say... yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 2: &amp;quot;Floetic&amp;quot; – energetic and nearly-formulaic; beautiful
arrangements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="very-good"></category></entry><entry><title>Beethoven's Symphony 9</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/beethovens-symphony-9" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-02-24:beethovens-symphony-9</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was led to listen to Beethoven's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Symphony_No._9_(Beethoven)"&gt;critically-acclaimed&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;Symphony No.
9&amp;quot;. Well, let's say I'm a novice regarding Classical music, but I didn't
find anything amazing in there. Let's call it acquired taste, but I've
heard dozens of Classical tracks that were superior. Let's say maybe I
wasn't focusing much on the music (I was listening to it while browsing
the web). Oh, and I even played it twice just to make sure, and still...
nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: the version I listened to is formally titled &lt;em&gt;Symphony No.9 in
D minor, Op.125 – &amp;quot;Choral&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; and was played by Wiener Philharmoniker,
Orchestra.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="classical"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="unrated"></category></entry><entry><title>The B-Sides 1990-2000 (2002)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/the-b-sides-1990-2000-2002" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-02-22:the-b-sides-1990-2000-2002</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm currently enjoying the wonderful &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Best_of_1990–2000#Bonus_B-sides_disc"&gt;The B-Sides 1990-2000&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (2002)
by U2. It's a bunch of real nice Dance re-mixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 8: &lt;em&gt;Salomé (Zooromancer Remix)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 9: &lt;em&gt;Even Better Than The Real Thing (The Perfecto Mix)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="rock"></category><category term="very-good"></category></entry><entry><title>Hold It Down (1995)</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/hold-it-down-1995" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-02-20:hold-it-down-1995</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently got hold of &amp;quot;Hold It Down&amp;quot; (1995) by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Das_EFX"&gt;Das EFX&lt;/a&gt;. Real good
ole-style hip-hop, thanks to a friend who, when I asked who he reckoned
the best hip-hop group is, he mentioned Das EFX. In my investigations, I
also got hold of their &amp;quot;Generation EFX&amp;quot; (1998) which is really bad.
Strange that just 3 years later people can fuck up like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 18 – &lt;em&gt;Hardcore Rap Act&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 12 – &lt;em&gt;Alright&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track 05 – &lt;em&gt;Real Hip Hop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="excellent"></category><category term="hip-hop"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Barry White's top tracks</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/barry-whites-top-tracks" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:barry-whites-top-tracks</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="points"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6 &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/simple-point-system-for-rating-music"&gt;points&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 landmark (&lt;em&gt;Bring Back My Yesterday&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 masterpiece (&lt;em&gt;Let Me Live My Life Lovin' You Babe&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 excellent work (&lt;em&gt;Just the Way You Are&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>BioShock</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/bioshock" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:bioshock</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wired.com/gamelife/2008/02/ken-levine-how"&gt;negative review of BioShock&lt;/a&gt; partly because everything
else I've read so far was full of praise, and partly because,
immersive as it is, really is overrated. For one, I couldn't believe
that I was restricted to basically one environment, and I got so lost
around the repetitive-looking environment just as I was in &lt;em&gt;Halo:
Combat Evolved&lt;/em&gt; (a superior game, even considering it was released
over 5 years earlier).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like about the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an amazing array of genetic weapons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great art direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fearsome Big Daddies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an appealing gloomy storyline of genetic engineering gone awry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing did alert me what a tremendously useful tool 3D games
could be as exploration tools to unfamiliar worlds.  Note that I've
lived through such an experience with the vastly underrated &lt;em&gt;Conflict:
Desert Storm&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>Body Bags</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/body-bags" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:body-bags</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Body_Bags_(comics)"&gt;Body Bags comic&lt;/a&gt; early this morning and it's
devastatingly unique and fresh, with some seriously interesting
characters. Nice stuff. Am not big on comics, but if they tend to come
like this, I'll definitely get hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="comic"></category></entry><entry><title>evil edits</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/evil-edits" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:evil-edits</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It gets disgusting when re-releases, usually in a form of 'the best of
X', gets their tracks' lengths reduced, all to make space for a larger
number of tracks on that album. The worst such a situation is in the
case of Don't Leave Me This Way (Harold Melvin &amp;amp; the Blue Notes) which
had a release that cut it to about 5 minutes of its original 10 minutes,
effectively getting rid of the most exciting part of that track, the
climactic second act. A similar thing happened to Brenda Fassie's
Weekend Special whose climax was also mercilessly cut in her Greatest
Hits album.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>GameSpy's 'BioShock' review</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/gamespys-bioshock-review" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:gamespys-bioshock-review</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year, I got seduced by GameSpy with their &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://goty.gamespy.com/2006/"&gt;2006 review&lt;/a&gt;, and this
time around, I got seduced yet again by their review of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://goty.gamespy.com/2007/special/22.html"&gt;BioShock&lt;/a&gt;.
Going through their various categories, that game got mentioned more
than twice, being among the top10 PC games, winning Art Direction award,
and then, in what truly caught my attention, winning the Best Story
award. The review makes me salivate. [&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/bioshock"&gt;update&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>Halo 3</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/halo-3" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:halo-3</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I could not spot a real improvement from Halo 2, bar the hyper-realistic
environments of Flood-infested walls, the addition of some vehicles, and
the ability to dislodge heavy guns. It seems most effort went into just
the environments while ignoring gameplay and a fresh and good storyline.
It's quite a pity because the first Halo was such an epic achievement,
while the second, while unable to replicate the first's grandeur, had
quite a few innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>hip-hop greats</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/hip-hop-greats" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:hip-hop-greats</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="landmarks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;landmarks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MC's Act Like They Don't Know (KRS-One and DJ Premier)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Downfall (Notorious B.I.G.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nas is Like (Nas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="masterpieces"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;masterpieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal in Man (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad Dreams (Busta Rhymes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doggy Dogg World (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G Funk Intro (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gz &amp;amp; Hustlas (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hip-Hop (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Music (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serial Killa (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="excellent"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;excellent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware (Big Pun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cowboys (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distortion to Static (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't Feel Right (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Mile (Eminem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elevators (Outkast)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For All My Niggaz &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Bitches (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fu-Gee-La (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gin And Juice (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Knock Life (Jay-Z)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold (KRS-One)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Many MC's (KRS-ONE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Many Mics (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm A African (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's A Party (Busta Rhymes feat. Zhane)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kick in the Door (Notorious B.I.G.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mask, The (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematics (DJ Premier, Mos Def)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mind Sex (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miss Jackson (Outkast)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Micranots? (Micranots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murder Was the Case (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next Movement (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old School (Tupac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ooh! (De la Soul ft. RedMan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track 15, album: Slum (Slum Village)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pump Pump (Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready Or Not (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respiration (Blackstar feat. Common)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond/React (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Score, The (Fugees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shook Ones Pt. II (Mobb Deep)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th Sense (Common and DJ Premier)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still (Dr Dre feat. Snoop Dogg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell Me Something (Arrested Development)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ten Crack Commandments (Notorious B.I.G.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Schools (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thirty Three Threes (Canibus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw Yo Hands in the Air (Cypress Hill)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tradin' War Stories (Tupac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travellin' Man (DJ Honda and Mos Def)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Way I Am, The (Eminem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woo-Ha (Busta Rhymes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wot The Do (The Roots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You Came Up (Big Pun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll Find A Way (Dead Prez)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="special-mentions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;special mentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life Goes On (Tupac) - chiefly for being an ex-landmark; am not
really enjoying no more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiet Storm (Mobb Deep feat. Lil' Kim) - chiefly for having a really
favorite chorus by the Kim lady&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shove This Jay-Oh-Bee (Canibus) - me loving the so-alive beat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="hip-hop"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Ma-Brrr</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/ma-brrr" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:ma-brrr</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We all know that each repeat viewing of a movie is a different
experience. You can say the same with a stage play, except that it's
never the same thing. I'm here referring to MaBrr (there is not even one
credible site I found with a few minutes of search), a musical play
currently seen at State Theatre, Pretoria. It's about the life and
career of Brenda Fassie, a deceased South African vocalist, who was
arguably the most popular of the country's artist in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first night was the best experience I've so far had in my stage play
experience. It was electrifying and the audience agreed with me. A few
goosebumps here and there. It's amazing how larger-than-life one person
can be made. It brought a new appreciation of South African art (and
abilities), that there's such a rich culture to export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are some the elements that made me so excited, the first time
around:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lead performance: I gained new-found respect for Lesego Motsepe, who
is famous for her long career in Isidingo, a soapie generally
regarded as South Africa's best; the director even mentioned that
someone stated that she wasn't LIKE Brenda, but rather, she WAS
Brenda; the result of the voice training she went through was
amazing, because she really sounded like her character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music: the compositions were remixed, and the live band bringing it
alive rocked; I wish it would get recorded because some of it were
improvements on the originals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dancers: though the dancing merely okay, their energy was tops,
especially the guys, and the quality of the choreography also helped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;costume design: what the dancers had to wear was mostly impressive,
and often offered an accurate display of dressing styles through a
bit of South Africa's past&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backing vocalists: wonderful, notably the fat guy, who had a tiny
moment to act, which was hilarious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extra emotion: well, Bongani Fassie, Brenda's son, pitched on stage
unscheduled, and even joined the lead performer to sing &amp;quot;Too Late for
Mama&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;miscellaneous: a bunch of scenes and moments are too many to mention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that this was opening night may have helped a lot, as well as
close to sold-out venue. Now, the shitty thing about stage is that such
moments can't be replicated, and even though it may have been recorderd,
it's just not the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revisit was something else. The attendance was really bad this time
around (a Thursday after Friday's opening night):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lead performance: she was probably tired and/or discouraged by the
small and unresponsive crowd; she mostly didn't even try to sound
like Brenda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music: there's wasn't a degradation, so kudos!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dancing: less energy, and that there were fallen beads on stage
probably didn't help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;costume design: same shit, so nothing to say here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backing vocalists: wonderful, but the fat guy was just reciting his
words this time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extra emotion: well, the Bongani Fassie thing can't be replicated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;miscellaneous: no surprises, nothing new worth mentioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="update"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to see this for the third time, this time on a Saturday, so the
audience was much bigger than last time, and the show was far better,
making me a little bit obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lead performance: she did better than last time, but maybe not as
good as the first night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music: I recall enjoying the previous moments better, maybe because I
got used to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dancing: the energy seemed as high as the first time around, and I
enjoyed it more (I really the supercool guys at the jazz club)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;costume design: same shit, so nothing to say here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backing vocalists: the nice fat guy was replaced by a less
interesting one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extra emotion: I kept getting (unbearable) attention from one dancer,
since I was on the front row seats; I guess she wanted to steal the
show, and I didn't allow her (she was unrelenting) so I shifted my
attention away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;miscellaneous: the kids called up on stage were much more fun than on
previous occasions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category><category term="stage"></category></entry><entry><title>me loves Cherry Poptart</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/me-loves-cherry-poptart" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:me-loves-cherry-poptart</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning I read &amp;quot;Cherry Does the Time Warp&amp;quot;, part of the funny and
politically satirical adult comic series, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherry_(comics)"&gt;Cherry&lt;/a&gt;. It's not the first
time I've read a Cherry installment, but this specific one parodies some
characters in history and popular media in a fun manner, but it's
highlight is Cherry's encounter with her teenage, sexually-inept mom
(and you can imagine what transpires).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="comic"></category></entry><entry><title>SABC 1 glory</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/sabc-1-glory" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:sabc-1-glory</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got captivated by the new SABC 1 theme presentation (for lack of a
better name), which is a fusion of computer animation and live footage
with reddish filtering, an artistic impression reminding me of the
visual landmark that is 300. It's however not nearly as popular or
memorable as the previous theme which portrayed South African Black and
White people having switched roles (as in White people living in
townships and Black people leading a more affluent lifestyle). This, the
latter, is an interesting play on the stereotypical both races have on
each other and was notably also because of the superb camerawork and
some interesting acting. It's interesting as regards the former for I
thought the latter couldn't be bettered.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="tv"></category></entry><entry><title>simple point system for rating music</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/simple-point-system-for-rating-music" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:simple-point-system-for-rating-music</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use a simplistic point system to rate top music tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;landmark = 3 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;masterpiece = 2 points&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;excellent work = 1 point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what others use and am too lazy to search.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Too Long In Slavery</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/too-long-in-slavery" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:too-long-in-slavery</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The mood of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dTuLVDa916U"&gt;Too Long In Slavery&lt;/a&gt;
(performed by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture_(band)"&gt;Culture&lt;/a&gt; and found in &lt;em&gt;Greatest Hits - The Frontlne Years&lt;/em&gt;)
matches it's title pretty well
(the vocalist sounds like he's in pain and so is the melody).
The track still sounds is near-playful,
though it has nearly brought me to tears on a few occasions;
it's a powerful delivery of a painful message.
It's my favorite among the group's work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>top music tracks</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/top-music-tracks" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:top-music-tracks</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All these are landmarks (i.e. beyond masterpiece level):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring Back My Yesterday (Barry White)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confusion (Fela Kuti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crying Guitar (The Movers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diamante (Zucchero)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django's Castle (Eddie Harris)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do You Feel Like We Do (Peter Frampton)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gauteng (Miriam Makeba)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give Me (Burning Spear)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Igbe (Fela Kuti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jikijela (Letta Mbuli)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lady (Fela Kuti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Love is Free (Double Exposure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Woman, No Cry (Bob Marley)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old Marcus Garvey (Burning Spear)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomorrow is Forever (Dolly Parton)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With or Without You (U2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is far from complete and notably won't include tracks from
Hip-Hop and House for they just don't fit, maybe as a matter of
prejudice, as in, &amp;quot;how could I append KRS-One next to the mighty Fela
Kuti&amp;quot;, or maybe such genres are simply incomparable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Toxic</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/toxic" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:toxic</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had developed a negative attitude towards Britney Spear's music due
bad quality (though to be fair, I haven't listened to much of her work,
all but the most popular few tracks). But there is one particular gem, &lt;em&gt;Toxic&lt;/em&gt;,
and I was surprised to find that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toxic_(song)"&gt;it's critically acclaimed&lt;/a&gt;,
especially since I reduced it to a guilty pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Up With Donald Byrd</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/up-with-donald-byrd" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2011-01-14:up-with-donald-byrd</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed Donarl Byrd's superb album, &amp;quot;Up With Donald Byrd&amp;quot;,
most especially the masterpiece House of the Rising Sun and My Babe. I
have listened to a few the guy's albums and nothing quite comes close,
in fact some are so bad that it's strange it's the same artist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I went onto the interwebs looking for like-minded people and
found one who &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.answers.com/topic/up-with-donald-byrd-1964-album-by-donald-byrd"&gt;disagreed&lt;/a&gt;, calling it forgettable. Either that's a
critic with a more sophisticated taste and much more listening
experience, or she's got twisted taste. I was actually surprised since
I'm even tempted to call this the best Jazz album yet!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="jazz"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Illadelph Halflife</title><link href="http://tshepang.net/illadelph-halflife" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Tshepang Lekhonkhobe</name></author><id>tag:tshepang.net,2009-07-27:illadelph-halflife</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is undoubtedly the best album by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Roots"&gt;The Roots&lt;/a&gt;, and includes
timeless acts like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Section&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wot They Do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Respond/React&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Push Up Ya Lighter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Alibi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ital (The Universal Side)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;em&gt;Section&lt;/em&gt; is actually what prompted me to write this post,
for I loved it so much that I wondered if &lt;em&gt;Next Movement&lt;/em&gt; (from their
later [Things Fall Apart album][]), which I have for a long time
regarded as the best hip-hop track ever, deserves it's position at the
top of the group's work, and therefore removing it from the list of
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://tshepang.net/hip-hop-greats"&gt;hip-hop landmarks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="music"></category></entry></feed>