<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/luck/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>me got meself another coding job</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/me-got-meself-another-coding-job/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/me-got-meself-another-coding-job/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, I was totally excited by having &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;me-got-meself-a-coding-job&quot;&gt;my first job working on
software&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I am very grateful for the chance the owner, who interviewed
me for the position, took on me. I learned an incredible amount of
stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some months ago, a friend enticed me to the idea of doing something
else, giving me contacts for &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;eiq.co.za&quot;&gt;some company&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; building software and
electronics products for the mining industry. So I wasn&#x27;t actually
looking for work, but I was glad of the opportunity since I was sort of
stagnating, and it really looked like this new company did some fun
stuff, and I got the vibe that I&#x27;d really get challenged.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been 3 months now, and my guess was right. I keep getting
surprised by the levels of smart I encounter regurlarly. These are the
sorts of people I simply can&#x27;t match with my lesser brain, but am glad
to work with, since they teach me so much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The systems we build are embedded, so I spend most of my time working
with C and C++, and it tends to be a serious challenge, given that
there&#x27;s a lot less hand-holding with those than with my favorite,
Python.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>me got meself a coding job</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/me-got-meself-a-coding-job/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/me-got-meself-a-coding-job/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I had one of the most exciting moments in my life when I got offered a
job at a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tauspace.com&quot;&gt;software development company&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (the title is Analyst: Software
Engineering). I don&#x27;t even know what my planned-for tasks are, and I
was all the more surprised because I think I didn&#x27;t do well at the
interview. Great news is I didn&#x27;t expect a coding job so soon,
especially given I don&#x27;t have previous professional exposure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an electronic technician (lesser than an engineer) by trade and am
pretty unhappy in my current job (testing, calibration, and
fault-finding of gyro-stabilised airborne surveillance&#x2F;observation
systems). That&#x27;s partly because I don&#x27;t really get challenged since
I&#x27;m on a production line. I do strongly doubt I&#x27;d be job-hunting was I
in development&#x2F;engineering.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of all however is I&#x27;ll be working on software, a dream job really,
considering I love computers and all, and specifically the software part
of it. Electronics is fine too, but the last time I really got close to
it was back in school, and I&#x27;m here talking of design, not &amp;quot;testing,
calibration...&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How lucky can one get!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
