<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2012-movie/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cloudy With A Chance Of Meatballs (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cloudy-with-a-chance-of-meatballs-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cloudy-with-a-chance-of-meatballs-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts off amazingly well, with the same level of movie magic offered
by gems like &lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;megamind-2010&quot;&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but is funnier by far.
Sadly, halfway through, things start being not so okay. That&#x27;s when we
get the ever-uninteresting, slow-the-movie-down morality talk, which
includes the beloved hero getting a little too cocky. There&#x27;s also some
annoying moments where the town inhabitants treat this hero unfairly,
like the moment where they attempt to attack him when something goes
wrong with his food-making machine. It&#x27;s fine when they are shallow and
stupid, but it gets unbearable when the writers makes them so
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;unforgiving-characters-are-annoying&quot;&gt;unappreciative&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One other not-too-kool thing is when these writers
push the boundaries of fantasy way too far when the food surrounding the
machine gain awareness, attacking the heroes to trying to shut the
machine down. That was just needless; the movie was already more than
good enough. Also, the mayor was just too annoying, given some villainy
that&#x27;s left unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, back to the good stuff:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The character design is amazing and so is the animation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed the character of the police officer, and the love he
showed for his son was touching.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lead character is recycled, but still exciting enough.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept is great, and exploited well enough, even though it runs
out of steam about halfway through.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The food design is great. It reminds me of &lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and even
rivals it. The most amazing of them all is the ice cream.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The jelly castle was a setting for the most enchanting moment,
making me wish fantasy was real.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lincoln Lawyer (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lincoln-lawyer-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lincoln-lawyer-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;2012-10-21 review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real nice camerawork and direction; very interesting performances. The
brutal acts of the criminal are sadly left unjustified&#x2F;unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still feel the same, surprisingly, but I neglected to mention my
favorites: the driver, the court snitch, the private investigator (the
ever-excellent William H. Macy), and the desirable female detective.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dark Knight Rises (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-rises-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-dark-knight-rises-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I am in love with the voice and utterances of Bane, a physically
formidable villain in a mask. The movie is far bigger and more intense
than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-dark-knight-2008&quot;&gt;the immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I also found it more entertaining (at
least on first viewing), and a lot less annoying, though nothing matches
the miracle that is Heath Ledger&#x27;s The Joker. The title character
sounds unconvincing with the silly voice, and the movie feels like a
mess. Maybe it&#x27;s just too long, and the writers too desperate to
impress. The stupid twist didn&#x27;t help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gone Baby Gone (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gone-baby-gone-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gone-baby-gone-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly a year after the initial viewing, I am a bit puzzled why I was so
impressed so much by this movie. It remains good, yes, but I went too
far by praising its direction, acting and cast, or even drawing
parallels with &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;se7en-1995&quot;&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I got right though was the twist:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twist is silly, and just doesn&#x27;t justify everything that happened
before. It sucks when movie makers don&#x27;t know how to end a perfectly
good story. On a positive note, that&#x27;s when the lead character (Casey
Affleck) chooses to do a very noble act, making him truly admirable,
especially considering what he sacrificed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, I was afraid a revisit would disappoint, especially because
this was the remaining movie I labeled &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;tag&#x2F;excellent&quot;&gt;excellent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the entire year of
2012... it was going to be the best movie of the year. Sadly, not one
movie from that year went beyong the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;tag&#x2F;good&quot;&gt;very good&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (7&#x2F;10) rating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Battle In Heaven (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/battle-in-heaven-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/battle-in-heaven-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Never in my movie-watching history have I seen a character as dull as
the lead character here. The only one that comes close is that of
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;crimson-gold-2003&quot;&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It also happens to be the most bizarre movie I have seen
this year. It explores sex in a way I have not seen before, in that we
get to see very unattractive characters (husband and wife) take part in
it. The way they are shot is also very suggestive, like the movie is
some sort of soft porn, only with superior direction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is also a more extreme form of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;romance-1999&quot;&gt;Romance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, in that it was
probably inspired by it, both in terms of explicit sexual shots and very
slow and pro-longed takes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only characters that seem alive are the young gal (fucking gorgeous)
and her friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Looper (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/looper-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/looper-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I dislike the overly-loud banging sounds, which mostly emanate from the
gunshots. This is from a very violent movie which cast Bruce Willis (he
should retire), and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Joseph_Gordon-Levitt&quot;&gt;Joseph Gordon-Levitt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, whose face should have been
left alone, especially since he does not resemble Bruce even a bit even
after all the non-sense is put on his face, digital or not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping this overrated non-sense will be the last time travel movie
ever made, since the concept is utter crap (nonsensical). The story
starts exciting enough but loses steam very soon after. None of the
perfomers are solid, especially Jeff Daniels as villain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Dictator (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-dictator-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-dictator-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;With hilarious moments all over the place, much of which is unique,
fresh, and daring. The lead character, played by the brilliant comedian,
Sacha Baron Cohen, reminds me very much of the Adam Sandler&#x27;s in the
wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;many-recent-movies-2009-02-27&quot;&gt;You Don&#x27;t Mess With the Zohan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, only a lot better. The movie
also has very good production design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one trashy scene where the lead helps deliver a child, but the
punchline actually makes it worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bourne Legacy (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-legacy-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-bourne-legacy-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The two facts, that the lead character is not Jason Bourne and that the
story occurs in parallel with the events in the Bourne trilogy, make for
very interesting narrative choices. I was not aware of this, so it was a
bit confusing until it was clear. Anyways, I am also very glad that the
new lead is quite capable, which is a relief since I was concerned,
considering I did not like him in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-avengers-2012&quot;&gt;The Avengers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He still is not a
match of Matt Damon though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of the direction itself also matches that of the last two
movies in the trilogy, but the fight choreography is even better, among
the best I have seen in a non-martial arts movie. I did not like the
chase sequence so much, and the lead opponent could be better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect 2 (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-2-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only because of my great love for &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2004&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It
feels like a student effort, and is just not interesting, and therefore
challenged my perseverance a bit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did however like two of the characters, the criminals who want their
money back. The guys playing them give superb performances. One other
quality performance is that of company boss, while the best friend is
not so bad in parts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Butterfly Effect 3 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-3-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-butterfly-effect-3-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far better than its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2-2006&quot;&gt;immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and a worthy successor to
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-butterfly-effect-2004&quot;&gt;the original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is a well-made and well-acted thriller with a
well-written script. The twist is interesting, though not entirely
convincing... feels forced. I enjoyed the performances of the 2
detectives, though no one was as good as overweight plant-loving
character, a sort of wise guide for the lead character. The &#x27;rape&#x27;
scene is superbly made.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Avengers (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-avengers-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-avengers-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;thor-2011&quot;&gt;Thor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; very unsatisfactory, the 2 recent Hulk movies very
lacking, and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011&quot;&gt;Captain America&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; fairly bad. That&#x27;s why I was concerned
when I heard that my favorite comic book hero, Iron Man, would be paired
with them into one movie. I was also concerned by the fact that Jon
Favreau was not directing. Luckily the movie turned out a lot better
than I expected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what makes it so good:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie is directed in a similar style to those 2 Iron Man movies,
including the clever humor and laid-back acting style.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie has some of the best visual effects I&#x27;ve seen yet, and
about as large-scale as any of the 3 &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies, without
the overly-frantic action where you can&#x27;t figure WTF is going on.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found the reaction of the city public refreshingly-realistic:
instead of watch and cheer the heroes, they run away from danger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Nightmare on Elm Street (1984)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-nightmare-on-elm-street-1984/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-nightmare-on-elm-street-1984/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This movie is one more reason I should probably stop paying attention to
the opinions of critics who get aggregated on Rotten Tomatoes. Most of
those who reviewed the movie actually felt &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rottentomatoes.com&#x2F;m&#x2F;nightmare_on_elm_street&quot;&gt;it was decent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One even
went as far as thinking the performances were any good. What the fuck! I
will be fair by admitting that the concept is actually good: people
getting attacked only when they fall asleep. I also liked some of the
visuals, like the gal who spins around and gets dragged around the room,
defying gravity. Everything else is plain bad, including the extremely
uninspired look and character development of the villain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mission: Impossible - Ghost Protocol (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mission-impossible-ghost-protocol-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mission-impossible-ghost-protocol-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked the concept of the device that creates an optical illusion; I
also liked watching the Burj Khalifa, my favorite building, on which
some of the (noisy) action takes place. Not much else is interesting,
least of which is performance of the leading lady, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Paula_Patton&quot;&gt;Paula Patton&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I did
however fall for the ultra-desirable &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;L%C3%A9a_Seydoux&quot;&gt;Léa Seydoux&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Total Recall (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/total-recall-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/total-recall-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is so different from the first same-titled one from 1990 such
that it cannot really be called a remake. It is not quite as
interesting, and so are the lead actors (there is no Schwarzenegger or
Sharon Stone), does not take place in Mars (sadly) and is a
straight-forward thriller without any mind-fuck qualities the first one
had. The action was really overlong, and had the too-many hero-luck
moments, making it nearly unbearable towards the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nice technology ideas I have not seen before:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Necklace that allows one to change appearance; by the way, the guy
the protagonist turns into gives a nice performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transport that goes through center of the planet straight to the
other side.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small video cameras that attach themselves to surfaces, shot through
a gun.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some I have seen:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;levitating cars (a few movies)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a machine that gives one convincing but fake memories (the first
&lt;em&gt;Total Recall&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brave (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brave-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brave-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A big let-down with a shallow and unexciting story, which is a strange
thing for a Disney theatrical release. This is made worse by my great
anticipation. Me was looking forward to something darker, as the poster
would suggest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hair and fur is done quite well, and so was the bear fight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Amazing Spider-Man (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-amazing-spider-man-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not really a supreme reboot, but it is an okay one. It does have
some exciting effects, and I most especially love the fights between the
hero and the villain. The love interest is not interesting, nor is any
of the characters who fill the movie. Well, maybe except the villain,
but only when in lizard form. The story is merely okay, and is bad at
times, e.g. the help the hero gets near the end with the cranes and all
(WTF!).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zombieland (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zombieland-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zombieland-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts very well, with well-made visuals of zombie attacks, and a
nice play on &#x27;rules to survive&#x27;. It sadly gets messed when it&#x27;s clear
the writers did not know where to run with the story, and made even
worse by the sisters, who serve only to annoy, especially the older one.
Her failed attempt at sex appeal and sass does not help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do however have to appreciate the moment where the Woody Harrelson
character expresses great admiration for Bill Murray.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dark Shadows (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dark-shadows-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dark-shadows-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this surprisingly laid-back, and more humorous than other Tim
Burton movies. The greatest pleasure offered is the villain, perhaps the
most interesting witch in movie history. Her cracked-skin nature is also
something fresh (me have not seen such before), her sexuality amazing,
her passive and quick-acting personality welcome (check for example how
she does not waste time to get to meet her old lover), and her beauty so
incredible that she can easily be forgiven for her great cruelty.
Another surprise is the sex scene, which I enjoyed a lot. Good humor
there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Cabin In The Woods (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-cabin-in-the-woods-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-cabin-in-the-woods-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This must be the weirdest of horror movies I&#x27;ve seen, and also
surprisingly highly rated. It still has those abused horror elements me
hates so much, and the only fresh thing it adds to the genre is the
characters who watch the victims in excitement. The leading gal is
extra-desirable but a little low on acting talent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Idiocracy (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/idiocracy-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/idiocracy-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It started pretty well, with nice humor, but the idiocy of a future
human civilization just went too far, and being a passive comedy is not
enough of an excuse for lazy writing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Igor (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/igor-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/igor-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much enjoyable, complete with an interesting lead and an even
more interesting creation in the form of a sweet oversized monster, Eva.
The character design is of good quality (check each of the mad
scientists for example), but the sad moment, that in which the lead
reveals lies he told, sucks as much as it normally does in, for example,
romantic comedies. This heavily taints an otherwise good fantasy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Man of the Year (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/man-of-the-year-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/man-of-the-year-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was surprised that &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Man_of_the_Year_(2006_film)#Reception&quot;&gt;critics disliked this one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for I enjoyed it much.
I found much of the humor great, and I found the performance of Robin
Williams wonderful. The romance however was not done very well, mainly
because the character of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Laura_Linney&quot;&gt;Laura Linney&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, herself a very excellent
actress (remember &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;kinsey-2004&quot;&gt;Kinsey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), is very annoying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those critics mentioned dislike of mixing the whole thing with
conspiracy, and in hindsight, it was quite unwarranted. The movie would
have done fine without it, and it was just not done right, and Jeff
Goldblum performance didn&#x27;t help either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Snow White and the Huntsman (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/snow-white-and-the-huntsman-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/snow-white-and-the-huntsman-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I went into this one with high anticipation, only to be met with lots of
careless direction, as if the thing was rushed. It is also the worst
performance of Charlize Theron in memory, and the only one I found
embarassing. However, the worst performance in the movie is that of the
lead character.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are isolated moments of beauty and decent visual effects. Not one
of the seven dwarfs are interesting, even though many were portrayed by
good actors. Why didn&#x27;t they use real dwafs?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Love You Phillip Morris (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-love-you-phillip-morris-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-love-you-phillip-morris-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Too often if happens that a movie starts promisingly well, and in this
case, with solid direction and exciting acting, but later on lulls you
into boredom, forcing you to keep checking how long is left before the
end. It remains good throughout of course, but the (extremely)
unconvincing performance of Ewan McGregor does not help at all. I kept
waiting for &#x27;his moment&#x27;, but it never comes. There&#x27;s also not a
proper explanation why the lead character, played by Jim Carrey, was so
in love with that Ewan one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more positive note, Jim Carrey gives an amazing performance. I also
enjoyed that of the ex-wife.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is one of those movies with a plot so complex that me got lost very
soon into it. It is also one of those movies that are so devoid of
excitement that it feels a bit like self-torture to watch to the end. It
didn&#x27;t help that the very uninteresting Gary Oldman is the lead
character, though it helped that there was a performance as fabulous as
that of Colin Firth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Prometheus (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/prometheus-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/prometheus-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The suspense, which runs the entire length of the movie, is a bit hard
to bear. The movie also feels incomplete, some stuff left unexplained:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why is the robot sinister&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why does the robot help near the end&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&#x27;s up with the old man&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creature design of the humanoid creatures is incredible. The ending
is solid, and the famous alien, which is in baby form, is flawless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Blood: the Last Vampire (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/blood-the-last-vampire-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/blood-the-last-vampire-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the imagery is beautiful, and so is the lead character. The
scene in the car with father and daughter is surprisingly good, and does
not fit the movie. That daughter is given the movie&#x27;s best performance.
The ends feels rushed... lazy writing. The demons are among some of the
worst creature designs ever in movies... there must have been a problem
with the budget.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brothers (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brothers-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brothers-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of emotion, but mostly bearable due to quality direction. Toby
Maguire has never been this scary. The nurse girlfriend is gorgeous as
fuck. The movie is pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Safe House (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/safe-house-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/safe-house-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see a movie so big with action so intense set in
South Africa. Other than that fresh setting, there is nothing new at all
about the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is at least one inaccuracy... the train service shown is used
almost exclusively by the poorer among city people in that country of
mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hunger Games (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hunger-games-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If we ignore the shallow non-sense about Americanism, I find &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tnr.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;film&#x2F;102038&#x2F;the-hunger-games-collins-lawrence-ross-terrible-un-american&quot;&gt;this
review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, among the few negative ones on the movie, very true. I find the
movie an uninteresting waste of time, and therefore it&#x27;s appeal is
mysterious to me. As mentioned in the review, there is a glaring lack of
explanation on the cruel situation some of the people find themselves
in. Not even the visual effects are really good, though I liked the
visual design of some of the sets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wrath of the Titans (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wrath-of-the-titans-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wrath-of-the-titans-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The visual effects are decent, the performance of Liam Neeson (Zeus) a
lot better than in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;clash-of-the-titans-2010&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the performance of Ralph
Fiennes a lot less menacing (and less interesting), and the movie itself
less exciting. The new character, the son of Poseidon, is interesting.
Andromeda, the queen of the human army, is given a miscast and
uninteresting performance by Rosamund Pike.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part 2</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-2/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-2/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots more action than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1&quot;&gt;the previous movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, perhaps more than all the
others too, though not really an interesting conclusion. The main battle
feels like a poor copy of that in &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings: The Return of the
King&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, though it&#x27;s not bad at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows, Part 1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows-part-1/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story of the Deathly Hallows makes for some of the best animation
I&#x27;ve seen yet, though it runs for only a few minutes. It&#x27;s a fresh
departure from an otherwise dull and overlong experience. The movie is
even a worse experience than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009&quot;&gt;the immediate predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though bearable, this is the worst so far in the series. Too much of it
feels like filler material (the romance and ensuing jealousy for
example), and it feels like we were denied a proper climax... it feels
incomplete. Even the visual effects are lesser, both in number and
merit, from (at least) the previous two movies. One thing that deserves
praise though is the smoke&#x2F;ink effect that was used whenever the
villains (dis)appear. It was also used to great effect in the
end-credits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The battle between arch-villain and Dumbledore is the best action piece
so far in this series. It&#x27;s quite intense and has wonderful visual
effects. There are other good visual effect moments here and there. Even
the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dementors&quot;&gt;Dementors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which I so admired in the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;harry-potter-and-the-prisoner-of-azkaban-2004&quot;&gt;3rd movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, have been given
a facelift, though I prefer the original look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ip Man (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/ip-man-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/ip-man-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Great martial arts choreography, some of the best I have seen; two
gorgeous guys, one the arrogant rural martial arts expert, and another,
the Janasese military leader, who is among the prettiest guys I&#x27;ve seen
ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing really new here, and the lead actor could be more
interesting. Sadly, each of these oriental martial arts actors have Jet
Li to match against, and that&#x27;s a high standard of appeal. I am still
giving this one high marks because I seriously enjoyed it, me being a
sucker for its brand of formula.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Beginners (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/beginners-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/beginners-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The one thing fresh about this movie is the loving portrayal of an
elderly gay man, which is something I don&#x27;t remember seeing before. The
direction is also pretty competent, and so is the acting. Pity it&#x27;s
being boring, and it&#x27;s slight bizarredness (e.g. talking dog) help make
it real unbearable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Please Give (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/please-give-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/please-give-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The uniqueness of the opening scene (breasts), and it&#x27;s song, provides
a good hint that you are about to be treated to something special, and
the movie does not disappoint, all until the needless cheating moment.
It&#x27;s very well-made and well-acted, and the spa gal has never been this
interesting. The dialog is incredible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Postal (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/postal-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/postal-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is special for being the first movie I saw poking fun at the
9&#x2F;11 disaster, where the plane crashing onto the skyscraper is portrayed
as an accident. The rest of it is seriously unconventional, some good,
too much of it uninteresting, and the whole thing pointless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zoolander (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zoolander-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zoolander-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Stiller gives &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;favorite-of-career-performances&quot;&gt;the most interesting performance of his career&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and
perhaps the only one I ever enjoyed. Sadly, he gives the only
interesting performance in the movie. Luckily, the movie makes up for
this with various hilarious moments, one favorite being the
playing-with-fire scene.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Felon (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/felon-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/felon-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a strange one because it feels so pointless by the end of it,
unless it&#x27;s just another anti-prison movie, in which case it&#x27;s pretty
much effective... the brutality is incredible. It&#x27;s also the first
time I&#x27;ve ever seen Harrold Perrineau play villain, and he is not so
convincing. The movie itself is very well-made, and the acting decent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Faster (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/faster-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/faster-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that this is a second rate actioner that isn&#x27;t overall decent, I
was not going to write a review about it, except that I actually found
the twist quite unique. I am temped to say &lt;em&gt;surprising&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but that&#x27;s
what twists are supposed to be. But this one is especially so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effort to make the professional assassin interesting worked pretty
well, considering it could have been a lot more cheesier&#x2F;cheaper. The
girlfriend of that assassin is extra-lovely too, and gives a decent
performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Kids Are All Right (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-kids-are-all-right-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-kids-are-all-right-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Julianne Moore and Annette Bening give incredible performances in
superbly-directed movie where they play lesbian mothers whose lives are
to be challenged by a stranger... sperm donor of their kids, also
played well by Mark Ruffalo. The issue is that he&#x27;s made so kool that
he&#x27;s not believable, and the contention he presents feels forced. It&#x27;s
an excellent premise, and interesttingly one that I haven&#x27;t seen
explored before, but the makers just didn&#x27;t know where to take the
story. I also don&#x27;t know what the point of it all is and it leaves a
few questions open.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Johnny English Reborn (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/johnny-english-reborn-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/johnny-english-reborn-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this a lot due to the delicious humor, best of which was the
out-of-control chair... absolutely hilarious. It was all nice, until
they had to do the stupid thing of bringing someone from the dead.
Instead of parodying the silly idea, they just fall prey to it. The end
is also lazy, and as uninteresting as the villain. Johnny&#x27;s sidekick is
a strange choice for a movie character, while Rosamund Pike seems a
goddess. How could anyone look like that! WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Infidel (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-infidel-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-infidel-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very different comedy with a very unlikely lead; I loved the
performance of the extremist Muslim leader, especially when in the house
of the infidel; the end, where a con-man is exposed, is a lousy cop-out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Streetcar Named Desire (1951)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-streetcar-named-desire-1951/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-streetcar-named-desire-1951/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The direction is shitty and the performances unbearably-irritating, most
especially the mentally-challended leading character (by Vivien Leigh).
As if that&#x27;s not enough, there&#x27;s also a horrible asshole played by
Marlon Brando. The only believable character is that of the lady
upstairs, though she isn&#x27;t given much screen time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is among the most irritatingly-unbearable movies I&#x27;ve yet seen.
How the movie, and its performances, got so much praise is hard to
fathom. What the fuck!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Change of Plans (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/change-of-plans-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/change-of-plans-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Brooke_White&quot;&gt;Brooke White&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the lead female performer, scores quite high on the
desirability charts, while the music her character does sucks hard. The
movie feels fresh (it&#x27;s not your typical pro-family fare), but not the
&amp;quot;family about to break apart&amp;quot; moment near the end, which is just too
common. Worse is that it&#x27;s annoying and feels contrived (and a better
actor should have been in the place of the government lady). The
attitude the older girl shows is also just too common, but it&#x27;s a
decent performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Izulu Lami (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/izulu-lami-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/izulu-lami-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the natural-looking performance of Tshepang Mohlomi, who plays
the leader of a gang of street kids. Also, his character is given some
depth: he appears an asshole on the sufrace, but is actually a nice guy
who, for example, allows his ass to get ripped apart, only to share the
rewards with the rest of the gang.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display of chilhood innocence (and naivéty) is done well, but sadly
none of the grown-ups are given any attention, all but the sister of the
dead mother, who gives the movie&#x27;s best performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bob The Butler (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bob-the-butler-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bob-the-butler-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a recycled story of a guy who appears to be a loser, but happens
to be quite useful when put in some specific situation. I appreciate it
because, regardless of being formulaic and shallow, it feels fresh --
it has unusual, laid-back direction, and quality comic performances from
the lead and, most especially, the master butler. It screws up with
it&#x27;s needless use of slapstick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Ides of March (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-ides-of-march-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-ides-of-march-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected a far more hard-hitting story, considering this is a modern
and high-end political drama. What I got was not interesting enough to
deserve going straight to cinema. It feels unfinished. Any random
episode of &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is superior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gal is very wantable though, and the wife of the presidential
candidate (played by George Clooney) gives a decent performance, but is
denied screen appearance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Robot (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robot-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robot-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though incredibly shallow, formulaic, and ludicrous, it is entertaining
at times. Also the beauty of the leading lady is without flaw and her
dance moves wonderful (there&#x27;s stupid full-length music sequences a few
times in the movie), and sex appeal nearly absent (though I would not
refuse an invitation).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anger the creator shows towards the robot is annoying (both given
unsatisfying performances), and is most unbearable at the moment when he
gets to break it apart. It&#x27;s too common &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;unforgiving-characters-are-annoying&quot;&gt;a flaw in Hollywood movies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
and it&#x27;s sad to see it in a movie from a different market. The anger is
totally unjustfified because the robot has that time done various good
deeds, including saving a girl from being raped, saving a number of
people from fire, as well as helping a woman in difficult labour. All
that is conveniently forgotten... it&#x27;s just unberarable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It&#x27;s a Wonderful Life (1946)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/it-s-a-wonderful-life-1946/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/it-s-a-wonderful-life-1946/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s sprinkled with some fun moments and interesting performances, but
I cannot forgive some of its shallow writing, especially the fantasy
moments near the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s one especially gorgeous woman (the wife), and one especially
desirable one (the seductive near-lover). The lead has his moments,
though his character&#x27;s self-importance is often annoying, though it was
probably interesting to audiences of the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite performace is by the lady playing Miss &amp;quot;Could I have
1750?&amp;quot; Davis, though it&#x27;s a very small role, lasting just a few
seconds. That performance also feels out of place in the movie of this
age... it feels a lot more modern.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;ebb.org&#x2F;bkuhn&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2008&#x2F;12&#x2F;24&#x2F;capra-free-software.html&quot;&gt;A review that inspired me to watch this movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Missing (1982)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/missing-1982/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/missing-1982/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The wife character, played by Sissy Spacek, is not only
superbly-developed, but also desirable as fuck. Not only that, but it&#x27;s
a wonderful performance. The father character is however given the
movie&#x27;s best character development, as well as its best performance.
One other great performance is that of the bubbly guy from the US
military.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director offers an exhilarating and well-written investigative
thriller, much like his earlier &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;z-1969&quot;&gt;Z (1969)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a more intense work, though
lesser overall. The subject matter is grim and the imagery horrific. The
filmstock is of shitty quality sadly, perhaps a deliberate decision, to
help make viewers feel unease.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Trade (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/trade-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/trade-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The pretty brother of the gal who gets kidnapped for sex should have
been given less screen time. Either that or more acting classes. Same
applies to his sister, the victim, though to a greater extent. I wonder
if Kevin Kline took the role because his career isn&#x27;t doing so good, or
because of the subject matter (one would hope for the latter). I wonder
what&#x27;s up with the guy driving the victims to their fates. He
represents a failed attempt at a portrayal of a bad guy with some good
inside of him, but is given a real poor performance. In conclusion, I
really think the director is bad, and should not have been allowed to
head a movie that carries such an important message.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Z (1969)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/z-1969/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/z-1969/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Weirdly humorous, especially given the serious subject matter of a
police-controlled plot to assassinate a politician who stirs things up.
It&#x27;s pretty unique, and very well-directed, and the relentlessness of
the guy in charge of investigating the whole thing admirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Arthur (1981)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/arthur-1981/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/arthur-1981/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rottentomatoes.com&#x2F;m&#x2F;1001240-arthur&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The world&#x27;s critics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; amaze me again, with their love for this
uninteresting and (mostly) unfunny comedy. Someone even nominated it for
its script. WTF! &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;arthur-2011&quot;&gt;The sequel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a lot better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some appeal to the lead performer, but he&#x27;s mostly just
annoying. None of the other performances are particularly good, except
of course &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;John_Gielgud&quot;&gt;the guy playing the caregiver&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who never fucks up anyways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Appleseed Ex Machina (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-ex-machina-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/appleseed-ex-machina-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The lead character from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;appleseed-2004&quot;&gt;the first movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; takes a backseat somewhat,
making way for the cyborg friend and former lover, and to a lesser
extent, the lover&#x27;s clone, as well as to multiple other key characters.
It&#x27;s an interesting concept actually, and I haven&#x27;t seen it explored
before: that the clone looks and acts so much like the former lover
presents a challenge, and the conflict is apparent, but not overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The director, who also directed the first movie, has worsened his
obsession with beautiful people. There&#x27;s a lot more of them here,
although I did really like a senior representative of some weapons
manufacturing company named Poseidon. She&#x27;s presented with greater
admiration than the lead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The action does not offer any real improvement over the previous movie,
even though the budget is 3 times as large. It&#x27;s also not as
interesting. The animation is of more consistent quality than the first
movie, but there&#x27;s nothing really groundbreaking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Why the fuck did they have to drastically change the
physical look of Athena (basically the president of the city) so much?
She&#x27;s not even recognizable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Bang-Bang Club (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-bang-bang-club-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-bang-bang-club-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Comments on articles tend to be bad, and if you are lucky, just decent.
They are seldom outstanding though, as seen of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theglobeandmail.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;arts&#x2F;movies&#x2F;the-bang-bang-club-fizzles-with-compromises&#x2F;article2011622&#x2F;comments&#x2F;&quot;&gt;these ones&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which are
critical of the article they respond to. Basically what&#x27;s happening is
that the critic does offer a decent review, summarizing the story
nicely, but then resorts to unjustified criticism. That is sad,
especially because I found the movie quite good. Read them (the
comments), for they are better reviews than mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still going to given mine of course, by mentioning two main things
I really appreciate about the movie:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The portrayal South Africa (my home) is quite authentic. There was
good research effort involved, to the point of even using the
now-obsolete cash. The behavior and the utterances of Black people
wasn&#x27;t screwed up either (as it so often happens when foreigners
set a movie here). The one complaint I have is that the white guys
aren&#x27;t convincing as South Africans, and there doesn&#x27;t seem to be
any real effort to mimic local accents. I even thought that the real
life Club members were foreigners.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was amazed by the performance of one local actor, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.google.co.za&#x2F;search?q=patrick+shai&quot;&gt;Patrick Shai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
I&#x27;ve never given kudos to the guy, though he never got a heck of a
lot of chances to strut his stuff (the local movie industry is
nearly non-existent), but he really shined here, and gives the
movie&#x27;s best performance. I also find his character to be the
movie&#x27;s most interesting because, regardless of him being among the
leaders of a small group of tribal killers, he also happens to have
a soft side... literally a savior of one heroic guy. Watching him
was a serious relief since I was concerned that these guys would be
some sort of faceless aggressors&#x2F;victims. Sure about all of them
were, but at least there was him, and one other guy saddened by the
death of wife and child.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an important movie, and it&#x27;s sad that it hasn&#x27;t achieved the
popularity it deserves. I&#x27;m still not going to claim it&#x27;s a
masterpiece because, other than that performance, I&#x27;m not sure I wanna
give it a repeat viewing. It&#x27;s not because it&#x27;s unpleasant. It just
feels that what kept me glued were moments that won&#x27;t be so thrilling
second time around. I don&#x27;t know, I&#x27;ll see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nit-picks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That scene depicting &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;iconicphotos.wordpress.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;08&#x2F;12&#x2F;vulture-stalking-a-child&#x2F;&quot;&gt;vulture and child in hungry Sudan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; should not
have been attempted, or at least removed from the movie. It adds
nothing to the movie, and too iconic a moment of history to be given
such a lame attempt. For one, the child in the movie didn&#x27;t look as
bony.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was left hungry for further exploration of the political climate
of South Africa, beyond the unconvincing angry Black guy criticizing
the White guys from profiting from taking photos of those in pain.
In fact I think it&#x27;s this sort of thing that makes the
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theglobeandmail.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;arts&#x2F;movies&#x2F;the-bang-bang-club-fizzles-with-compromises&#x2F;article2011622&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&#x27;unjustified&#x27; criticism&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I mentioned above make some sense. Such
things tend to only dawn on me some time after the movie has ended.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Arthur (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/arthur-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/arthur-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A large part of this romantic comedy is quite enjoyable, and helped much
by the delightful and rather fresh performance by the lead, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Russell_Brand&quot;&gt;Russell
Brand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He also gave me &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;2011-movie-review&quot;&gt;one of 2011&#x27;s best performances&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;get-him-to-the-greek-2010&quot;&gt;Get Him to
the Greek&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), so it was great watching him offering similar acting style.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest happens to be &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-unbearable-hollywood-romantic-comedy-formula&quot;&gt;the formula that too many Hollywood romantic
comedies tend to adopt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it&#x27;s so fucking annoying. Nick Nolte&#x27;s
character was neither interesting nor portrayed well. In fact, he&#x27;s
embarassing. The lead girl is fucking desirable, but her character was
made annoyingly uptight, since it had to fit in with that formula I
mentioned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Horrible Bosses (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/horrible-bosses-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/horrible-bosses-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of hilarious moments, though none is as great as
the pregnancy one; Jamie Foxx does a nice bit performance; the character
of Kevin Spacey is rather overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is fun, but it sadly has a sketchy, amateurish feel of &lt;em&gt;The
40-Year-Old Virgin&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Office Space&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, both of which were also fun. It
just feels like a collection of antics, instead of one solid whole
worthy of being called a movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>J. Edgar (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/j-edgar-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/j-edgar-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The production design is top-class (impeccable set design and props),
while the old-age make-up is embarassingly bad. Even the 2 actors
playing the aging characters are unbearable to watch, perhaps as
unbearable as the immensely unpleasant character of J. Edgar Hoover. The
movie itself starts okay, but starts to be really boring and pointless.
I was surprised that it was made by the great Clint Eastwood. It must be
his worst.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Anonymous (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/anonymous-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/anonymous-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I praised the costume and production design when the movie began, but
not later on. I either stopped caring, or the excellence wasn&#x27;t
sustained somehow, I just don&#x27;t know. I was also impressed by the 2
ladies who portrayed Queen Elizabeth I. The conspiracy story wasn&#x27;t so
riveting since I&#x27;ve heard it before (and I don&#x27;t care much since I
think Shakespeare is overrated, either that or I&#x27;m not smart&#x2F;cultured
enough to enjoy his work). The movie is however very well-made, and non
of it bores at all, even though it loses steam part-way through.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hangover Part II (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hangover-part-ii-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hangover-part-ii-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t expect much from this since it was trashed by critics, but
found it quite entertaining, and filled with interesting characters. My
favorite is the character played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ken_Jeong&quot;&gt;Ken Jeong&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a fun-loving criminal
with feminine mannerisms. One other great thing about the movie is the
setting, which portrays Bang Kok is some gritty, seedy city, where crime
is rampant and the police under-resourced. It feels authentic, whether
or not it&#x27;s based on reality. It&#x27;s a showcase of good production
design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having watched the previous (and lesser) movie also makes one appreciate
this one more, even though the formula is the same.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Black Death (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/black-death-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/black-death-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very grim portrayal of a witch hunt motivated by an epidemic in some
ancient European area. It&#x27;s well-made and well-acted, and the battles
are more convincing than the more expensive movies set in its time, and
violence more brutal. There&#x27;s not one light-hearted moment, no comic
sidekick, just a whole lot of shit life. Lucky me being born here and
now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Secretariat (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/secretariat-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/secretariat-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite my dislike of the subject (animal abuse for the sake of
entertainment and profit), I was curious enough to watch the whole
thing. It&#x27;s competently-made and got some decent performances, but it
is merely yet-another sports movie, only this time involving animals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Science of Sleep (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-science-of-sleep-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-science-of-sleep-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Much like the first experience I had with &lt;em&gt;Underground&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, I found this
unbearably irritating. This is due to the bizarre storyline and
directing, as well as an eccentric&#x2F;insane lead character.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desirable gals, especially the main love interest (played by
Charlotte Gainsbourg), makes it survivable. The romantic drama involving
her almost makes the movie worthwhile, and her performance is
amazing&#x2F;flawless. The gal playing the friend is a lot prettier though,
while the one playing the colleague isn&#x27;t bad either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Iron Lady (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-iron-lady-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-iron-lady-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonderful cast:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meryl Streep is good as usual in the lead role, though I wasn&#x27;t
entirely satisfied with her portrayal of modern-day (frail) Margaret
Thatcher.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lady playing the young Margaret, Alexandra Roach, is amazing,
and her performance the movie&#x27;s most interesting. I&#x27;m even tempted
to call it the movie&#x27;s best, but am held back from that opinion
given that it&#x27;s pretty much carecatured.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The guy playing the modern day husband, Margaret&#x27;s hallucination of
a dead man, Jim Broadbent, offers nice and laid-back humor.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direction is sophisticated and smooth, though there&#x27;s too much
focus on the modern-day Margaret, with so many flashbacks that it&#x27;s
just distracting. I also left the movie feeling like I still don&#x27;t know
enough about this 20th century giant. Perhaps the treatment was a little
too humorous, and too soft, especially considering the great importance
of the issues involved in Margaret Thatcher&#x27;s reign as prime minister.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Battleship (2012)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/battleship-2012/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/battleship-2012/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Real nice visual effects, some of the best I&#x27;ve seen yet:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the wheel-of-destruction and the destruction it wields make for some
of the most impressive character designs ever; the design isn&#x27;t so
fresh... it&#x27;s inspired by some similar machinery in one of the
&lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&#x27;s not groundbreaking, but the facial rendering of the aliens is
amazing; it&#x27;s not at the level of a Davey Jones or a Kong though&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie isn&#x27;t as big and loud as the &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie series, but
the concept is a lot less silly, and the story a lot less annoying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most surprising thing about the movie is the appearance of the
leg-less guy, some ugly big guy who gives a wonderful performance, the
most interesting in the movie. It&#x27;s surprising because I&#x27;ve never seen
the guy before, and that a crippled character would be given such a key
role. Sure there was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-1964&quot;&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but that was a comedy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was sad when the movie ended, both because it was too short, and
because there was no explanation on what the aliens wanted. What made
this even sadder is fact that they appeared not wholly evil, making them
more interesting. I even thought that, later in the movie, there would
be something like &lt;em&gt;stop fighting us; we come in peace&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Remember Me (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/remember-me-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/remember-me-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts in a very promising way, with a well-directed
robbery-and-murder scene, complete with great camerawork, pacing, and
acting. Sadly, the movie soon turns into some soppy, uninteresting
romance, with two uninteresting lovers, whose characters appear to
desperately feel interesting. Luckily we get good performances from
Chris Cooper (as always) and Pierce Brosnan, both playing the respective
fathers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire exercise feels pointless though, and the Sep 11 reference
needless. What the fuck is up with that?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>After the Rain (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/after-the-rain-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/after-the-rain-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the duels, especially the bloody one (the only such in the
movie). I enjoyed the music, singing, and rejoicing of the poor people
in the inn even more. The greatest moment in the movie, one thing that
brought tear to eye, is the act of kindness that the lead character
showed toward the unruly and disliked prostitute.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wife of the lead is a badly-developed character. The attempt to make
her angelic is nearly ludicrous, and the performer isn&#x27;t skilled enough
to help achieve the goal. Another bad character, though to a lesser
extent, is the political leader. His portrayal is too fierce to
convince.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the movie is rather empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Company Men (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-company-men-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-company-men-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Smooth, laid-back direction, with nice sets; It&#x27;s a small peak at the
effects of a troubled company on the employees who lose their jobs;
it&#x27;s well-made, except that it gets tired within an hour, and there
isn&#x27;t much left for the rest of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bad Teacher (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bad-teacher-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bad-teacher-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another comedy that relies heavily on goofiness for its laughs, and
pretty effective at that. It is in large part due to the
overly-competitive and pretentious rival teacher, played well by Lucy
Punch. Another good performance is by Justin Timberlake, playing an even
goofier yes-man. The lead performance by Cameron Diaz is extremely
uninteresting, but luckily her students are well-cast, and a very
non-standard cast at that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly the movie is ridiculously shallow, and there is no battle to
fight, and nothing is resolved... I don&#x27;t know what the fuck it&#x27;s
about. It feels very incomplete. Even the quality cast is underused (I
wish I could see more of Timberlake, the fat teacher, the kids, and much
less of Cameron Diaz).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lorenzo&#x27;s Oil (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/lorenzo-s-oil-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/lorenzo-s-oil-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Offers some insight in medical science processes, but there is at least
one concept that was dumbed down too much (Why volume of specific
compound rises when intake of food containing it is reduced?). I&#x27;m sure
it was for the lay audience, but I don&#x27;t think the audience is that
stupid. Nick Nolte is annoying and unconvincing with the Italian accent
while Susan Sarandon&#x27;s character is annoying with her obsession and
selfishness. Their perseverance is admirable though, as well as their
efforts to help discover the treatment for the disease their son suffers
from.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balanced view of the scientific community vs. the parents is handled
quite well, and isn&#x27;t as simplified as you&#x27;d come to expect in movies.
The scientists and those who respect them aren&#x27;t viewed with
incompetence (let&#x27;s ignore the dumbed-down part) or laziness, only with
the eye that they do have other priorities which are not necessarily
less urgent&#x2F;important than the one faced by the parents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mississippi Burning (1988)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mississippi-burning-1988/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mississippi-burning-1988/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A mildly entertaining drama about some FBI guys investigating some
race-related violent crimes, which gets tiring about halfway through.
None of the characters are really interesting, nor is the acting, except
that Frances McDormand is a bit lovely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Serpico (1973)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/serpico-1973/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/serpico-1973/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was attracted to this because of the story of a guy who exposed police
corruption, but it turned out to be unbearably boring. Al Pacino gives a
decent performance, but it&#x27;s not enough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Dirty Shame (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-dirty-shame-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-dirty-shame-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching the faces made by the lead actor. Some funny shit.
Sadly, the movie&#x27;s only worthy moment is where her character dances
with old people. I love her daughter too, but that&#x27;s mere sexual
attraction (she&#x27;s totally wantable!?). Other than that, there&#x27;s some
minor things that entertain, but the rest of the movie is crap. I don&#x27;t
get what the point is. It&#x27;s too overdone to be funny, and if it&#x27;s
supposed to be satirical, it&#x27;s the worst I&#x27;ve seen. The movie would
have been far more effective if the sex-crazed people didn&#x27;t look so
idiotic. Fuck, some even have supernatural powers. Why didn&#x27;t the
makers of the movie do some decent visual effects?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I get the vibe that the director is a lot more capable
that what he displays here, so maybe I&#x27;m missing the point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Birth (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/birth-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/birth-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicole Kidman is kick-ass and so is her acting +++ check the almost
unbearable intensity she portrays at some high-brow show (probably
opera) which she visits with her boyfriend. The script is damn amazing
too, and so is the camerawork, and this, a drama, is among the most
suspenseful movies I&#x27;ve ever seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit rendered the movie a litle boring, but the performances and
great direction kept it interesting. The story also felt a lot more
silly. I can even understand why the movie was so heavily panned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Real Steel (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/real-steel-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/real-steel-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The kid actor playing the lead&#x27;s son, Dakota Goyo, gives a real good
performance and his character is really interesting and unpredictable,
just the like the movie. The lady playing the lead&#x27;s love interest is
quite good too. The movie is strange, directed in an unusual manner,
such that I didn&#x27;t enjoy much of it, especially the first half. It
started being a little fun when I started seeing some action on stage,
but there wasn&#x27;t even enough of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asshole levels of the lead character (played by Hugh Jackman in a
surprisingly decent performance) are hard to bear, when he is being an
ass. The redneck is given a memorable performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Sunset Limited (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-sunset-limited-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-sunset-limited-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This I watched merely for the sake of curiosity: the entire movie takes
place in a single room and has only two characters engaged in one long
conversation. They discuss a number of issues (god, suicide, jail, bad
deeds, friendship...). Samuel L. Jackson is as unsatisfying (and noisy)
as usual while Tommy Lee Jones should have done something more fitting
of his acting skills. It happens to be mainly noise about nothing, and
me wonders what the point is (life sucks?). Beware of some really bad
usage of sound effects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Colombiana (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/colombiana-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/colombiana-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For almost it&#x27;s entire running length, it&#x27;s very fast-paced, a fact
that helps hide its incompetence, considering that there&#x27;s nothing new
or fresh, other than having the first young girl action hero I&#x27;ve seen
yet. Hers portrayal is not convincing, even when grown up. However,
there&#x27;s a good performance by the guy playing the lead FBI agent
(&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lennie_James&quot;&gt;Lennie James&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), who recently impressed me in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-next-three-days-2010&quot;&gt;The Next Three Days&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
The subplot involving the love interest was a waste of time, although it
was well-made, as is the movie in general.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Swordsman II (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/swordsman-ii-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/swordsman-ii-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The romantic relationship between Jet Li&#x27;s lead character and that of
the lead villain (he didn&#x27;t suspect anything about his&#x2F;her
villainy&#x2F;sexuality) is both the most important and my favorite in the
movie. This lead character is surrounded by at least two other lovely
women (me want them), both of whom appear to have the hearts for him,
but he doesn&#x27;t once make a move on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a very low budget movie, but the martial arts choreography is
impressive. The direction is a little unfocused, and the humor does get
in the way of that focus... the balance between comedy and drama isn&#x27;t
quite right, as is so common with old Jet Li movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Legend (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-legend-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-legend-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Real nice opening credits visuals, some interesting martial arts, and a
weird thing where the main story ends way before the end of the movie.
It&#x27;s like the makers were honest enough to realise that they didn&#x27;t
have much material, and decided to start another subplot involving some
Russian fighters challenge our hero. As is usual with these martial arts
Chinese movies, the white foreigners receive some seriously shallow
character development, and happen to be unconvincingly evil.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lead character is done poorly by Vincent Zhao, the same guy who
spoiled &lt;em&gt;Once Upon A Time In China&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; series by replacing Jet Li in the
4th and 5th movies in the series. I don&#x27;t remember enjoying any of his
other performances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ferris Bueller&#x27;s Day Off (1986)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/ferris-bueller-s-day-off-1986/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/ferris-bueller-s-day-off-1986/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbearably slow pacing, maybe the worst I&#x27;ve experienced yet. The gal
playing jealous sister is desirable, while the guy playing friend gives
a decent performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Midnight in Paris (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/midnight-in-paris-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/midnight-in-paris-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this only because Woody Allen made it, and now I wish he was
the one playing the lead character, not a poor imitator. The fantasy
element of it is a bit interesting (no one in my experience has made
such a smooth and unassuming time travel movie) but there&#x27;s a feel of
self-importance about the whole thing and that&#x27;s annoying and makes it
unbearable. Maybe Woody is getting lazy and arrogant. I haven&#x27;t seen
all of his work, but this is likely his worst. The costumes are nice
though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
