<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/documentary/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Music is the Weapon (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/music-is-the-weapon-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/music-is-the-weapon-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have deep respect for Fela Kuti&#x27;s musicianship, and more than any
other musician I&#x27;ve ever listened to. His intense love for the craft,
though I suspect that it may at times been detrimental to those
surrounding him, is hard to beat. His political views seemed relevant
too, as he mentions Nigerian government&#x27;s oppressive acts, one of which
resulted in the death of his mother. How he was going to help correct
these injustices is another thing altogether&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fela Kuti was an eccentric character, at least as portrayed. He had the
fearless attitude of an traditional activist, which is a quality I
admire (and lack). He also promoted and practiced traditional African
religion (while opposing Christianity and Islam), and polygamy, which is
okay in itself, until the fact that the women themselves would not be
allowed to have other partners. Maybe Fela didn&#x27;t mind it (he din&#x27;t
mention it), but I doubt it. That&#x27;s some double standards which I
really hate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentary itself is pretty decent, but lacks the depth I was
hoping for. I guess I&#x27;m more interested in the musical Fela Kuti than
the politics, even though one heavily influenced the other, making it
hard to separrate the two. But check out &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.com&#x2F;review&#x2F;R28YF6P9MDOEPS&#x2F;ref=cm_cr_dp_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B000079DF9&amp;amp;nodeID=130&amp;amp;tag=&amp;amp;linkCode=&quot;&gt;this quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which is
far better and more detailed than I can muster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
