<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2009-movie/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Inglourious Basterds (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/inglourious-basterds-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first scene is top-class, for the performance of the weary farmer
when forced to make an unpleasant choice, the sort where I feel
self-death is better. The best performance of the movie however is that
of Christoph Waltz, who plays the Nazi officer questioning him. Brad
Pitt is quite limited in terms of talent but not charisma, and is
provides the weakest performance of all key characters. Quentin
Tarantino is a weirdo who possesses the freedom (perhaps too much) to
paint whatever he pleases on screen, and luckily got the talent. He
gives this one superb suspense, exciting dialog, unusual (and
unpredictable) story, and wonderful editing. It&#x27;s my favorite and best
of all his works, followed by &lt;em&gt;Reservoir Dogs&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting, and rare, thing is I enjoyed the movie a lot more on a
revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Changeling (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/changeling-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/changeling-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie has some great elements: production design, costume design,
cinematography, direction, and cast, especially John Malkovich, who
gives his best performance I&#x27;ve yet seen. The story itself is okay
enough, but I enjoyed it a lot more on the first viewing. I also enjoyed
Angelina Jolie&#x27;s performance as grieving mother on that first viewing
than on this revisit, even going as far as calling it her best yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Network (1976)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/network-1976/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/network-1976/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s what I wrote in 2009:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a strong satire like &lt;em&gt;Network&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, complete with powerful appearances
by Faye Dunaway and Robert Duvall, one tends to wish the entire thing
was shot and edited at least as well as it&#x27;s mightier counterpart,
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-1964&quot;&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s got quite some heavy-handed dialog that may
have inspired the superior and much younger &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;good-night-and-good-luck-2005&quot;&gt;Good Night &amp;amp; Good Luck&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
What&#x27;s also commendable is that the one voice of sane reason actually
is offered by a man who is likely more cruel than all others in the
story (bar those in the last meeting of course, a moment which would
be a spoiler if revealed).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit, as usual, didn&#x27;t impress as much. I still appreciate the
humor and satire, but the fact that it made me feel asleep is not a good
thing. I didn&#x27;t even enjoy the two performances I so praised above. I
don&#x27;t even remember who I was referring to by &lt;em&gt;one voice of sane
reason&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and the latter movie I mentioned is a lesser movie overall. One
thing I still celebrate though is that very last scene... the meeting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men Origins: Wolverine (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-origins-wolverine-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-origins-wolverine-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The worst in the X-Men movies, it just feels like an excuse to milk the
brand. Fact that the production was troubled probably explains it. None
of the visual effects are any good, and the location of the final fight,
top of the cooling towers, was quite stupid... why did Wolverine go
there? Also, why did my favorite guy had to wear such a stupid and
unconvincing fat suit? Horrible!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tokyo Story (1953)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tokyo-story-1953/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tokyo-story-1953/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Weird why this gets such great accolades from top critics. Sure it&#x27;s
not bad and it&#x27;s actually well-made, but I don&#x27;t see anything that is
truly exceptional. It does however tell a very universal story,
regardless of familiarity with Japanese culture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is extreme kindness and modesty in a widowed girl, often to a
point of ridiculousness, but then again such angels actually exist. My
favorite performance is that of the more pro-active&#x2F;talkative daughter,
one who scolds her father a bit about his drinking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the acting, where the characters face the camera, is just
awkward, forcing one to notice lack of ability, most especially from the
lady playing the mother.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie was a lot less bearable on first viewing, due mainly to being
overly slow-paced, as well as being eventless. I did appreciate it more
on this revisit, perhaps because I could easily look past the stylistic
choice, and instead enjoy the ride where we get treated to quality
character development and a rather simple story sprinkled with extremely
polite people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>District 9 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/district-9-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/district-9-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The documentary style has been employed elsewhere before, but there&#x27;s
nothing quite like &lt;em&gt;District 9&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in all movie history. Its weird and
wonderful story starts off with nice comic touches and transitions into
a harrowing tale of human torture, and ends as some action-adventure of
sorts, complete with superb visual effects, with some nice creature
ideas. Sure there&#x27;s warts here and there, but to have a gem like this
emerge from my country of residence, South Africa, is quite something.
It is the best movie based there. The lead performance also deserves
applaud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Yellow Earth (1984)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/yellow-earth-1984/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/yellow-earth-1984/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A harrowing tale of a woman yearning for freedom in poor and rural
China. It is a very meditative work, more powerful than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2009-05-04&quot;&gt;Raise the Red
Lantern&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and full of raw emotion (check especialy the guy who plays the
father, the movie&#x27;s strongest actor) and simple in terms of
storytelling. It also showcases the side of China I never really saw so
vividly displayed, the musical side. The movie is touching to the point
of tears.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst all the pain is at least one hilarious moment which involves
bed-wetting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Watchmen (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/watchmen-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/watchmen-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watchmen is bizarre in a delightful manner, though it has annoying black
spots all over the place. One major one is everything about the
too-powerful shining guy (Mr Manhattan), and another is the bad old-age
make-up, so bad it may be deliberate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bright spots make up for this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the performance of The Comedian, especially the moment when he kills
a pregnant lady, pregnant with his child&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the equally affective one where the disguised face is exposed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of brutality in the movie, including the supposedly-nice
protagonists breaking bones needlessly. The scene itself, where they get
attacked by some oriental guys, is stupid. Either that, or it is some
sort of parody, as is the case with the War Room thing, parodying a
(great) satire, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;dr-strangelove-1964&quot;&gt;Dr. Strangelove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one werid movie that I just don&#x27;t know how to place, so will
leave it here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Baise-moi (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/baise-moi-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/baise-moi-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A low-key French-language and less cartoonish answer to &lt;em&gt;Natural Born
Killers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It also has affecting and believable performances and a
horrific, painful, and powerful story which also feels as random and
undirected as its two leads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best performance is that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Raffa%C3%ABla_Anderson&quot;&gt;Raffaëla Anderson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the more
trigger-happy of the 2 girls. It is sad that she has not done anything
else of significance, beyond porn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one complaint I have is that the switch between &#x27;sad girls&#x27; to
&#x27;killer girls&#x27; is not really explained, and rather sudden.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>There Will Be Blood (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/there-will-be-blood-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/there-will-be-blood-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is how I felt on first viewing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Daniel-Day Lewis&#x27; oil driller in &lt;em&gt;There Will Be Blood&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, I
don&#x27;t remember any other character in movie history as ruthless as Al
Pacino&#x27;s in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2007-11-05&quot;&gt;Scarface&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;; Lewis&#x27; however is tougher, darker, and even
better-developed, rendering Pacino&#x27;s seem a mere maniac. None of the
other performances has any noticeable flaw either and the movie starts
like a masterpiece (the first few moments of silence showcases
top-class direction, the characters are amazing, etc.) and, though it
never lowers to the level of common fare, doesn&#x27;t quite reach the
pinnacle. The end leaves one wishing there could be more to the story,
perhaps a bit of color to an otherwise painful movie (there&#x27;s not a
single ray of light, bar the barely-explored romance of the lead&#x27;s
son). Interestingly, the entire work isn&#x27;t as depressing as the story
suggests, but rather more of an adventure, as well as a unique and
powerful exploration of mining life, not to mention a graphical
depiction of the dangers it entails.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a revisit, I take back the claim that Lewis&#x27; character is actually
tougher than Pacino&#x27;s. The rest of the review is still accurate though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to add that the cast is among the best I have seen yet in
movies. In addition to the magnificent Lewis:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Paul_Dano&quot;&gt;Paul Dano&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gives an incredible performance, one that is so good me
wonders if he can ever equal it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dillon_Freasier&quot;&gt;Dillon Frasier&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gives among the most impressive child performances
ever. It is all the more impressive that this was his first
performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie could have done well with a different ending though, for the
one it has is a bit over-the-top, even though not pointless. This is not
to say it is not well-made of course, for it is in fact among the
best-made of all in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Frost&#x2F;Nixon (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/frost-nixon-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/frost-nixon-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Frank Langella, a decent actor, is a little embarassing when portraying
the infamous Richard Nixon. He does a caricature, and is given way too
much screen time, almost to a point where he is hard to bear. He must
have been having fun doing the performance, which must have been easy as
hell... stuff of comedies. The rest of the movie is very well-made and
does not bore for a minute.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the sad things of watching a movie based on actual events is the
tendnecy to wonder how much of it is fiction. As for this movie,
Wikipedia has &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Frost&#x2F;Nixon_(film)#Dramatic_license_and_factual_inaccuracies&quot;&gt;a nice collection of such cases&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Terminator Salvation (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/terminator-salvation-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/terminator-salvation-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked the concept of the robo-bikes and... nothing else. The movie is
very unentertaining, and even disturbing at times. Not one character is
interesting, nor is any performance. The first two movies in the
franchise were a lot more watchable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Avatar (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/avatar-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/avatar-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;good&quot;&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The best thing in the movie is the tribal humanoid creatures; they
are given solid and believable personalities, as if they actually
exist. The best work is the leading lady, who also happens to be
damn fucking&#x27; desirable. I also loved the female spiritual leader
(she got presence).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire experience of those humanoids riding flying creatures is
pure movie magic. The creatures they ride are quite impressive
(check for example when our hero is to tame one for the first time).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of Avatars is quite unique and fresh... it would be
interesting to experience another body.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The human characters were not given quality treatment, all but the
lead (the image of him and his wheelchair is iconic). Most
unconvincing is the scarred military leader, followed by the
corporate representative (Giovanni Ribisi).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general feel of the alien world feels too artificial (there&#x27;s
too many bright-colored plants and animals). The creature design is
not satisfactory.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The helicopter driver lady should have been excluded. She is just
not an interesting actor, and cheapens the movie further.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-others-feel&quot;&gt;what others feel&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked this &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;12&#x2F;22&#x2F;opening-pandoras-box-the-arguments-over-avatar&#x2F;&quot;&gt;short analysis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One commenter &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;12&#x2F;22&#x2F;opening-pandoras-box-the-arguments-over-avatar&#x2F;#comment5&quot;&gt;correctly noted&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; stylistic similarities to the
much-deplored Jar Jar Binks of Star Wars fame.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also enjoyed a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.huffingtonpost.com&#x2F;ray-kurzweil&#x2F;reflections-on-iavatari_b_500226.html&quot;&gt;disapproving review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by a famous inventor and
futurist, Ray Kurzweil.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shoot &#x27;Em Up (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shoot-em-up-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shoot-em-up-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The main villain is annoying to watch and the gorgeous love prostitute
uninteresting. The lead character is interesting enough, and so is the
action. Some of the humor, none of which is actually funny, is taken a
bit too far (one guy kills another with a carrot).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the camerawork but not the negative view the writers have on the
customers of sex workers. It&#x27;s too shallow, just like the movie, though
luckily it doesn&#x27;t pretend not to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Revenge of the Fallen (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-review-2009&quot;&gt;first review (2009)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the 2nd &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie is going to have superior visual
effects to its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-2007&quot;&gt;predecessor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but nothing more groundbreaking. You oughta
love the destruction of the aircraft carrier though. And the same
complaint I had with the first one is that there&#x27;s way too much going
on as regards the action such that I can&#x27;t keep up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears I wasn&#x27;t the only one who loved the human hero&#x27;s parents in
the first movie, as evidenced by their far greater screen presence here,
and they don&#x27;t misstep here too. But they don&#x27;t help advance the
story, which is pretty much non-existent anyways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember anything believable, and at the end of it ya feel like
&lt;em&gt;what a waste!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, but then the entire concept of the Transformers is
pre-juvenile anyways!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;second-review-2010&quot;&gt;second review (2010)&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit of &lt;em&gt;The Transformers 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; was an unpleasant experience. It makes
apparent the farce&#x2F;silliness the entire concept actually is. I am
especially annoyed by the impossible survival our heroes have, and worse
still, none of the members of the military are any interesting. It&#x27;s
nearly unbearable and just too noisy. It&#x27;s as bad as the first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Law-Abiding Citizen (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/law-abiding-citizen-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/law-abiding-citizen-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got &lt;em&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&#x27;s theme of super-smart villain who got everything
figured; difference here is that the villain&#x27;s deeds aren&#x27;t so
well-justified, and its creators ignored what made &lt;em&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&#x27;s ending
great, which spoils what is an otherwise superbly-made and -acted
movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit left a bitter taste in mouth, and none of the major performers
helped. In fact, I was surprised by how bad Gerard Butler was. I must
have been blinded by my love for him in &lt;em&gt;300&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rashomon (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rashomon-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rashomon-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Of the highest-rated of Akira Kirosawa&#x27;s movies, &lt;em&gt;Rashomon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is given
the stature of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-samurai-1954&quot;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, if not more, but for me it&#x27;s just a
dumb story with bad acting. In fact I found its ridiculousness
unbearable in this revisit. Regardless, Toshiro Mifune is really an
interesting actor, but happened to be given a shitty role, where he
practically is a madman. I also enjoyed the performance of the inquisive
guy, though he overdoes it, not to mention silly grins and forced
laughter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2012 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/2012-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/2012-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember a movie whose visual effects are of this scale, and
only those of &lt;em&gt;King Kong&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;top-visual-effects&quot;&gt;are superior&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The early scenes are much fun,
with nice superficial touches reminiscent of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-2007&quot;&gt;Transformers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The whole
thing is dragged by some family drama as well as an uninteresting John
Cusack. Me loves the designs of the arks. The &#x27;chase&#x27; scenes, all an
excuse to showcase the extravaganza that is the effects, are pure fun. I
also enjoyed the large Russian billionaire, an otherwise unconvincing
buffoon that offers much comic relief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Quantum of Solace (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/quantum-of-solace-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/quantum-of-solace-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This Bond we find in &lt;em&gt;Quantum of Solace&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; must be the most intense yet,
and partakes in equally-intense thrills, and in what is perhaps the best
Bond movie yet. Actually the movie&#x27;s first half (and its action) is so
good that it reminds of (the superior) &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;taken-2008&quot;&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, even though it got
spoilt by the revenging beauty (incompetent performance, stale character
and subplot) and an even worse finale.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Small Soldiers (1998)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/small-soldiers-1998/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/small-soldiers-1998/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie offers at least one superb one-liner:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not artificial intelligence; actual intelligence!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also offers wonderful character design. I just wish it could have
been more scathing (and less childish), it being a war satire and all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
