<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/2011-movie/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Limitless (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/limitless-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/limitless-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Possessing a great story concept, this movie centers around an
experimental drug that increases mental performance to beyond genius
level. The movie is filled with great visuals and there&#x27;s a nice
performance by the guy playing the Russian money-lender. As for Robert
De Niro, I really wish a more interesting actor was given the role.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pandorum (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pandorum-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pandorum-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very nice production and creature design, although both these elements
have been copied (inspired) from elsewhere. The whole thing is rather
disturbing though (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ben_Foster&quot;&gt;Ben Foster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is an intense actor; the sound effects
were extremely loud; the sounds made by the creatures didn&#x27;t help
either). It&#x27;s edge-of-your-seat stuff, with horrid enemies all over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pathology (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pathology-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pathology-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite an original story with a spectacular opening sequence, and a touch
here and there of wonderful shots (e.g. check the part where the lead
drinks water greedily, the day after his first experience).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is wonderful casting too, even though I&#x27;ll have to excuse the
lead and the villain. I most especially appreciate the role of the
middle-aged lead of the team, played by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;John_de_Lancie&quot;&gt;John de Lancie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He was a
pleasure to watch. There was also another nice, but tiny, performance by
the guy playing the fiance&#x27;s father. There&#x27;s great characters, like
the massive black guy, as well as the trailer-trash fat guy. The dialog
is quite good too, and the make-up is even better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is quite silly, and rather pointless. The lead transforms
(participates in the game) way too quick to convince. There is also too
much (raunchy) sex, most of which is needless. The great jealousy the
villains portray is unconvincing, and so is their bullying. Also, the
ending feels rushed, as if there wasn&#x27;t much material to work with.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2008&#x2F;film&#x2F;reviews&#x2F;pathology-1200535058&quot;&gt;this review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Contagion (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/contagion-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/contagion-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very well-made, rather convincing&#x2F;realistic (the fresh dialog
contributes well to that), well-acted movie (Laurence Fishburne is a joy
to watch, and so is Gwyneth Paltrow). One favorite scene is when husband
(Matt Damon) is told of passing away of wife while in hospital. The
reaction is quite sad, and perhaps represents the best such scene I&#x27;ve
ever seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is quite gloomy, and makes me impatient when we are actually
going to finally manage to be fully immune to disease
(nanomedicine&#x2F;genetics). The subject matter makes it among the most
important movies ever made.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] A &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.salon.com&#x2F;2011&#x2F;09&#x2F;09&#x2F;contagion_review&#x2F;singleton&#x2F;&quot;&gt;superb review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; whose one criticism (disrespect for
blogging) was on point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Groundhog Day (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/groundhog-day-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/groundhog-day-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Would be kinda nice to be caught in an eternal day. Imagine all the
stuff you can learn, and all the experiences you can have. All the risky
things you&#x27;d do, and all the impact you can have on people. That&#x27;s
what the lead character does, and he goes as far as committing suicde a
few times, only to wake up the next day, and the next day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is done well, but has not aged too well. Would be nice to see
a remake of one of the most interesting movie concepts ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Being There (1979)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/being-there-1979/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/being-there-1979/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;1st review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fantasy that is extremely funny in places and very entertaining
everywhere else. I found the rich man&#x27;s wife irresistible. In the
movie&#x27;s funniest moment, the ultra-dumb protagonist didn&#x27;t find her
so attractive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;everywhere else&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; isn&#x27;t exactly accurate, since I found the moments
before the lead leaves the house quite boring. Also, I didn&#x27;t find the
lady &lt;em&gt;that&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; delicious this time around. It remains a special movie, and
kinda edgy, since you keep getting worried if anyone would actually
discover that our hero is actually a retard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Unknown (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/unknown-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/unknown-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;First review:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a similar feel to &lt;em&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and is also set in dark Europe and
stars the very capable Liam Neeson. The storyline is solid and so is
the acting. There is a lack of gloss, and it&#x27;s very edgy. The twist
is pretty good and so is the action, although it&#x27;s not kool when you
see an untrained person suddenly capable of driving a car like a
stuntman. Writers this good could have come up with something better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels a lot worse, which is yet another instance of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;The case of
&#x27;The Matrix Reloaded&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s not as interesting, it does not feel
like &lt;em&gt;Taken&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, it&#x27;s not set in dark Europe, the twist not too
interesting (unless it&#x27;s your first time), and the untrained life-saver
merely irritating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>X-Men: First Class (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/x-men-first-class-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/x-men-first-class-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A decent attempt at telling the origins of Magneto and Xavier, their
meeting feels forced. It is good entertainment, but none of it is
outstanding at all. The visual effects aren&#x27;t any groundbreaking as one
would hope from a spectacle such as this. The villain is not
interesting, and so are most characters, especially his followers, all
shallow as fuck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sucker Punch (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sucker-punch-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sucker-punch-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was mesmerised by the imagery, and I don&#x27;t see why it would be
regarded any lesser than that of &lt;em&gt;300&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It was interesting to discover
that the same director was responsible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite of the fantasy scenes is the first battle scene, which has
three mean-looking &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;suckerpunch.wikia.com&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Samurai_Warriors&quot;&gt;Samurai Warriors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The envisioning was near-perfect,
and the visual and character design masterful, complete with excellent
visual effects and camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie in general is well-made, and has great production design. The
music is decent, though too loud, and so are the action scenes. I wish a
better action director was involved, since the lack of experience of the
girls shows. Perhaps there should have been more time spent in training
them. The director tries to make up for it with frantic visual tricks
(camerawork, editing, and visual effects).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] It&#x27;s interesting that what got me to watch this is
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.time.com&#x2F;time&#x2F;specials&#x2F;packages&#x2F;article&#x2F;0,28804,2101344_2101366_2101545,00.html&quot;&gt;Time magazine&#x27;s Worst movies of 2011&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, of which this was number 2. It
just happens that I was attracted by the plot of alternate realities and
a pretty gal wearing a sword. I later on discovered that the movie was
generally poorly received, both commercially and critically. Weird.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Legend of the Guardians: The Owls of Ga&#x27;Hoole (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/legend-of-the-guardians-the-owls-of-ga-hoole-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/legend-of-the-guardians-the-owls-of-ga-hoole-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;intial-review&quot;&gt;intial review&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owls aren&#x27;t interesting animals at all, so I watched this in
preparation of moving on, but was captivated by the photo-realisitic
rendering of the birds&#x27; faces. I also enjoyed the humor offered by the
two birds that kidnapped the brothers, and that&#x27;s one other thing that
encouraged me to watch the rest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie runs for around 100 minutes, but it feels very epic. It lacks
the immediate and glossy excitement of a Disney&#x2F;Pixar movie, and feels
more stately and serious, as well as darker. The characters are
well-developed and it doesn&#x27;t feel like shortcuts were taken, well
other than that the repeat trips felt shortened, much like Timon and
Pumba&#x27;s when they followed Simba back home. The battles are very
well-made, and the ocean waves, though brief, were quite impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;revisit&quot;&gt;revisit&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not experience any epicness second time around, nor did I notice
any outstanding character development. The eye candy was also not as
impressive. I also noticed annoying coincidences, as well as a far less
enjoyable experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Super 8 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/super-8-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/super-8-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some nice performances by the kids, especially the explosives lover, the
lead character, the pretty gal, and my favorite, the movie director. I
loved also that of the guy playing the gal&#x27;s father. The train crash is
the movie&#x27;s best visual effects moment, and among the best crashes ever
in my movie-watching history. Character design of the creature, the
spider-like villain, could be a lot better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Repo Men (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/repo-men-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/repo-men-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not intense enough to do justice to the subject matter, perhaps due to
being a little too unrealistic. It is however very well-made, has
quality cinematography and production design, and is well-acted. Forest
Whitaker is a pleasure to watch, as usual, Jude Law is damn gorgeous,
and the lady that plays his wife even more so. The girlfriend is not
interesting, sadly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the subject matter, it would have been nice if there was some
explaination of how such cruelty came to be socially acceptable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Thor (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/thor-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/thor-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Does not live up to the hype, some parts of the shallow story are
embarrassing, and the humor is recycled. The visual effects are meh, and
so is the costume design of the Asgards. Their city has a nice design
though, excessive as it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title character is gorgeous as fuck. I also like the concept of the
mysterious gatekeeper, and the character. The silver robot is also
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the movie more on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Next Three Days (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-next-three-days-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-next-three-days-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Superb direction ensures that we are kept on edge of seat for much of
the running length of the movie, and even the slow parts add to the
suspense. The lead detective is quite impressive, and I also enjoyed the
portrayal of the father of protagonist, as well as the (damn gorgeous)
wife of protagonist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie opens with wonderful dialog, and the rest of it more than
lives up to the high standards that scene sets.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special mention should go to the guy at the airport checkpoint. The
performance is amazing, though shortlived.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Killers (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/killers-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/killers-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember enjoying the movie a lot more first time, most especially
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Katherine_Heigl&quot;&gt;Katherine Heigl&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It is still enjoyable, but that Katherine, though
desirable, is just so irritating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else I felt last time I watched:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writers had no clue where to run with the story; I got surprised
when it ended, because the attacks were simply unjustified, and there
was no resolve.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Transformers: Dark of the Moon (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/transformers-dark-of-the-moon-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t see any improvement in visual effects over &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;transformers-revenge-of-the-fallen-2009&quot;&gt;the previous
movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The story is shit too, but the gal excessively gorgeous, much
more so than the previous overrated Megan Fox. Beyond money-making,
there can&#x27;t have been a reason this movie was made, especially since it
doesn&#x27;t add anything. The action is as frantic and hard-to-follow as in
the predecessors, with an annoying tendency of having the humans tougher
than would be realisitc (check how much they&#x27;re thrown around, only to
stand and continue fighting). Very little of the humor is effective, my
favorite being the part where the lead assaults own car.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Source Code (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/source-code-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/source-code-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Though engaging, it&#x27;s not very exciting, but the leading guy, Jake
Gyllenhaal, gives a real nice performance. Check especially the moment
when he&#x27;s told an uncomfortable fact. The villain is amazing too, and a
very unusual choice. The guy running the Source Code program is given an
embarassing and unconvincing performance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that this was made by David Fincher, you know, the same guy who
made &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fight-club-1999&quot;&gt;Fight Club&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;se7en-1995&quot;&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it was way too underwhelming, too
average. The story, the acting, the direction, none outstanding. I get
the vibe that the work the movie is based on is quite famous, so maybe
this movie doesn&#x27;t do it justice. This is easily Fincher&#x27;s least
interesting, perhaps with the exclusion of his first, &lt;em&gt;Alien 3&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I nearly forgot that the opening credits sequence was quite good.
That and the fact that I could not actually figure what was going on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Green Hornet (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-green-hornet-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-green-hornet-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of the movie is better than the latter, with the humorous
antics of the title character, and the excellence of his sidekick, not
least of which is the coffee-making. The lead villain is also fun to
watch, especially with his the constant (and humorous) concern of the
fearsomeness of his image&#x2F;presence. The split-screen moment, where
various bounty hunters are sent for the title character, is amazing, and
among the most innovative visuals I&#x27;ve seen in movies yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the movie gets a little annoying when this title character stops
being funny (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;unforgiving-characters-are-annoying&quot;&gt;and ungrateful&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), starting with the moment he shoots the
sidekick. There is also unexplained physical prowess, the sort that
makes the movie feel like passive entertainment, and the destruction
that happens in the movie&#x27;s final action sequence is way too much. Why
the noise?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Brewster&#x27;s Millions (1985)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/brewster-s-millions-1985/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/brewster-s-millions-1985/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very delightful and shallow comedy about a guy who is to spend
millions within a month for an even bigger reward. Richard Pryor, the
lead, is fun to watch and so is the story, especially early on. The best
act in the movie is the lead&#x27;s political campaign. I can vaguely
remember it, so I consider among the funniest movies I&#x27;ve watched this
year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] Richard Pryor style of comedy makes Chris Rock look
like a sorry imitator.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Warlords (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-warlords-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-warlords-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Among the best movies I&#x27;ve ever seen Jet Li star in, this is an
unforgiving portrayal of the brutality of war, and the horrid politics
surrounding it. I was amazed by some of the action, the highlight being
the cannon-hit-cannon moment, something I have never seen in any movie.
The movie itself was quite a surprise hit for me, for I never even heard
of it before, so I expected some passive actioner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A revisit wasn&#x27;t as impressive, and in fact I found myself rather
impatient when it would end, and there isn&#x27;t great pleasure in the
sadness, and maybe also because I tend to look for an ideally good
character, instead of the lead character that Jet Li portrays, perhaps
the most complex he has done yet, more complete he has ever done
(sometimes he&#x27;s kind and sometimes not).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bad casting choice was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Takeshi_Kaneshiro&quot;&gt;Takeshi Kaneshiro&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who plays one of the
three leaders and a narrator. He&#x27;s just not convincing in the role, or
maybe he&#x27;s just not a good enough actor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Abduction (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/abduction-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/abduction-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Takes forever to start, and the delay isn&#x27;t filled with good
filmmaking. There&#x27;s some bad acting (lead, his gal, and best friend)
and some interesting ones (Alfred Molina and Sigourney Weaver), some
shitty story and kiddy romance, and little else that&#x27;s positive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Angel Heart (1987)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/angel-heart-1987/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/angel-heart-1987/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s at least moment where Mickey Rourke shines, where he bullies an
old medical doctor into providing some info. Robert De Niro is
impressive, that is until we tire of his spurious appearance. The black
gal is intensely gorgeous, but I don&#x27;t know what&#x27;s up with the
romp... maybe it was for the audience. Otherwise the movie is not very
interesting and the twist is shitty-ass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>In the Company of Men (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/in-the-company-of-men-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/in-the-company-of-men-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Rather captivating with unusual dialogue, making it feel realistic, and
with a really good performance by Aaron Eckhart as the biggest asshole
of them all. It&#x27;s also a real bleak look at the modern workplace.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Just Go With It (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/just-go-with-it-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/just-go-with-it-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It does not even try to be a good movie, but then again it is an Adam
Sandler comedy. There&#x27;s some very hilarious moments, even though none
of them were original, except the ass-coconut moment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One strange thing though is that I enjoyed Jennifer Aniston&#x27;s
performance, and for the first time (if memory serves well). I also
enjoyed the performance by the girl playing her daughter. Girls of that
age are hardly ever funny (or no one writer really tries), but she was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Love Actually (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/love-actually-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/love-actually-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a delightful&#x2F;fresh feel to it and there&#x27;s a bunch of fun
moments, but the whole thing is spoilt when it goes into typical
romantic comedy mode near the end, things like dozens of people
following a man who intends to propose, or a kid breaching airport
security to go mention his love for some gal. Bill Nighy and his manager
were fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sweeney Todd - The Demon Barber of Fleet Street (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sweeney-todd-the-demon-barber-of-fleet-street-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sweeney-todd-the-demon-barber-of-fleet-street-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Great set design, camerawork, and costume design; a very dark story with
some disgusting elements; a very unbearable musical style (the singing
is often embarassing, and not very well-made, and exposes some bad
acting). I like the ugly actor (the aid of the evil judge), but he&#x27;s a
little too clown-like to celebrate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Elephant Man (1980)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-elephant-man-1980/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-elephant-man-1980/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The filmmakers made sure that the disfigured man looked really
disgusting, and the idea is rather challenging, especially because I&#x27;d
lose my appetite if I shared a table. That doesn&#x27;t look very good
(what&#x27;s the difference between me and the racists?).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is too slow and not very interesting, as if the makers relied
only on the curiosity of this shitty-looking and not much else. Those
who mistreated this guy should have been portrayed in a more convincing
way, because they just look mindless, as if the director was desperate
to make them look bad, just in case we wouldn&#x27;t notice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Atonement (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/atonement-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/atonement-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Superb performances by all 3 people playing the writer girl, my favorite
being the youngest, which happens to be among the best child
performances I&#x27;ve ever seen. One other nice performance is the young
girl who eventually gets raped. I like the rather lame use of
type-writer sounds during certain sequences; I also like the expansive
sets showing bombed (World War II) areas as well as the military camp
(that wasn&#x27;t cheap). Otherwise the main story (a man gets
falsely-accused of rape) is boring and often full of sentimentality, and
I enjoyed none of the other performances.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hanna (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hanna-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hanna-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A pathetic attempt at a nuanced, quietly stylistic assassin movie, which
instead happens to be a serious test of one&#x27;s patience and
perseverance. Lead actress is of course good (remember &lt;em&gt;Atonement&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but
what&#x27;s up with the story!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pirates of the Caribbean - On Stranger Tides (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Far less spectacular and less annoying (there&#x27;s no Keira Knighley or
Orlando Bloom) than the earlier movies, it does have nice humor,
gorgeous mermaids (wonderfully portrayed), and a totally enjoyable
performance by the fat guy who has Jack Sparrow brought in for
questioning, if we exclude the silly moment... the two-thumbs-up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sexy Beast (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sexy-beast-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sexy-beast-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good performances throughout and some of the best visualisations of fear
I&#x27;ve seen yet. Ben Kingsley is an amazingly adaptive actor, and his is
most likely the worst asshole I&#x27;ve seen in any movie... worse than Al
Pacino&#x27;s in &lt;em&gt;Scarface&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Where the Wild Things Are (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/where-the-wild-things-are-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/where-the-wild-things-are-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre movie with creatures, designed to look like dolls, done in bad
taste. Those creatures are however as realistic as it gets, and the
story tends to be spooky in places (e.g. one of them asks the
near-victim if he&#x27;d be good dinner). Catherine Keener, who plays the
mother of the lead character, is as impressive as always.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Irréversible (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/irreversible-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/irreversible-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A skillfully-done experimental tragedy told backwards, having among the
most horrific scenes I&#x27;ve yet seen in any movie, and I&#x27;m not referring
to the rape scene, prolonged as it was (isn&#x27;t it the longest rape scene
ever?). There&#x27;s good acting and dialog, complete with high levels of
realism.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Princess Mononoke (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/princess-mononoke-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/princess-mononoke-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched this with high expectation, due the high critical acclaim it
possesses, but now have to wonder that the fuck is wrong with these
people. The story, an epic, resonates a bit with environmental care, so
I guess that&#x27;s part of its appeal, but the animation and visual design
is crappy as hell, and so is the dialog (likely partly because of shitty
translation).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Castle (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-castle-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-castle-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An awkward but witty comedy about a simple (and dumb) family on the
verge of being forcibly removed from their home due to an airport
extension. The movie&#x27;s best performance, though brief, was that of the
lawyer who took over the case. It was fun to watch his perplexed
reactions to the dumbness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Life, Above All (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/life-above-all-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/life-above-all-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is much authenticity and freshness in the treament of poor South
African township experience, but there is also a lack of those since the
behaviour of some of the people is such that I&#x27;ve never witnessed (or
heard of, given the demographics of the setting) as a citizen of that
country... it&#x27;s little too westernized, and annoyingly so too. Also,
the language was a little too pure to be believable for anyone familiar
with it. The story is mildly interesting and acting decent, my favorite
being the prostitute teenager.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is more important than it&#x27;s good, because it effectively
showcases the negative effects of denial and idiocy: &amp;quot;It&#x27;s not HIV,
I&#x27;m just not feeling okay; maybe it&#x27;s witchcraft; Friend, find me a
good traditional doctor; In the meanwhile, I&#x27;ll try these herbal
thingies&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Megamind (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/megamind-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/megamind-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;These 5 movies offered some of the best first-time viewing experiences I
ever had:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monsters, Inc.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2001)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2004)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Robots&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2005)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ratatouille&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2007)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall-E&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (2008)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do they all have in common:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wonderful character design and development&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enchanting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a great&#x2F;exciting story concept&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest entrant on this list is &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, a thoroughly satisfying
movie, which has the traditional hero&#x2F;villain thing, with a twist. The
character of the hero is simply amazing, for its deliberate
stereotypical design and development. The movie also has great costume
design. The title character is great fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, one other characteristic of this list of movies is that the
appeal went down on a revisit, a very worrying trend, and that was the
case with &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, though it wasn&#x27;t so devastating for it remains
excellent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shutter Island (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shutter-island-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shutter-island-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Me did not enjoy this psychological thriller starring an uninteresting
Leonardo Di Caprio. His character is investigating a missing patient in
some island prison for the criminally insane, and it drags on, inducing
sleep along the way. What&#x27;s the point?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dragon Hunters (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dragon-hunters-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dragon-hunters-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The character design is quite impressive, all but the purple dog and the
monsters. The oversized warrior is an admirable character, due to his
great (and naive) kindness, and of course, his looks (design). The
movie&#x27;s best design is however the servant of the gal&#x27;s father, even
though it&#x27;s the kind seen before (that of villainous characters).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of the movie is unlike I&#x27;ve seen before, a world with weird
gravitational behavior, with pieces of ground constantly breaking from
the land and floating in the air. It&#x27;s a dark story that, sadly, feels
too short.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>One Day (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/one-day-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/one-day-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;What&#x27;s up with people making depressing movies? This one is pretty
well-made, but it drags on and on with a boring love story. One thing of
value it portrays is that life tends to turn out different (and worse)
to what we hope&#x2F;expect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kung Fu Panda 2 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/kung-fu-panda-2-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this even more than the first time (which wasn&#x27;t the case
with the first movie). The humor is great, and so is the action, and
it&#x27;s overall better than the first movie, except that nothing beats the
escape sequence and the wobbly bridge fight. The villain is amazing, as
is his display of martial arts prowess. Sadly, the movie feels a bit too
short, and doesn&#x27;t take itself seriously at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shrek Forever After (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shrek-forever-after-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shrek-forever-after-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one, given that I find the series rather
overrated, bar the 2nd movie. But this one is quite an experience, and
far superior to any of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the kid that insists on Shrek screaming&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donkey was actually interesting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the warrior Fiona was great to watch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the villain was fun to watch, and his mannerisms reminds of that of
the title character of &lt;em&gt;Megamind&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is a lotta fun&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Ogres species was fun to watch, and it was interesting to note
that he looked like nothing compared to some of them; character
design is amazing; check especially the cook&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great humor: the villain serving the witches; the cook proposing
serving food during battle; the meet between fat cat and donkey&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the early scenes in which Shrek harks back to the early,
freedom-filled, days&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movie revisits can be real strange. The first time I watched this one, I
deemed it a masterpiece, but a revisit proved it not much better than
the others in the &lt;em&gt;Shrek&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; franchise. It makes me wonder... maybe my
mood was different. It&#x27;s not as bad as the worst in the series (&lt;em&gt;Shrek
3&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but it doesn&#x27;t seem as good as the 2nd (&lt;em&gt;Shrek 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically, it&#x27;s a little disappointing (the human faces are really
bad, not much better than the original &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (1995). None of the
visuals are any impressive either, well other than Donkey&#x27;s fur, which
sometimes look photo-realistic. Luckily the new ogres are interesting,
far more interesting than Shrek himself, my most favorite being the
cook. And of the previous elements I watched, Fiona was no longer
interesting, and villain not as much fun nor is the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Warrior&#x27;s Way (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-warrior-s-way-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-warrior-s-way-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There is extreme brutality and violence, in this super-exciting fusion
of guns and swords. It&#x27;s rare to successfully mix Oriental and Western
fantasy. I don&#x27;t remember live-action fantasy martial arts so
impressively-executed (the ones that come close are &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;kung-fu-hustle-2004&quot;&gt;Kung Fu Hustle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;House Of Flying Daggers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). The costume design is amazing, for both West
and East. The final battle is exhilarating. Shit, I wish I had words to
describe it. Did you check the ninjas? The sound?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie&#x27;s best performance was the head of the ninjas, while Geoffrey
Rush&#x27;s was just business as usual (nothing challenging for him here,
nor was it required). The gal is okay, and not as annoying as she could
have been.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minor complaints I have is the unimpressive cowboy villain, and the
not-lethal-enough look of the lead (where&#x27;s Jet Li when you need him?).
I would also have preffered a less polished feel of the camerawork (it
feels too sanitised, too fantasy-like).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was again wondering if there was something wrong with considering
the generally negative critical reception of the movie. Maybe they
are the ones who have problems. Were we watching the same movie?
Perhaps I will understand on a revisit.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.screendaily.com&#x2F;reviews&#x2F;the-warriors-way&#x2F;5021277.article&quot;&gt;a quality review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that does a good job of justifying its
negative conclusion.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am worried that this is another &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;Case of The Matrix Reloaded&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is indeed another &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-case-of-the-matrix-reloaded&quot;&gt;Case of The Matrix Reloaded&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It is far less
impressive than on first viewing, but I still love the fantasy-like
fight sequences of the ninjas, but most especially, their
characterisation (they look as menacing as fuck). The part of the story
where the lead character gets to meet a gal and exercise a more relaxed
life is boring and not too well done. It reminds me of a similar kinda
thing in &lt;em&gt;Fearless&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, where Jet Li&#x27;s character goes to chill in a farm.
As if that&#x27;s not enough, both the lead character and the Amercian
villain are unconvincing, while the movie&#x27;s best performance is that of
the guy playing head of the ninjas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Toy Story 3 (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/toy-story-3-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/toy-story-3-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the best &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movie, and the only one I truly enjoyed.
The toys go through some elaborate adventures, ending up in some
seemingly hopeless situations, but luckily ending up surviving one way
or another. And the ending is as happy as can be. The environment, as
presented by the leader of the childcare toys, is so-gorgeous and
so-enchanting. The baby villain is quite scary, and the main villain is
unforgivably evil. My favorite characters are Rexx (the sweet dinosaur)
and the female cowboy (with her retarded voice). The clown, who makes a
first appearance here, is the best-designed character in the whole
series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A revisit was by far less enjoyable, but some moments remain
interesting (the Spanish mode), some charming ones (check the college
age toy owner with the toddler) and some great visuals (check the trash
sequence).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The First Grader (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-first-grader-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-first-grader-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Touching drama about the oldest person (84) to start formal primary
school education. Well, it so happens that he met opposition (there&#x27;s
isn&#x27;t a shortage of idiots in the world). The guy playing him gives a
very good performance, and just as impressive are the schoolmates,
especially the kid with an artificial leg. She also happens to provide
the movie&#x27;s most tear-jerking moment, where she mentions a future
career of choice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes these kids all the more impressive is that they were taken
from just two primary schools, which makes me assume they were
untrained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is paced a little too slow, although the horrendous past of
the old man is thrown in to help hold interest. Those flashbacks are too
frequent, unfortunately. Keeping the movie shorter would have been a
better solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cars 2 (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cars-2-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cars-2-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was not a big fan of the original, but this one is even worse. It also
happens to be an excuse to give more screen time to the rusty car that I
suppose was a big hit in the first movie. There was some decent humor
but nothing fresh. Some of the visual are pretty good, but
inconsistently so, as if it was hastily put together... &amp;quot;we gotta go
make millions quick&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mindhunters (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mindhunters-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mindhunters-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A bit disturbing with a gripping storyline. LL Cool J is an interesting
actor and so is the guy (in an interesting twist) who turns out to be
the villain. The setting (a simualtion of a small town, complete with
dolls&#x2F;statues for humans) is quite spooky, but the whole thing isn&#x27;t
satisfactorily justified, and the villain is too capable to convince (he
got too many things right in a very short period of time).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Something Borrowed (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/something-borrowed-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/something-borrowed-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some day I should simply stop punishing myself so much. I should learn
to quit the first sign I see trouble. My problem is high levels of
curiosity, for I&#x27;m often worried what I must miss, while wary of
passing judgement on a movie before watching its entirety.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s kinda hard to find an original and good romantic drama&#x2F;comedy, and
worse still, they tend to wallow in unbearable cheesiness. This one is
worsened by uninteresting leads, the Tom Cruise and Kirsten Dunst
look-alikes. It&#x27;s fucking weird how come movies like this still get
made at all, because there&#x27;s absolutely nothing new in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Who Framed Roger Rabbit (1988)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/who-framed-roger-rabbit-1988/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/who-framed-roger-rabbit-1988/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A mostly uninteresting and irritating mixture of 2D animation and live
action, which luckily has an ultra-sexy wife of the title character. No
one else is interesting, unless you want to mention the brief appearance
of the pig &amp;quot;that&#x27;s all folks&amp;quot; and Bugs Bunny. The movie is also badly
directed and acted, and it&#x27;s strange considering that the director is
Robert Zemeckis. Maybe the producers (the money people) got in the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Green Lantern (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/green-lantern-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/green-lantern-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one because I watched the trailer, which
exposed uninteresting visual and character design and a weak lead actor.
The movie turned out even worse than I expected, with an unbearably bad
and ludicrous story. Not even the visual effects help, because none of
them are any good. How can everything in the movie suck so bad!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the ugly guy who was to train the lead was a little interesting,
even though the character is recycled. The concept of a device that
allows one to create temporary matter-energy simply by willpower is kool
too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Season of the Witch (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/season-of-the-witch-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/season-of-the-witch-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It started reasonably well and slowly worked its way down into badly
recycled material. The adventure feels artificial, the villain
uninteresting, the characters shallow as shit, but worst of all is what
happens near the end. In my (pitiful) memory, this is the second worst
movie Nicolas Cage has been in (remember &lt;em&gt;Ghost Rider&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Cemetery Junction (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/cemetery-junction-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/cemetery-junction-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It got the same sort of camerawork and set design (set about the same
time?) as &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-05-06&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Education&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it also happens to be a coming-of-age
story, only a lot less serious and a lot more of a fairy-tale. The
acting is decent, but Ralph Fiennes isn&#x27;t convincing... more a
caricature than a shitty husband.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia: I don&#x27;t remember anyone mocking own father as the troubled kid
does here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Priest (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/priest-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/priest-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever went into a movie and realise within the first minute it&#x27;s not
going to be any good? If proven right, it can become a painful
experience, and you can&#x27;t wait for the end to come, because it&#x27;s not
so bad that it&#x27;s unwatcheable. What made me notice the early badness?
The very first two people to appear on screen (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Paul_Bettany&quot;&gt;Paul Bettany&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Karl_Urban&quot;&gt;Karl
Urban&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and their poses (they are vampire killers) are very telling.
Worse still, we have &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Cam_Gigandet&quot;&gt;Cam Gigandet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the sidekick. The story is so
unexciting, the climax is rushed and the post-apocalyptic world is
recycled and unexplained. The only bright spot I can remember is the
vampires themselves, even though the design isn&#x27;t original; it is
similar to that of the monsters in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;i-am-legend&quot;&gt;I Am Legend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Descent&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Confucius (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/confucius-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/confucius-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An embarassing lead performance by Chow Yun Fat; with the help of
unimpressive direction and script, it showcases silly ancient Chinese
traditions, as if they were somehow virtuous. Oh, and I still wondered
what&#x27;s so great the title character did for the world, other than at
times using his influence to try exert kindness to his world. I would
have preferred some time spent on explaining how he actually gained that
influence... and I&#x27;m not visiting his Wikipedia article.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Year One (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/year-one-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/year-one-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A fun and lazily-written movie set in ancient mythical times; there&#x27;s a
number of hilarious moments and fun characters, my favorite of which are
Caine (first biblical murderer) and the high priest. Sadly, the fun
isn&#x27;t very consistent (hence the work &#x27;lazy&#x27;), but it&#x27;s enough to
keep one interested. The most hilarious moments ought to be the one
involving foreskins.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dante&#x27;s Inferno: An Animated Epic (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dante-s-inferno-an-animated-epic-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dante-s-inferno-an-animated-epic-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An entertaining fantasy about some heroic warrior fighting demons in
hell in order to reach his loves. It&#x27;s moderately well-made and has
some interesting animation (check when Satan forcibly pulls that lover
towards self), but the storyline skimps through the details, and feels
shallow... it feels incomplete.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monty Python&#x27;s Life of Brian (1979)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-life-of-brian-1979/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-life-of-brian-1979/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Poking a lotta fun at some the blind adherance and factionalism that is
all too common in society, and doing it in a very humorous way. This is
brilliant humor by the way. The effort of making the costumes and the
environment feel authentic is impressive. The only real annoyance is the
character of Brian&#x27;s mom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, unlike &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;monty-pythons-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975&quot;&gt;Holy Grail&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it doesn&#x27;t feel too much like a
collection of gags.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monty Python&#x27;s The Meaning Of Life (1983)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-the-meaning-of-life-1983/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-the-meaning-of-life-1983/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of excellent humor (&lt;em&gt;the machine that goes PING&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;welcome to the
middle of the movie&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;baby falling from pussy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, ...), perhaps even
funnier than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;monty-python-s-life-of-brian-1979&quot;&gt;Life of Brian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, though it was quite a surprise that it
resorted to vomit humor, and the most disgusting in memory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was also disorganised as a whole movie, though not as much as
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;monty-python-s-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975&quot;&gt;Holy Grail&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Whatever Works (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/whatever-works-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/whatever-works-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Its being very feel-good is ironic, given that its main character is as
pessimistic a guy as it gets, insulting people everywhere and getting
away with it (reminding of Gregory House from the series, &lt;em&gt;House&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).
There&#x27;s interesting acting, and I really like the part where the
characters look at the camera, perplexed at what they are supposed to
see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fresh as it feels, the movie really smacks of laziness. Woody Allen is a
talented movie maker, but he didn&#x27;t really put much effort here, or at
least it doesn&#x27;t feel like it. The movie feels like a glorified sitcom,
and it&#x27;s fantasy-like, with quirky happenings here and there, and
doesn&#x27;t feel like one solid whole. This isn&#x27;t what I want from
theatre.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Machete (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/machete-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/machete-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Goog ole-fashioned action movie, with a deliberately sgallow storyline
and two beloved leading ladies, one (Jessica Alba) of which has never
performed this well anywhere (in my experience of course). The leading
guy, an ugly motherfucker who I only ever saw doing secondary roles, if
fun to watch. He does look like a tough guy. Steven Seagal is as scary
as always, and I wonder what the fuck Robert De Niro is doing here.
Aren&#x27;t there more cerebral scripts for him out there?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Monty Python&#x27;s Quest for the Holy Grail (1975)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/monty-python-s-quest-for-the-holy-grail-1975/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s funny moments but the whole thing feels more like a collection
of sketches than a unit commonly knows as &lt;em&gt;a movie&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;a film&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among my favorite moments is when an anarchist explains to the baffled
king about how his community operates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Insidious (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/insidious-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/insidious-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Stupid stories can be told well (remember &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but not this
one. The visual design of the ghost world is embarassing, and feels
staged. Luckily, the exorcist (or whatever she&#x27;s called) is given a
decent portrayal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shaolin Soccer (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-soccer-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-soccer-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very shallow story, very entertaining direction (best of which are the
fantasy martial arts), very funny in places, and very charming, but
muddled with cheap and childish ethics. A totally beloved gal, who
happens to be funny too (check the ghost dress and the sexy pose).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Joneses (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-joneses-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-joneses-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Demi Moore is still so damn gorgeous after all these years! The movie is
a real good play on the concept of &lt;em&gt;kool neighbors&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; even though it fails
to end it well. It takes the concept a little far, meaning they fail to
make it believable, but luckily the whole thing is kept entertaining.
The subplots (cheating hubby and homosexuality) were left ununsed and
were therefore needless, as if thw writers didn&#x27;t have a filler...
lack of creativity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Captain America: The First Avenger (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/captain-america-the-first-avenger-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of its moments are so bad that they are hard to bear. There&#x27;s some
uninteresting acting too, e.g. the frail Captain America and the love
interest. None of the other performances are really good, and the
villain is embarassingly bad, as if from some low-budget sci-fi movie.
The script is bad and it&#x27;s strange that the movie comes from the same
studio as &lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There isn&#x27;t even decent visual effects to lessen
the pain. Luckily, the final-form Captain America hero is fun to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>My Big Fat Greek Wedding (2002)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/my-big-fat-greek-wedding-2002/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/my-big-fat-greek-wedding-2002/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An okay and shallow romantic comedy; there&#x27;s some bad make-up for the
lead character in her early scenes; none of the acting is any good and
the male romantic lead is especially bad, as if he&#x27;s embarassed or
something; it&#x27;s interesting watching warm human relationships like the
Greeks in the movie have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Semi-Pro (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/semi-pro-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/semi-pro-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Very funny (favorite moment is the unloaded gun scene), and some of the
humor is very original. The movie is in the style (the goofiness) of the
other Will Ferrell vehicle, &lt;em&gt;Blade of Glory&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Andr%C3%A9_3000&quot;&gt;André 3000&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is
interesting to watch and, with talent like this, me wonders why he
isn&#x27;t working more regularly in movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bridesmaids (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bridesmaids-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bridesmaids-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My memory sucks but this is the best chick flick I&#x27;ve seen yet.
Although some of the humor is recycled, it doesn&#x27;t feel so. Much of it
is quite good and original. There are good performances from the lead
and the lady getting married. The traffic cop isn&#x27;t bad either, but the
movie&#x27;s most interesting character is the masculine lady. I haven&#x27;t
quite experienced a tomboy character done this way. There&#x27;s the
suckiness that is so common with romantic comedies (the fallout between
best friends), and worse, merely brushed away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, it&#x27;s interesting the kind of effort that goes into
mindless things like wedding ceremonies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Grown Ups (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/grown-ups-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/grown-ups-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There isn&#x27;t much going for this one, except I admire one of the
characters (in his early forties) falling in love with an elderly lady.
The movie is not unbearable but it should be given a miss. Chris Rock
shows again his extreme lack of acting skill and Salma Hayek hasn&#x27;t
lost her position as among the most beautiful women on the planet. That
old lady gives a nice performance BTW and she looks pretty for her age.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Midnight Meat Train (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-midnight-meat-train-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-midnight-meat-train-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After watching what felt like a waste of time, I was surprised to find
that &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Midnight_Meat_Train#Reception&quot;&gt;there were those who found it decent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The villain is given a
laughably bad performance by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Vinnie_Jones&quot;&gt;Vinnie Jones&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I don&#x27;t remember any of
his work any good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some parts of the movie are decent:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the intrigue the lead character goes through as he unravels the
mystery that is the serial killer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lady our lead character tries to impress with his art&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Hate Valentine&#x27;s Day (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-hate-valentine-s-day-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-hate-valentine-s-day-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This was dealt a harsh blow by critics and, although I don&#x27;t like it
much, I don&#x27;t see how it&#x27;s any worse than typical American romantic
comedies. It&#x27;s as annoying as they tend to be (hard-to-bear romance
with an overlong &#x27;sulking&#x27; period) but it has some good humor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Asterix and the Vikings (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/asterix-and-the-vikings-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/asterix-and-the-vikings-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I always found the characters of Asterix &amp;amp; Obelix series fascinating.
Most interesting was the kindly Obelix, the overweight warrior who
happens to be the toughest of them all. The voice talent he&#x27;s given
here is pretty good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this rather quirky movie, the more interesting character is Abba, the
daughter of the Viking king. She isn&#x27;t an originial creation, but her
sass, her tough-gal attitude, and her front-teeth gap makes her fun to
watch. I also liked the dumb son of the villain. There&#x27;s good humor
sprinkled all the place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Other Boleyn Girl (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-other-boleyn-girl-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-other-boleyn-girl-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember enjoying any of Eric Bana&#x27;s performances until now;
two of American&#x27;s great sweethearts are here (the ridiculously
desirable Scarlett Johanssen and the sophisticated and disturbing
Natalie Portman). The are other good performances, and none is better
than that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ana_Torrent&quot;&gt;Anne Torrent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who plays the queen&#x27;s first wife.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie starts off as yet-another English period drama (though I liked
the detailed look at the lives of the rich and pwoerful at the time),
but the intensity of the events at the end almost led me to call it
overall excellent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>9 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/9-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/9-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A weird post-apocalypse movie about bizarre puppet-like creatures trying
to survive in a world where they are terrorised by some scary robot
whose goal is left untold. The action is top-class and the adventure
heavy, with many cliffhanger moments, but the central premise (mentioned
in the twist) is damn silly. Character design is pretty good (the main
villain is awesome and so are its minions) while character development
is typical.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lives of Others (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lives-of-others-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lives-of-others-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;changelog.complete.org&#x2F;archives&#x2F;6756-the-lives-of-others&quot;&gt;an article&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that inspired me to watch this one. It&#x27;s one of
those movies that make you lucky to live in today&#x27;s South Africa,
because it shows abuses of human freedom in East Germany in the
mid-80&#x27;s. The acting is pretty good, especially by the guy who is
taking part in the spying of the palywright. The very last moment is a
tearjecker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bolt (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bolt-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bolt-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was attracted by the high-tech action, thinking that&#x27;s what the movie
was about, but I was soon disappointed; the all-too-common cheap
sentiments were unbearable; the humor, though not fresh (except the
begging-for-food part), was fun. Great voice talent and sound.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The American President (1995)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-american-president-1995/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-american-president-1995/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It feels dated and Annette Benning is so damn pretty. It was hard not to
compare the movie with &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; tv series (I saw the first two of
its seasons). The whole thing feels shallow. The &lt;em&gt;oh shit! it really is
the president&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; thing is so lame and boring. Ok, there was too much of it
in the tv series. Why do I feel like some episodes of that series were
actually better. Sure the debates and storylines of that series were
deeper and more complex, but some episodes were actually more exciting
than this movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Das Experiment (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/das-experiment-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/das-experiment-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Lacking the intensity of its &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-experiment-2010&quot;&gt;remake&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and its lead character not as
heroic (and even annoying), I was left unsatisfied. For its remake, the
injustices begin very early during the movie (perhaps within 30
minutes), while for this one, they begins only in the last 30 minutes.
They however go way too far to be believable (e.g. attempted rape). The
romance is beautiful (did you see that gal!), but they just had to push
it as far as the gal having a part in the violence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Curious George (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/curious-george-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/curious-george-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The uninteresting first scene, that of the playful title character
having fun, made me not want to proceed to the rest, but the ultra-sweet
female love interest and the eye she had for the museum tour guide led
me on. It isn&#x27;t much, and has some unbearable and formulaic happenings
(e.g. the evil son of the museum owner, the break-up between the tour
guide, and the got-to-get-the-monkey-back shit). I managed to muster a
smile here and there as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gamer (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gamer-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gamer-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Intensely violent with some decent visuals here and there. Tries too
hard to impress with over-the-top scenarios and frantic action. The
billionaire villain was fun to watch, especially during the dance
sequence. I don&#x27;t remember the lady playing the talk show host this
sensual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Get Him to the Greek (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/get-him-to-the-greek-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/get-him-to-the-greek-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some real nice performances from the two leads, especially the guy
playing the rock star (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Russell_Brand&quot;&gt;Russell Brand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). Sean Combs was fun to watch,
despite his lack of acting skill, probably due to good character
development. The movie has good humor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Gulliver&#x27;s Travels (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/gulliver-s-travels-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/gulliver-s-travels-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;To make up for its extreme shallowness, the movie is very exciting. I
liked the concept of supreme Civil and Mechanical engineering abilities
of the little people. I also enjoyed how the movie made fun of old,
formal-sounding English. The movie also happens to be a Jack Black
vehicle, and this guy has some real good humor. What else me liked is
the robot. Also, the water effects (the storm) are amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Letters To Juliet (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/letters-to-juliet-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/letters-to-juliet-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exquisite cinematography, (excessively) loving characters, and some of
the best depictions of Italian food and romance. The lead character
looks so damn nice at the wedding. The movie is overlong (it drags) and
has some unbearable romance. I like romance, but not when it&#x27;s so
blatantly formulaic. Maybe if I was a stereotypical female, I&#x27;d melt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Experiment (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-experiment-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-experiment-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Captivating but stupid and unexplained concept&#x2F;story; decent
performances; lovely romance (complete with a desirable gal); the sound
effects are overdone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;das-experiment-2001&quot;&gt;The original movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes this remake look better than it actually is;
but it&#x27;s sadly more pretentious... feels more &#x27;merely for show&#x27;; the
guys performing the experiment are even given godlike status, while
those in the original actually have faces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Librarian: Quest for the Spear (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-librarian-quest-for-the-spear-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-librarian-quest-for-the-spear-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Desperate in need of a decent budget (it&#x27;s a fantasy after all); the
concept is interesting, but the movie gets real stupid in its last
third, and the shitty action and unconvincing, B-movie villains don&#x27;t
help either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Red (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/red-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/red-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t like this much (John Malkovich was annoying, Morgan Freeman
uninteresting, and so was Bruce Willis and the girlfriend). But I really
like the eye-pleasing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rebecca_Pidgeon&quot;&gt;Rebecca Pidgeon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who plays the opponent&#x27;s boss.
I just wish that opponent would have been played by a better actor than
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Karl_Urban&quot;&gt;Karl Urban&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paper Man (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paper-man-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paper-man-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Too much in here is unbrearably irritating (the two imaginary
characters, the asshole boyfriend, the slapstick) and uninteresting. The
movie is a horrible experience, though that was eased by the warm
moments between the lead and the stupid (allowing self to be treated
like trash by irritating boyfriend) gal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Penance (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/penance-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/penance-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An okay torture movie where a number of strippers get abducted by a
religious nut claiming to cleanse them of sin. It&#x27;s pretty much stupid
and made worse by its ineffective documentary style. Luckily, the acting
isn&#x27;t bad, though only &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Michael_Rooker&quot;&gt;Michael Rooker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; stands out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Planet 51 (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/planet-51-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/planet-51-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When you got recycled (and shallow and stupid) material, the least you
can do is make it interesting. On the bright side, character animation
for the human when in the large spacesuit is fun to watch, especially
when dancing on stage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shadowboxer (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shadowboxer-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shadowboxer-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The main plot, that of an assassin softened by an innocent being, has
been done a number of times before. But the movie remains fresh. It&#x27;s
clear that the writer is politically liberal, bordering on provocative.
Most notable is the sexual relationship between a young black guy (Cuba
Gooding, jnr.) and an elderly white lady (the beautiful Helen Mirren),
something I don&#x27;t remember portrayed in movies before. As a sidenote,
it&#x27;s probably these two roles that got them in later movies (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-hit-list-2011&quot;&gt;The Hit
List&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;red-2010&quot;&gt;Red&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, respectively).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie pretty much weird, with the sort of direction I haven&#x27;t seen
before. It didn&#x27;t see much distribution, and I only watched it because
I deeply enjoyed the director&#x27;s later work, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;precious-2009&quot;&gt;Precious&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Illusionist (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-illusionist-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-illusionist-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It starts impressively well (the backstage, complete with the bony lady)
but soon devolves into a drag that doesn&#x27;t really go anywhere. The
direction is good, and the lead character superbly-developed. It&#x27;s just
not a match for the director&#x27;s earlier masterful &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-triplets-of-belleville-2003&quot;&gt;Triplets of
Belleville&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rabbit Hole (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rabbit-hole-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rabbit-hole-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicole Kidman has played troubled women quite a few times before, but
the performance she gives here is quite fresh, and really unlike
anything I&#x27;ve seen before, either from her or anyone else. The
character she plays is also quite throughly developed, and my shitty
memory says she is the greatest female asshole I&#x27;ve seen yet in any
movie. This character is grieving of son&#x27;s accidental death.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy playing the killer gives the movie&#x27;s best performance, and
perhaps the best teenage performance in any movie (remember the quality
of my memory). He&#x27;s fucking amazing. And this is a movie not having any
shortage of excellent acting. Most notably, we have &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sandra_Oh&quot;&gt;Sandra Oh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who is
as desirable as she is excellent. She is a good actor, but she hasn&#x27;t
in my eyes done anything better than this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m still not sure about Aaron Eckhart. Not a bad performance at all,
but he&#x27;s too uninteresting. I&#x27;m also not sure about the lady playing
the mother. Not bad either, but not too beliavable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialog is quite good and so is the camerawork. The great direction
easily hides the fact the movie itself is pretty much plotless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rio (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rio-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rio-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the first third unbearable, and the whole thing is rather trite
and recycled. Things become better when the bird wearing a bottle cap as
a hat charms me. The street celebrations are beautiful. Regardless, this
isn&#x27;t Pixar-quality, complete with shitty, supposed-to-be-kool music
and singing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Rango (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/rango-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/rango-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the top-of-the-range quality of the animation and character
design, this is a largely unnteresting adventure story of an
annoyingly-deceptive reptile in thirsty Wild West town. Lucily there&#x27;s
some colorful characters:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the freedom-fighter gal with her heavy America South accent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the old and wise guy who got run over by a car, with his heavy
Mexican accent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the snake, whose creation must have been the single most complex
character in the whole movie, and perhaps among the most complex
digital characters ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s great voice talent, but the story, not so much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>13 Assassins (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/13-assassins-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/13-assassins-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A re-imagining of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;seven-samurai-1954&quot;&gt;Seven Samurai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, complete with its Toshiro
Mifune (the forest guy who is looked-down upon for not being a samurai,
and his slight rebellion), its charismatic leader, battle and acting
style (one wouldn&#x27;t guess that it was made only in 2010). The villain
is excessively brutal, more than any that Akira Kurosawa committed to
screen (if memory serves well). Luckily, the movie isn&#x27;t soiled with
the silly characters that were so common in Akira&#x27;s movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shaolin (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Embarrassingly bad, recycled shit, which would have one fooled early on,
due to decent camerawork and atmosphere. Sadly, soon enough we see some
bad acting and dramatisations. Not even the martial arts rescue it. The
brutality is laughable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I must find something positive. Ummmm... I like the sworn brother,
the one who proposes arranged marriage. The villain&#x27;s performance is
quite good as well, but only before he gains power, because afterwards
he brings some unexciting swagger, you know the one that has been done
how many times before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s okay to rehash stuff, but if you do it worse than everyone else,
eish! I hate pretentious movies. This one wanted to be a memorable epic,
a masterpiece even, but it&#x27;s a cheap imitation. Disgusting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Hit List (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-hit-list-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-hit-list-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s got some good elements, and the lead actor, Cole Hauser, is really
great on screen. The direction of the opening scenes (following the
stressed-out hero, nd his meeting with the killer) is pretty good. The
violence near the end is quite weird, and mentioning it would be a
spoiler.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have appreciated a better budget and superior camerawork. Cuba
Gooding jnr. is badly cast as the killer (he&#x27;s damn unconvincing). The
story is thing and shallow, and the cheating thing painted in a lighter
way was just unneeded, as if fucking is a greater cheating crime than
kissing. Really?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The American (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-american-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-american-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A very fresh assassin movie with great romance (did you see that gal?)
and sound effects. The story is so thin (and rather meditative) that I
don&#x27;t know what to make of the movie. Many unexplained things happen,
but I guess that&#x27;s not exactly a weakness. Rather, it&#x27;s implied. The
uncomfortable situation our protagonist finds self in is quite edgy, and
it makes me wanna NOT become a gangster. The intense violence is always
unsettling, especially if it&#x27;s merely imminent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tangled (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tangled-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tangled-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An enchanting fantasy with superb character design (the evil old lady,
the drunkards, and the 2 outlaws), amazing action sequences, and nice
humor. It&#x27;s originality is in having a horse in a different role than
in anything I&#x27;ve seen yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending (&#x27;climax&#x27;) feels forced, and does not do justice to the
rest of the movie; the movie is a musical, and none of it is
embarassing, but the love song (on the boat) is the low point...
boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one, simply because I
never heard it mentioned before. Note also that, for a few years now, I
don&#x27;t really check out what&#x27;s on the circuit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Let Me In (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/let-me-in-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/let-me-in-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An exercise in embarassment. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;let-the-right-one-in-2008&quot;&gt;The first novel-to-movie adaptation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was
released only 2-3 years before. I thought they wanted to offer something
else, maybe a budget, with some visual flair. But there&#x27;s nothing. In
fact there is an uninteresting &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Elias_Koteas&quot;&gt;Elias Koteas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the investigator (there
was basically none in the earlier movie), and the companion of the
vampire (played by an extrememly uninteresting &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Richard_Jenkins&quot;&gt;Richard Jenkins&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who
bored me horrendously in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;eat-pray-love-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eat Pray Love&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). But these greedy
motherfuckas just wanted to exploit a good story, and give nothing in
return. In fact, the even got lazy, walking briskly over material that
was dealth with more depth in the first movie. But, I don&#x27;t know the
details of the novel, so who knows, they might be more faithful than the
first movie. So I guess they just wanted to make an extra buck from an
audience that&#x27;s too lazy to read subtiles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While watching this, I kept wondering if would I give it more praise had
I not seen (or known) about the original movie. I&#x27;m not sure, because
it comes across as yet-another-horror movie, even though there&#x27;s a gal
vampire. But that&#x27;s not exactly a new concept (remember &lt;em&gt;Interview With
A Vampire&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). It&#x27;s not even remotely interesting. What&#x27;s most puzzling,
beyond that the shit (it&#x27;s not that smelly, I just hate it) got made is
the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Let_Me_In_(film)#Critical_response&quot;&gt;positive response&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; it received from critics. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Prophet (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-prophet-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-prophet-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some serious storytelling here and is unlike anything I&#x27;ve seen before,
other than a resemblance to the mini-series, &lt;em&gt;Blood In, Blood Out&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. An
epic prison movie, though something I don&#x27;t really wanna see again.
There&#x27;s very little happy things going on. There&#x27;s a beautiful visual
(the accident) and an interesting concept (one guy taking on a few
gunmen).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with movies is that they tend to go through different
episodes, which sadly often don&#x27;t quite compare to each other. This
situation is worse for long movies like this one (3hrs). The setup is
quite intense. It&#x27;s so good that I was expecting more than what
ultimately transpired (the slow rise of our &#x27;hero&#x27; through the ranks,
and the complex politics surrounding him). It&#x27;s good direction, but it
could have been better, and this lead of hours, although he competently
leads the movie, falls short at times. Reminds me of Liam Neeson in
&lt;em&gt;Schindler&#x27;s List&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Inland Empire (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/inland-empire-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/inland-empire-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Excessively bizarre, and disturbing at times I couldn&#x27;t figure what the
fuck the story is about; the whole is unbearable, and the experience is
made worse by it&#x27;s 3hr length. How can people get away with so much
audience torture? Worse still, there are mainstream critics who called
it &lt;em&gt;brilliant&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. What did I miss?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Let the Right One In (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/let-the-right-one-in-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/let-the-right-one-in-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the most original of all vampire movies I&#x27;ve seen. Nice
performance from the little gal playing the vampire. Also, though it
kills the innocent, you do feel compassion for it. It&#x27;s origins are
sadly left unexplained. It remained captivating throughout even though
the pacing is slow and the gloss is limited.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] The re-make had good reviews, so I went into it
excited, only to be &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;let-me-in-2010&quot;&gt;seriously disappointed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Scar (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/scar-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/scar-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A run-of-the-mill horror that, luckily, has pretty gals and decent
camerawork. There is nothing new and the twist is underwhelming. What I
like about it is that it&#x27;s not pretentious, and is devoid of arrogance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people spend so much effort on a movie, I wonder how they the
justify the question, &lt;em&gt;what makes this stand above the rest?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Straightheads (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/straightheads-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/straightheads-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A revenge story, and not much else. The sexual spontaneity of the couple
deeds is strange, and isn&#x27;t justified. The story setup is made to look
like there was more than what actually transpired.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Headless Woman (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-headless-woman-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-headless-woman-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to watch this one a few times in pieces because it was too boring
to bear. It&#x27;s a sleep-inducing exercise, following an extremely
uninteresting semi-retarded lady who is suffering from an untold
incident, as well as the guilt of (potentially) hitting a human with her
car. We are led to keep hoping that something will actually happen, but
nothing does. Luckily the acting is good and so is direction and
camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] There is one critic who &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;nytimes.com&#x2F;2009&#x2F;08&#x2F;19&#x2F;movies&#x2F;19headless.html&quot;&gt;found it great&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, inspiring me
to give it a second look. It&#x27;s a better and deeper review than mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Grit (1969)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-1969/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-1969/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality direction can successfully mask an okay storyline. As evidence
of that, this sucky movie has a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;true-grit-2010&quot;&gt;a far better movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; based on that same
story. And it&#x27;s not like that much-younger movie takes advantage of
superior visuals of anything like that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also do not get the appeal of John Wayne; why did anyone thinks he&#x27;s
any interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>True Grit (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/true-grit-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Quality dialog throughout and decent acting. Some big names are
involved, but it&#x27;s interesting that they stayed away from expensive
gloss, and instead focused on the simple story of &lt;em&gt;we gotta find this
killer&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] One critic &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.observer.com&#x2F;2010&#x2F;culture&#x2F;year-end-roundup-what-see-and-skip-ball-drops?page=1&quot;&gt;complained&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;True_Grit_(2010_film)&quot;&gt;via&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) about Jeff Bridge&#x27;s
self-indulgent performance, and I totally agree. The guy is a fine
actor, but he really was getting too comfortable. I would not go as far
as saying the performance was any bad at all, as the critic claims. It
seems he disliked it so much that he decided to go all irrational on us.
It was probably just a lashback against the overwhelming (undeserving)
acclaim the movie got.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>WΔZ (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wdz-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wdz-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching the first half of the movie, I saw a &lt;em&gt;Se7en&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (urban decay and
the brutal violence on some of its citizens; the tough cops
investigating; oh, and the glorious ending). Yeah, it was quite intense,
with a different touch of a lower budget and less glitzy style, but very
effective. This was helped by an amazing cast, all well until the guy
playing the informant shows his shortcomings near the end. Wonderful
setup and script, until an unsatisfying (and unjustified) ending. The
horrid deeds are unjustified too, and the movie doesn&#x27;t offer the
intense emotional impact when the credits roll. You see, movie endings
are extremely important, because if they are shitty, they really mess
the glory that may have already been presented. I didn&#x27;t care much for
the resonation with &lt;em&gt;Saw&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; movies, for the story didn&#x27;t need it. This is
a movie that should have risen above that level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Orphan (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/orphan-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/orphan-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazing camerawork.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vera Farmica is immensely beloved (as usual).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her two kids are amazing, especially the daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The title character is quite good too, a superb child performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;C._C._H._Pounder&quot;&gt;CCH Pounder&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the lead nun; haven&#x27;t seen her in quite a while,
so this is sort of a nice comeback&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As often happens, especially with mystery-thrillers, the allure
doesn&#x27;t last beyond the setup. It&#x27;s tiring and repetitive, and the
motives of the villain are unconvincing. The running length should
also have been reduced.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Idiots (1998)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-idiots-1998/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-idiots-1998/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Full of powerful moments and superb acting; a very original story and
desirable gals (especially the newest member of the group). Takes some
patience initially, and its eccentricity (and film stock) doesn&#x27;t help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Messages Deleted (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/messages-deleted-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/messages-deleted-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed all the performances, and this was helped by me being a fan of
Deborah Kara Unger (always a pleasure watching this god-damn desirable gal,
though she&#x27;s aging). The lead was nice as well, and his gal gorgeous
beyond words. The story is quite thin, and feels incomplete, but it&#x27;s
real weird that the movie didn&#x27;t get much attention at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>According to Greta (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/according-to-greta-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/according-to-greta-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s well-made and has decent acting, but offers nothing new, with the
lead&#x27;s assholeness levels unbearable, and for far too long. The
boyfriend is given a nice (though not too skilled) performance and so is
the grandpa. The diary visual effects are nice (but I&#x27;ve seen them
elsewhere before). The message the movie offers, compassion, is
delivered quite well, although it&#x27;s made in an unconvincing manner
(it&#x27;s like fantasy).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hunger (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hunger-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hunger-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you put a few people in a hole in which they can&#x27;t escape, and
provide only water for a month, what would they do? The movie covers the
concept and quite effectively at that, with the ending, the sort I
normally don&#x27;t like in horror movie, quite satisfying. Oh, they do end
up eating each other. I kept thinking I&#x27;d rather die, but maybe that&#x27;s
becaue I don&#x27;t know the pain of hunger. But screws that, I&#x27;d commit
suicide first. That seems an easier solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is very low-budget and feels like its made by students, but
the acting is quite good. It would have benefited from decent
cinematography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>She&#x27;s Out of My League (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/she-s-out-of-my-league-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/she-s-out-of-my-league-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I hardly ever enjoy romantic comedies because they tend to be cheap
recycled material and this one is no different, except that it&#x27;s
actually funny in many places (highlights are the moments with the
family), and full of good comic performances, most notably the fat guy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shelter (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shelter-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shelter-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is full of excellent performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Julianne Moore, but has she ever fucked up in her career?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lady who lost 3 sons; superb portrayal of grief.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Rhys Meyers, with a caveat that he plays a character whose
body is used as host by a number of souls (personalities of dead
people), so he doesn&#x27;t always keep up.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cinematography, production, and direction are top-notch. The script
(and dialogue) is quite good as well, until we get beyond roughly an
hour, where, like many movies that start well, the writers don&#x27;t know
where to take the script. That&#x27;s where the explanation of the story
must come in, and maybe it&#x27;s because I find supernatural claims shitty,
but it&#x27;s just not done well. We get offerred standard horror fare,
nothing good enough to justify the whole thing. Fuck, there&#x27;s even a
moment where our heroic psychologist plays action hero. Eish!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] Regardless of the shitness, I think the movie received
too little attention from mainstream critics and audience. We must
probably blame the marketing team too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>4 Months, 3 Weeks and 2 Days (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Done with the style of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;crimson-gold-2003&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it&#x27;s a superbly-made and
-acted movie about the ravages of poverty and the problems associated
with making abortion illegal. The general ill-treatment people give each
other is horrid, but luckily things are lightened up when our hero&#x27;s
boyfriend celebrates mom&#x27;s birthday (even though there&#x27;s a sour note).
And the mom gives quite a good performance (and so does everyone else).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the comparison with &lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, it has far better acting, but
doesn&#x27;t cover as much ground and is therefore simpler. I can&#x27;t decide
which is superior between the two, but &lt;em&gt;Crimson Gold&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; had a stronger
emotional impact on me. Maybe that makes it a better movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Animal Kingdom (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/animal-kingdom-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/animal-kingdom-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was expecting more from this (well-made) crime drama about a boy who
moves in with a criminally violent family following mother&#x27;s death. All
performances are good though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Antichrist (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/antichrist-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/antichrist-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple is going through a period of immense pain in their life,
triggered by the death of their toddler. A lot of the imagery is horrid
and bizarre (e.g. there&#x27;s an animal walking around with a stillborn
still attached to pussy), and the movie itself is rather dreamlike, with
the director exercising high levels of freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twist near the end is quite shocking; the love the man has for the
woman (who is mentally screwed by the loss) is impressive. This woman is
given is really good performance. The dialog is quite good as well. The
title is misleading, and is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Antichrist_(film)#Development&quot;&gt;a removed concept&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that was in an
earlier script.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Despicable Me (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/despicable-me-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/despicable-me-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The were moments of good humor (e.g. when lead character was stealing
the shrinking machine), but much of the time, the whole thing is
irritating; the writers worked hard at making this child-friendly (e.g.
being hit multiple missiles results only in a sad face covered in
smoke); the excessivley-advanced gadgets are nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula (1992)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-1992/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-1992/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An unbearably-uninteresting and badly-made take on the legend of Dracula
(Gary Oldman), the world&#x27;s first vampire. It&#x27;s rather shocking that it
was made by the great Francis Ford Coppola, and it&#x27;s probably his
worst. A better (character development; acting) vampire can be found in
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nosferatu_the_Vampyre&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nosferatu&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (1979). Winona Ryder is quite bad as the vampire&#x27;s
lover, though not as much as Keanu Reeves (who also has a face so
gorgeous).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of the vampire&#x27;s shadow, which defies physics, is rather
interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paul (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paul-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paul-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s good humor to be had in here, but I expected more. The two
idiotic scifi lovers who help rescue the alien are played by the guys
who appeared in &lt;em&gt;Shaun of the Dead&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and they are fun to watch, most
especially the short one (he looks like an old woman). The alien they
are rescuing, the title character, is not interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sex, Lies, and Videotape (1989)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sex-lies-and-videotape-1989/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sex-lies-and-videotape-1989/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just one piece of memory of this movie, and it&#x27;s of James Spader
sitting naked watching women talk of sex on video. I can&#x27;t recall
anything else, other than that I really found it boring, but that was
back in the 90&#x27;s. I probably didn&#x27;t even watch the whole thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways I really loved the movie this time around. The direction is
really amazing, with wonderful performances, especially from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Andie_MacDowell&quot;&gt;Andie
McDowell&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Not only desirable, but a fuckin&#x27; excellent performance. She
isn&#x27;t a bad actor, but I don&#x27;t remember her shining like this
elsewhere. As for James Spader, I don&#x27;t remember enjoying any of his
performances, until now. Well, not entirely, but I loved his portrayal
of mystery guy in his early scenes. Great character development there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialog is excellent, and the story simple, and it feels really
fresh. Quite a feat, considering that it&#x27;s made in the 80&#x27;s (there&#x27;s
hardly anything still fresh from that era).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It (1990)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/it-1990/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/it-1990/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Horrible horror without much going for it, except that the clown is
quite interesting, given his humorous and sinister character (and
laughter). Why they made the lady so sexually suggestive is strange. Oh,
and the black guy, why do I smell Black activism? The (non)battle with
the giant spider is ludicrous. It&#x27;s one of those things that make it
hard to believe that movie makers always watch their creations before
release. They could have done better with that spider, even in 1990. Oh,
and the whole thing is just left unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Saw: The Final Chapter (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/saw-the-final-chapter-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/saw-the-final-chapter-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An early scene, involving the gal cheating on two guys, was very
promising. That our gal was so fine also did help, and is the fact that
the torture was on public display. This made it look like it actually
had a fatter budget, and this got me excited. The only other moment that
was well-done was the torture of the racist, and this is due to it&#x27;s
great production design and casting. The rest of the farce was worn out.
Luckily the movie was more enjoyable than it&#x27;s predecessor, &lt;em&gt;Saw IV&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole premise of the series is actually interesting (though I sure
hope no one would tries to imitate it), and I wish it was limited to the
initial ideology, whereby the victims&#x27; decisions involved only them.
But it seems to the writers that wasn&#x27;t exciting enough, and there was
instead an insistence on having it been done to others too, who were
often innocent (e.g. you go through some horrid torture OR your wife
dies). Sounds like desperate writing to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2008-10-12&quot;&gt;earlier review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of another in the series.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Rainmaker (1997)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-rainmaker-1997/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-rainmaker-1997/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to find that this movie was made by the legendary
Francis Ford Coppola. It&#x27;s not quite big and famous either, perhaps due
to its lukewarm story and direction. I&#x27;m however glad that it has these
nice elements:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enjoyable performance of Danny Glover, who plays the judge in
the case. I don&#x27;t recall enjoying any other of his performances.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie&#x27;s best performance is that of Jon Voigt, who plays the
defence lawyer. None of his other performances are as good or as
enjoyable, but my memory has been proven unreliable.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I watched this only cuz I read the book (the version
condensed by Readers&#x27; Digest).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Chronicles of Narnia: The Voyage of the Dawn Treader (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-the-voyage-of-the-dawn-treader-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-the-voyage-of-the-dawn-treader-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t watch the whole of this, the 3rd in the Narnia series. I just
flipped through to ensure I wasn&#x27;t missing anything of worth:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The watery dolphins were likely a homage to my favorite visual
effects work this year, the sea god from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-chronicles-of-narnia-prince-caspian-2008&quot;&gt;the 2nd Narnia movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lion looked better than on that predecessor, but not necessarily
more realistic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The water effects near the end of the movie, where it forms a
wall-like effect, are amazing. This is some of the best water work
ever.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My favorite visual effects work is the sea serpent. It&#x27;s an
equivalent of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kraken_(Pirates_of_the_Caribbean)&quot;&gt;the Kraken&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man&#x27;s
Chest&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). As was the case with the sea god, this was an interesting
departure from the series&#x27; obsession with bad character design.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not going to withstand the pain of watching the entire movie
though. I&#x27;ve suffered enough the with two predecessors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Firm (1993)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-firm-1993/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-firm-1993/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An reasonably enjoyable movie that is sadly showing its age. Luckily
there&#x27;s many nice performances:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holly Hunter: I didn&#x27;t even notice it was here, until I saw the
credits; it&#x27;s been a while I guess; she plays the lover of the
private investigator.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Gary_Busey&quot;&gt;Gary Busey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: He&#x27;s fun to watch as private investigator. He gets
some of the movie&#x27;s best dialogue. Also, I don&#x27;t remember enjoying
any of his performances, until now.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ed Harris: This is one good actor, and I only wish he was given
enough great roles, instead of playing second fiddle to shitty
actors like Tom Cruise. The scene where he breaks in anger, where he
reveals the size of his balls to the Tom Cruise character is solid.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Strathairn: The character of the hero&#x27;s brother was rather
misplaced and was given too much importantance. It was just not
needed for the story. That however shouldn&#x27;t make us ignore the
fact that it was performed well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a bunch of desirable gals too, not least of which was the great
Holly Hunter herself. Another is the wife, and another (the most
desirable) is the lady who seduced our hero on the beach in what is
easily the silliest moment in the movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] Now, this Gary Busy guy is one prolific muthafucka,
with over 120 movie appearances! I think most are shit though, as is
often the case with actors this active. Remember &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dennis_Hopper_filmography&quot;&gt;Dennis Hopper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Chronicles of Narnia: Prince Caspian (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-prince-caspian-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-chronicles-of-narnia-prince-caspian-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As so often happens, it baffles me why so many critics &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Chronicles_of_Narnia:_Prince_Caspian#Reception&quot;&gt;found this any
good&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The only thing worthy of praise is the sea good, who happens to
embody some of the best water effects I&#x27;ve seen yet. Everything else
was just bland (cinematography, costumes, battles, acting, story,
production and creature design, character development), just like the
first movie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Informant! (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-informant-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-informant-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Not really interesting, and that&#x27;s not helped by the rather untalented
(or should I say uninteresting?) Matt Damon who plays the title
character who reveals his company&#x27;s price-fixing activities. It drags
and drags, and really paints a bad picture of this informant guy to the
point where you (I) end up hating him. The plot is overly complex, and
the director attempts to keep it light with a comic touch or two, but it
doesnt work. I seriously didn&#x27;t enjoy this, even though I have to admit
that it&#x27;s well-made (direction, sets, camerawork, script).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lazarus Project (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lazarus-project-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lazarus-project-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Slow pacing gives it a feeling of self-importance, and makes it boring,
especially after lethal injection. Having a bad actor as lead doesn&#x27;t
help either. Luckily, the other performances aren&#x27;t so bad, though none
is any spectacular. The twist is rather implausible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Lost Battalion (2001)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-lost-battalion-2001/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-lost-battalion-2001/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story is not interesting enough for this to be a cinema movie,
that&#x27;s why it went straight to tv. I hate watching a movie which makes
me impatient when it&#x27;s going to end. The interesting moments are too
few to make if worth a watch. One notion worth mentioning though is the
idea of sacrifice, that one high-ranking officer knowingly sacrificed an
unusual number of soldiers for the &#x27;greater&#x27; good. It&#x27;s not clear
what the standpoint of the movie is, but I suspect the writer leaned
more towards the brutality being worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] It would be interesting to know why attaching knives on
rifles stopped becoming fashionable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Road (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-road-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-road-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It is better than the annoying &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-10-25&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Book of Eli&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but not as
interesting. The portrayal of the post-apocalyptic world is as grim as
it gets, and seems far more realistic than &lt;em&gt;Eli&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;i-am-legend&quot;&gt;I Am Legend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The
danger they face, where people kill and&#x2F;or eat each other for survival,
gives an edge to the movie as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Black Swan (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/black-swan-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/black-swan-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Excessively depressing and disturbing (all the blood and physical harm;
the annoying personality of the lead character; her possessive mom).
Also, like &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;showgirls-1995&quot;&gt;Showgirls&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;all-about-eve-1950&quot;&gt;All About Eve&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; before it, it&#x27;s main theme
is of a fresh stage performer hungry to be at the top, and the harms
resulting from that obsession. At the end, Darren Aronofsky is revealed
to be the director. Not that I would have guessed it, but it wasn&#x27;t
surprising, given the director&#x27;s other movies, &lt;em&gt;Pi&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;requiem-for-a-dream-2000&quot;&gt;Requiem for A
Dream&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which could hardly be called easy viewing. It&#x27;s very well-made,
but I seriously didn&#x27;t enjoy it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hell Ride (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hell-ride-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hell-ride-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another Tarantino copycat, perhaps the worst I&#x27;ve seen yet. Michael
Madsen sucks because he does the same performance he always gives (since
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-10-25&quot;&gt;Reservoir Dogs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and so does Dennis Hopper. The slow pacing is nearly
unbearable, and the smart-ass dialogue is just not as good as Tarantino
can make it. Interestingly, Tarantino lend his name to the movie
(&lt;em&gt;Tarantino presents...&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). Seems like he&#x27;s not easily embarassed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The King&#x27;s Speech (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-king-s-speech-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-king-s-speech-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Rush, who plays the speech therapist, gives an amazing
performance. He always delivers good performances, but this was perhaps
his best ever. The moment he was sitting on the kings&#x27; chair was
wonderfully humorous.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colin Firth, who plays the title character, did very well too. I don&#x27;t
remember enjoying any of his other work, and this is probably the best
he&#x27;s done yet too. He even got awards for it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helena Bonham Carter is always a pleasure to watch. Here she plays the
king&#x27;s wife.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production design is amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie drags a bit, especially for the tiny story it tells.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Zombies of Mass Destruction (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/zombies-of-mass-destruction-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/zombies-of-mass-destruction-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie is very well-done and has very interesting characters,
most notably the ever-smiling candidate for mayor position.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freshness of the direction and cinematography reminds me of the
superior &lt;em&gt;Call Back&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, the best horror I saw for the first time
in 2009.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It covers issues of homosexuality and xenophobia very well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The treatment of the zombie side of things is really shitty. Perhaps
it&#x27;s a lack of a budget, but it&#x27;s done so bad, with bad make-up,
and shitty horror movie happenings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves (1991)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/robin-hood-prince-of-thieves-1991/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/robin-hood-prince-of-thieves-1991/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It isn&#x27;t aging well and has nothing going for it: not it&#x27;s story,
it&#x27;s performances, or its direction. It&#x27;s formulaic as hell, and humor
doesn&#x27;t work. Being led by an extremely uninteresting Kevin Costner as
title character doesn&#x27;t help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sleepy Hollow (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sleepy-hollow-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sleepy-hollow-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I had great fun watching this. I can&#x27;t even tell which I enjoyed more
between it and another superb Tim Burton movie, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;alice-in-wonderland-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alice In
Wonderland&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, nor which is better. The humor, which is solely driven by
the very capable Johnny Depp, is spot-on, while the mightily desirable
Christina Ricci is put there as an excuse for a love interest. The
character design of the headless horseman is wonderful, and so are the
caricatures of the villagers, especially the priest; Tim Burton is
master of caricatures, and I love quality caricatures. His imagery and
atmosphere is also great.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tron: Legacy (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tron-legacy-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tron-legacy-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre sci-fi taking place mostly in a computer system, about an
exciting wish for one computer program to escape into the real world.
There&#x27;s interesting artefacts, like a small rod that transforms into a
vehicle at will, while the simulation of Jeff Bridge&#x27;s face is
disappointing, especiallly considering the great work done to Brad
Pitt&#x27;s face in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;fincher-s-most-pointless-yet&quot;&gt;The Curious Case of Benjamin Button&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was
released in 2008. The imagery is very (too) stylish. None of the
performances are worthy of praise (did they have to cast Olivia
Wilde!?).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nanny McPhee (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this one hard to bear. If I saw it first, I would likely not
have given it&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010&quot;&gt;far superior sequel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a chance. It&#x27;s strange that they
were written by one person, because it&#x27;s full of formulaic family
values, and stuff that is so stupid it makes me cringe. Even Emma
Thompson sucks. The only enjoyable character is the caricatured cook.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Stepfather (1987)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-1987/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-1987/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better than &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-stepfather-2009&quot;&gt;its remake&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An extra-gorgeous&#x2F;desirable daughter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better lead performance, though not quite award-worthy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good stunt work (the speeding car; the fall down the stairs).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suffers from lack of explanation for the villain&#x27;s deeds, as was
its remake..&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not fun enough... sleep-inducing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mata Hari (1931)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/mata-hari-1931/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/mata-hari-1931/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This looks good for a movie so old. I expected some creaky stuff, due to
rotten film stock. Anyways, the title character, a spy, is extremely
uninteresting and is given a very unconvincing performance by Greta
Garbo. Similarly unconvincing and even caricatured is the general she
chills with, and worse still, her soon-to-be-lover.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Crimson Gold (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/crimson-gold-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/crimson-gold-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a one-of-a-kind movie (almost) following a small-time
crook&#x2F;pizza delivery guy (Hussein) on his devoid-of-excitement journey
around some densely-populated city. The guy playing him has a lot of
presence (and he&#x27;s really fun to watch), even though in a typical
Hollywood, he would be reduced to merely a secondary character. The
direction is such that you feel affinity with the main characters, and
they feel as real as any movie can make them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s a few wonderful moments in the movie:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene where our normally-sad protagonist passes time by giving
pizza away, and he does this to some of his captives. That act
kindness gave me warm and fuzzy feelings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The scene where our protagonist delivers pizza to a rich guy, who
invites him to stay and enjoy the pizza with him. The motivation is
that he needed to vent a bit and needed some ears for that.
Hussein&#x27;s unwillingness reminded me of the Travis Bickle (Robert De
Niro) in the classic scene of &lt;em&gt;Taxi Driver&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, where one passenger
talks about the pain of a cheating wife... well except that rich
man&#x27;s pain isn&#x27;t quite as intense. The scene also serves to show
the heavy contrast between the worlds of the rich and the poor (and
you should compare rich man&#x27;s place with Hussein&#x27;s; it&#x27;s
ridiculous how the world came to be like this).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though almost nothing happens (at least as compared to normal
Hollywood fare), the movie also covers the issue of sexual oppression,
but very skillfully and subtly, and in more than one occassion. It made
me appreciate some of the pleasures we have here in South Africa.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The style of this movie is very similar to that of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Abbas_Kiarostami&quot;&gt;Abbas Kiarostami&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;A Taste of Cherry&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Wind Will Carry Us&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), and that&#x27;s not
strange since he wrote the screenplay, and is considered by the director
as his mentor. Most notable, it&#x27;s far better than those two boring
pieces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Rosenbaum, the best movie critic I&#x27;ve read, has a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jonathanrosenbaum.com&#x2F;?p=6061&quot;&gt;superb
and highly-detailed review&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He&#x27;s also the one that inspired me to
watch the movie for he is a huge fan of it, to the point of labeling
it a masterpice.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;ve compared this to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;4-months-3-weeks-and-2-days-2007&quot;&gt;4 Months, 3 Weeks and 2 Days&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which is made
in a similar style.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Legend of 1900 (1999)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-legend-of-1900-1999/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-legend-of-1900-1999/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty much enjoyable, with good dialogue, and a fun performance from
1900&#x27;s stepfather, and a lovely love interest, but what an oddball kind
of story? It&#x27;s like some sort of fantasy, and has a weird and
unconvincing competitor, and it&#x27;s as if the faster you can play piano,
the superior you are considered to be. It&#x27;s a pointless story, and I
don&#x27;t know why anyone who write it. Such a strange thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula 2000 (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-2000-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-2000-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the worst vampire movie I&#x27;ll ever see, in a genre that doesn&#x27;t
have a shortage of bad ones; extremely bad direction and script; luckily
the chosen gal is desirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nanny McPhee And The Big Bang (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nanny-mcphee-and-the-big-bang-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I just found out that this is a sequel. It&#x27;s a feel-good fantasy, made
for kids, with some decent moral lessons. Well, there&#x27;s also some shit
about &amp;quot;it&#x27;s okay to determine reality with your bones&amp;quot; bullshit. Not
good. Emma Thompson is always great to watch, even when under heavy
make-up. The encounter between the two boys and the father who is a
senior in the military was quite powerful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had it not been for the misleading title (I thought it had something
to do with the &#x27;beginning&#x27; of the universe), I would not have
bothered.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hate &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;nanny-mcphee-2005&quot;&gt;the original&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tango &amp; Cash (1989)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/tango-cash-1989/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/tango-cash-1989/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A faity-tale of a story with plenty of holes, but is a whole lot of fun.
I hardly ever enjoy Kurt Russel&#x27;s performances, but this one was far
more bearable. Stallone has always been charismatic on screen, and the
gal playing her sister is ultra-gorgeous (though very unconvincing).
Some of the bad guys are mere comic relief (check the guy with massive
jaws; check they guy with a pony-tail, the one who looks constipated).
Good ole cheap action-comedy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Cat In The Hat (2003)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-cat-in-the-hat-2003/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-cat-in-the-hat-2003/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One of these days I&#x27;m simply going to have to admit the world&#x27;s movie
critics are quite strange, and I really can&#x27;t rely on them for what
they consider excellent. Take for example their thoughts on &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Cat_in_the_Hat_(film)#Reception&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cat
in the Hat&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This is because I find it really great family
entertainment. It&#x27;s great fantasy and very funny, with great production
design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Ministers (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-ministers-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-ministers-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;An especially shocking first scene got me excited, and whatever happened
afterwards didn&#x27;t justify it&#x27;s magnificence. It has some really good
direction (very dark with high suspense; wonderful romance), acting, and
dialogue, but the ending is shiite. There was a need for a bigger
budget, as evidenced by the less-than-adequate production design. There
was also a need for a better plot; the story about the burning building
is just not enough, and the great jealousy of scarface is just juvenile.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nacho Libre (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/nacho-libre-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/nacho-libre-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is some oddball comedy, with highly-skilled direction, comic
acting, production design and camerawork. It has nice parodies of common
movie elements, but it gets tiring once it&#x27;s clear that the writers
don&#x27;t have any story tell actually; it&#x27;s fun initially, but it
doesn&#x27;t go anywhere as it &#x27;progresses&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sex And The City (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sex-and-the-city-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sex-and-the-city-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone might feel a need to slap me on my wrist, but I&#x27;m seriuosly not
a fan of romantic comedies&#x2F;chick flicks (I&#x27;m not the target market,
duh!). I&#x27;ve never been much interested in the tv show in which this is
based for similar reasons. But I relented, and in turn got punished by
2hr+ of age-old formula that made me hate the genre in the first place.
Regarding the story, the musings regarding sexual&#x2F;romantic relationships
are quite sickening (think &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;eat-pray-love-2010&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eat Pray Love&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Stepfather (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-stepfather-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first scene is classic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decent acting (my fave is hose salesperson)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pretty ladies (my fave is hose salesperson, and the son&#x27;s
girlfriend)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice cinematography (the atmosphere fits the subject matter)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just another murder thriller, adding nothing new to the genre, and
with a shitty story; the writers just didn&#x27;t know what to do with
the killer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;the-stepfather-1987&quot;&gt;The earlier movie&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is much better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Unstoppable (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/unstoppable-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/unstoppable-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought that the critics would be with me with this for being not
great, but [they actually liked it]. That&#x27;s strange for I didn&#x27;t see
anything worthy in it. In fact there&#x27;s some stupid things: there were
cars parked right next to where the attempted derailment was; some train
driver manages to keep the speed of the train super-humanly constant,
when driving in reverse. More annoying is the subplot regarding the
conductor&#x27;s troubled marriage, which is maybe as bad as Denzel
Washington&#x27;s uninteresting performance. The guy is just plain
overrated, and always plays himself (instead of seeing the character he
plays, I see him playing the character).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also no character development. If you are not going to bother
creating decent characters, at least try make them interesting. Well, at
least the daughters of Denzel are pretty, but they are nothing other
than filler material. They tried make them interesting by having them
work at a strip-club though, which reminded me of Will Smith&#x27;s stripper
gal in &lt;em&gt;Independence Day&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. None of these served the story in any way, so
it&#x27;s a strange distraction in my eyes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[they actually liked it]:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Black Book (2006)</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/black-book-2006/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/black-book-2006/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Although there&#x27;s some interesting-enough stuff going on, helped much by
a quality performance by an immeasurably gorgeous leading lady, it just
feels like... there isn&#x27;t anything remarkable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidenotes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jonathan Rosenbaum has an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jonathanrosenbaum.com&#x2F;?p=5780&quot;&gt;interesting comparison&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;schindler-s-list-1993&quot;&gt;Schindler&#x27;s
List&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, citing &lt;em&gt;Black Book&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to be morally more complex, and therefore
less escapist.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mention of the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;mata-hari-1931&quot;&gt;Mata Hari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; inspired me to watch it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Invincible Iron Man (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-invincible-iron-man-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-invincible-iron-man-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was strange watching this one, for the story is so different from the
two live-action movies (father is still alive; some sprinkling of
supernatural stuff; Pepper is much older, Tony Stark is boring, ....).
It was a fun watch too, other than that the story is pretty much
shallow, and offers nothing fresh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Children Of The Corn (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/children-of-the-corn-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/children-of-the-corn-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wife is oh-so-gorgeous&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quality performances by the wife and the husband; each was a
pleasure to watch&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my shitty memory says that this is the best couple quarrel in my
movie history; oh, and her abuse was rather intense, and unbearably
so; it was so horrid that when hubby retaliated physically, it felt
like justice (and this is from someone who can&#x27;t bear the thought
of male-hit-woman acts)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;edgy like fuck, and without abusing it&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kids are unconvincing, especially their leaders, the so-called
prophets&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how the fuck can an 8-year-old throw a knife so well, so far?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unexplained story; all of that, and for what, exactly?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Disturbia (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/disturbia-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/disturbia-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This displeasing movie is so ridiculous that it would have been salvaged
by having the twist being that the guy was just hallucinating all the
time, especially since it was hinted that house arrest makes people go
crazy. Fuck, what&#x27;s up with the supposedly hot gal? What the hell was
the respectable Carrie-Anne Moss doing here?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dorian Gray (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dorian-gray-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dorian-gray-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a movie adaption of a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Picture_of_Dorian_Gray&quot;&gt;novel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that had a rather interesting
concept: a painting is made of a pretty man, and instead of him getting
injured or aging, it&#x27;s the image of the painting that does. It&#x27;s fun
watching the title character&#x27;s deeds, though he sometimes does it at
the expense of the innocent. The negative influence his &#x27;mentor&#x27; has
on him is annoying, and worse still, the &#x27;mentor&#x27; complains when his
fuckin&#x27; daughter falls for Dorian - hypocrisy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Farmhouse (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/farmhouse-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/farmhouse-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Edgy as horror movies tend to be, nothing special; an extremely bad
performance by the guy playing husband; I didn&#x27;t get it at the end...
I don&#x27;t know why the couple did what they did.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Paranormal Activity 2 (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/paranormal-activity-2-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/paranormal-activity-2-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Mother and daughter are sooo pretty; quality performances and dialogue;
very realistic direction; It just takes a bit of patience though, and I
wish the mystery was explained at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Percy Jackson &amp; The Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/percy-jackson-the-olympians-the-lightning-thief-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/percy-jackson-the-olympians-the-lightning-thief-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a weird one, with a silly title, and nice visual effects, and a
desirable gal in the form of the title character&#x27;s love interest. The
script is really stupid (e.g. one woman withstands the abuses of a
smelly man in order to keep her son safe, since the smell can hide the
son&#x27;s scent!) and the end empty like a mothafucka. They just sit there,
without dialog? So, so strange that you spend millions on technical
wizardry, but neglect to spend enough time developing the story.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shinobi: Heart Under Blade (2005)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shinobi-heart-under-blade-2005/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shinobi-heart-under-blade-2005/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Oriental fantasy is my kinda movie genre. The characters in this one are
as colorful as a peace-loving man effortlessly killing over a dozen
ninjas, or a super-sweet doll who happens to be among the top warriors
in the village. The story is rather silly, where self-sacrifice is the
order of the day. It&#x27;s edgy at the same time, but is too poetic for my
liking (think &lt;em&gt;Hero&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) and there&#x27;s
isn&#x27;t enough of great martial arts choreography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Seventh Seal (1957)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-seventh-seal-1957/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-seventh-seal-1957/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know if we were to take this as comic farce or serious fantasy
drama, but it turned out too eccentric and unfocused. Luckily it got
great cinematography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could not help but notice the physical resemblance between Max von
Sydow (lead character) and Hugh Laurie of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;House_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) fame.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/g-i-joe-the-rise-of-cobra-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/g-i-joe-the-rise-of-cobra-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice visual effects (check the suits) help rescue the shitty and
formulaic movie. The action is rather too loud, but the Paris chase
sequence deserves praise. I wish a better lead actor was chosen; I wish
there wasn&#x27;t no past romantic connection with him and the lady; I wish
there wan&#x27;t no past connection between the two best fighters: the
villainous one and the silent one. These are all badly-handled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sunset Boulevard (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/sunset-boulevard-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/sunset-boulevard-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is typical of those unbearable age-old Hollywood movies. It&#x27;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sunset_Boulevard_(film)#Stature&quot;&gt;overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as hell, and I&#x27;m now curious what it&#x27;s appeal was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He may be a caricature, but the butler is interesting to watch.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wannabe writer is so wantable, and so is her friend.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shitty storyline.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unconvincing scenarios.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overacting by the lead lady, playing a yesteryear star.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bill &amp; Ted&#x27;s Bogus Journey (1991)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/bill-ted-s-bogus-journey-1991/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/bill-ted-s-bogus-journey-1991/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I expected this sequel to be junk, but was pleasantly surprised to find
it was about as exciting as the first, and perhaps funnier, and with
richer content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Grim Reaper was great fun to watch; one of the highlights was
him challenging the duo, who were playing for their freedom from
hell.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was fun to watch the evil Bill &amp;amp; Ted.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The novelty of freshness went away.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keanu Reeves still sucks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The genius scientist could have been more fun, and their melding
seemed to serve no purpose.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss the splattering of comic one-liners that the original had.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>All About Eve (1950)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/all-about-eve-1950/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/all-about-eve-1950/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I only watched this one because it was said to be an inspiration
(ripped-off) for the underrated &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;showgirls-1995&quot;&gt;Showgirls&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and it certainly is. So
much of the story crept through (young and ambitious blood taking over
from the established; lawyers of the established getting involved; much
conniving involved in the process; etc). Luckily I did enjoy this one
throughout, which is quite a rare thing for a movie so old. But, the
movie is waaay &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;All_About_Eve#Critical_reaction&quot;&gt;overrated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. WTF!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gorgeous gals: Marilyn Monroe playing a small part of a young gal
trying to make it as an actor and Bette Davis playing the
established actor&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nice dialogue here and there&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shitty (unconvincing) performance by the gal playing the title
character, Eve&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;another shitty performance by the gal who introduces Eve to the
established&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stagey direction, as is common with movies this old; and we are
supposed to take these characters seriously?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Alpha &amp; Omega (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/alpha-omega-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/alpha-omega-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Stale (nothing new) and second-rate animation and story; the main love
interest is charming, but the movie&#x27;s best is the French golfer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>God On Trial (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/god-on-trial-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/god-on-trial-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s amazing that one can take a silly idea, and make a decent movie of
it. I&#x27;m not sure what the point was, but the some powerful moments, and
decent acting. My favorites were the physicist&#x27;s turn in the court, but
better still was the rabbi, whose encyclopedic knowledge of the Old
Testament made his argument all the more moving. Stellan Skarsgård, who
plays the judge, is as great as usual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>I Am Love (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/i-am-love-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/i-am-love-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Good quality but stale tale of forbidden romance. It has decent acting
throughout, especially from Alba Rohrwacher, who plays the lesbian
daughter. Tilda Swinton is quite good too, except that she overdows her
role a little too much (e.g. her restlessness is over-the-top). This
makes her portrayal rather unbelievable, even though she is a pleasure
to watch (as usual).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>(500) Days of Summer (2009)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/500-days-of-summer-2009/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/500-days-of-summer-2009/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Tries so hard to be fresh, and although its back-and-forth is unique, it
doesn&#x27;t rescue the movie from being yet-another-romantic-drama. It&#x27;s
ineffective, and there&#x27;s nothing refreshing, and it&#x27;s attempt at
trying to make it different makes it unbearable. I was surprised that it
got such &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;(500)_Days_of_Summer#Critical_reception&quot;&gt;good ratings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One fresh concept I gotta applaud is the Expectations&#x2F;Reality thing,
where two scenes are put side-by-side, one real and one not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Downfall (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/downfall-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/downfall-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t recall ever seeing such extreme loyalty and devotion to a
living figure as the people surrounding Adolf Hitler in this grim
portrayal of his final hours. It goes beyond irrational, and into insane
territory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent movie by the way (acting, direction, writing). The portrayal
of Hitler&#x27;s moments of outrage are classic, one of which has been
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.bbc.co.uk&#x2F;2&#x2F;hi&#x2F;uk_news&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;8617454.stm&quot;&gt;parodied numerous times&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dark Matter (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dark-matter-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dark-matter-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The story is quite original: our hero is a boy genius and the villain is
a professor he assists, who proves to be a hypocrite averse to being
challenged.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Meryl Streep doing here by the way? I mean her character? She
does add sweetness to the otherwise dull movie though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Air I Breathe (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/the-air-i-breathe-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/the-air-i-breathe-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie has three parts: the first got me excited due to superb
direction and nice storytelling; the 2nd doesn&#x27;t lose superb direction
but gets tedious; the 3rd makes me wonder why the writers bothered, but
luckily has one desirable gal, the one with a rare blood type.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing turns out pointless (and stupid) at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wall Street: Money Never Sleeps (2010)</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/wall-street-money-never-sleeps-2010/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/wall-street-money-never-sleeps-2010/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;pros&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;production design; check the home of the father (Michael Douglas)
and the office of the billionaire (Josh Brolin)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cinematography; the best moments are near the end&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Susan Sarandon is both beautiful and lovely&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cons&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feels like a desperate attempt to live off the shine of the 80&#x27;s
(overrated) original&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the slow pacing and stale direction made me go &amp;quot;when does it end?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is stale&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lead actor is miscast, and exposes his lack of talent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
