<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Tshepang logs</title>
        <link>http://tshepang.net</link>
        <description></description>
        <generator>Gutenberg</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="http://tshepang.net/tags/bad/rss.xml/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Nightmare on Elm Street (1984)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-nightmare-on-elm-street-1984/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-nightmare-on-elm-street-1984/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This movie is one more reason I should probably stop paying attention to
the opinions of critics who get aggregated on Rotten Tomatoes. Most of
those who reviewed the movie actually felt &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rottentomatoes.com&#x2F;m&#x2F;nightmare_on_elm_street&quot;&gt;it was decent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One even
went as far as thinking the performances were any good. What the fuck! I
will be fair by admitting that the concept is actually good: people
getting attacked only when they fall asleep. I also liked some of the
visuals, like the gal who spins around and gets dragged around the room,
defying gravity. Everything else is plain bad, including the extremely
uninspired look and character development of the villain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A Dirty Shame (2004)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/a-dirty-shame-2004/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/a-dirty-shame-2004/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed watching the faces made by the lead actor. Some funny shit.
Sadly, the movie&#x27;s only worthy moment is where her character dances
with old people. I love her daughter too, but that&#x27;s mere sexual
attraction (she&#x27;s totally wantable!?). Other than that, there&#x27;s some
minor things that entertain, but the rest of the movie is crap. I don&#x27;t
get what the point is. It&#x27;s too overdone to be funny, and if it&#x27;s
supposed to be satirical, it&#x27;s the worst I&#x27;ve seen. The movie would
have been far more effective if the sex-crazed people didn&#x27;t look so
idiotic. Fuck, some even have supernatural powers. Why didn&#x27;t the
makers of the movie do some decent visual effects?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;sidenote&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;] I get the vibe that the director is a lot more capable
that what he displays here, so maybe I&#x27;m missing the point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Abduction (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/abduction-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/abduction-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Takes forever to start, and the delay isn&#x27;t filled with good
filmmaking. There&#x27;s some bad acting (lead, his gal, and best friend)
and some interesting ones (Alfred Molina and Sigourney Weaver), some
shitty story and kiddy romance, and little else that&#x27;s positive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hanna (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hanna-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hanna-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A pathetic attempt at a nuanced, quietly stylistic assassin movie, which
instead happens to be a serious test of one&#x27;s patience and
perseverance. Lead actress is of course good (remember &lt;em&gt;Atonement&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but
what&#x27;s up with the story!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Green Lantern (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/green-lantern-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/green-lantern-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t expect much from this one because I watched the trailer, which
exposed uninteresting visual and character design and a weak lead actor.
The movie turned out even worse than I expected, with an unbearably bad
and ludicrous story. Not even the visual effects help, because none of
them are any good. How can everything in the movie suck so bad!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the ugly guy who was to train the lead was a little interesting,
even though the character is recycled. The concept of a device that
allows one to create temporary matter-energy simply by willpower is kool
too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Season of the Witch (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/season-of-the-witch-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/season-of-the-witch-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It started reasonably well and slowly worked its way down into badly
recycled material. The adventure feels artificial, the villain
uninteresting, the characters shallow as shit, but worst of all is what
happens near the end. In my (pitiful) memory, this is the second worst
movie Nicolas Cage has been in (remember &lt;em&gt;Ghost Rider&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Priest (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/priest-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/priest-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever went into a movie and realise within the first minute it&#x27;s not
going to be any good? If proven right, it can become a painful
experience, and you can&#x27;t wait for the end to come, because it&#x27;s not
so bad that it&#x27;s unwatcheable. What made me notice the early badness?
The very first two people to appear on screen (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Paul_Bettany&quot;&gt;Paul Bettany&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Karl_Urban&quot;&gt;Karl
Urban&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and their poses (they are vampire killers) are very telling.
Worse still, we have &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Cam_Gigandet&quot;&gt;Cam Gigandet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the sidekick. The story is so
unexciting, the climax is rushed and the post-apocalyptic world is
recycled and unexplained. The only bright spot I can remember is the
vampires themselves, even though the design isn&#x27;t original; it is
similar to that of the monsters in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;i-am-legend&quot;&gt;I Am Legend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Descent&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Insidious (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/insidious-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/insidious-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Stupid stories can be told well (remember &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), but not this
one. The visual design of the ghost world is embarassing, and feels
staged. Luckily, the exorcist (or whatever she&#x27;s called) is given a
decent portrayal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shaolin (2011)</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-2011/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/shaolin-2011/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Embarrassingly bad, recycled shit, which would have one fooled early on,
due to decent camerawork and atmosphere. Sadly, soon enough we see some
bad acting and dramatisations. Not even the martial arts rescue it. The
brutality is laughable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I must find something positive. Ummmm... I like the sworn brother,
the one who proposes arranged marriage. The villain&#x27;s performance is
quite good as well, but only before he gains power, because afterwards
he brings some unexciting swagger, you know the one that has been done
how many times before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s okay to rehash stuff, but if you do it worse than everyone else,
eish! I hate pretentious movies. This one wanted to be a memorable epic,
a masterpiece even, but it&#x27;s a cheap imitation. Disgusting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It (1990)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/it-1990/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/it-1990/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Horrible horror without much going for it, except that the clown is
quite interesting, given his humorous and sinister character (and
laughter). Why they made the lady so sexually suggestive is strange. Oh,
and the black guy, why do I smell Black activism? The (non)battle with
the giant spider is ludicrous. It&#x27;s one of those things that make it
hard to believe that movie makers always watch their creations before
release. They could have done better with that spider, even in 1990. Oh,
and the whole thing is just left unexplained.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hell Ride (2008)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/hell-ride-2008/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/hell-ride-2008/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Another Tarantino copycat, perhaps the worst I&#x27;ve seen yet. Michael
Madsen sucks because he does the same performance he always gives (since
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;tshepang.net&#x2F;recent-movies-2010-10-25&quot;&gt;Reservoir Dogs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and so does Dennis Hopper. The slow pacing is nearly
unbearable, and the smart-ass dialogue is just not as good as Tarantino
can make it. Interestingly, Tarantino lend his name to the movie
(&lt;em&gt;Tarantino presents...&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). Seems like he&#x27;s not easily embarassed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dracula 2000 (2000)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/dracula-2000-2000/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/dracula-2000-2000/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the worst vampire movie I&#x27;ll ever see, in a genre that doesn&#x27;t
have a shortage of bad ones; extremely bad direction and script; luckily
the chosen gal is desirable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Disturbia (2007)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tshepang.net/disturbia-2007/</link>
                <guid>http://tshepang.net/disturbia-2007/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This displeasing movie is so ridiculous that it would have been salvaged
by having the twist being that the guy was just hallucinating all the
time, especially since it was hinted that house arrest makes people go
crazy. Fuck, what&#x27;s up with the supposedly hot gal? What the hell was
the respectable Carrie-Anne Moss doing here?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
